[SPEAKER_00] بسم الله الرحمن الرحيم نحمدكم ورحمة الله الرسول الكريم أما بعد So we were on lesson number four We learned a couple of important things Just wanted to do a quick review because It's been over a week since we had the class Or exactly a week, sorry, since we had the last class So, some of the important things we learned in this lesson First is حرف الجر Right? حرف الجر, the plural of which is حروف الجر They are those letters that make the letter after it, كسر Do you guys remember that? And we learned two حرف الجر in the last class Can anybody remind me what they were? على and في, good What does على mean, Haroon? What does على mean? Quick, quick, quick, come on, quick On or upon, okay Then في In In Okay, alright
[SPEAKER_00] So, inshallah, by next class This is optional homework If you're not able to do it, it's fine Because it might take some time But you can find five or ten examples Of each في and على from the Qur'an Right, inshallah, we'll implement whatever we learned about them And we'll see how it applies in the Qur'an And we'll see how often actually these two prepositions come in the Qur'an So, في means in And على means on, right? And again, the effect that it has on the word is That it makes the word كسر, right? So, you have You'll have المسجد And then, let me erase all this
[SPEAKER_00] This is المسجد Right? As soon as you add a في As soon as you add a في It becomes المسجد المسجد المسجد في المسجد Okay? So, just remember في The general rule is Whenever في and على come before a word It will make the word after it كسر It will have a زر after it Alright? Everybody remember this rule, right? You guys remember from last time? Okay Today, inshallah, we're going to learn Two more members of this family What is the characteristic of this family? This family that I taught you guys last time?
[SPEAKER_00] Huh? Nosey? No, those are the استفهام That's people who like to ask questions a lot The questioning No, that's the difference حرف الجر We mentioned that they're demeaning They like to put people down, right? So, حرف الجر is something that makes the next word كسر So, they're the demeaning family Okay Okay Okay Then, the next thing we learned is أين Right? أين is part of which family? Yeah, the nosy family, right? The one that asks a lot of questions So, أين specifically always wants to know where you are Right? They're always texting you where you're at So, أين means where Okay? Where Wait, so, is this family
[SPEAKER_00] like who, what, when, where, like that? Sorry? Like, this is where, right? So, the other one I have is also you Like in this family So, is it like who, what, when, where, like that? Like all of those? Yeah, we already, we did what, we did who Now, we're doing where, right? You'll learn why soon And how as well, inshallah Okay أين محمد هو Right? Who, what, we learned is from which family? Come on, everybody's I guess everybody flushed out everything we learned before Because of the test And you only remember the vocabulary now You don't remember any of the rules anymore Is that what happened? Huh? Pronouns Okay, very good, mashaAllah أبّمائر
[SPEAKER_00] أبّمائر, right? Or the singular form is بمير Again, the terminology is not too important at this stage But if you can pick it up now then It'll make it much easier for you later on, inshallah But the main thing you have to understand It's a pronoun, right? And we explained what is the utility What's the benefit of Pronouns When we speak in English Forget Arabic right now We're talking about in English What's the benefit of pronouns? Yeah, you don't have to repeat the name It's a natural way of speaking You don't keep saying the person's name That, you know, Harun came to the masjid Harun asked me a question Harun memorized the Quran Harun came to class Harun didn't do his homework Harun did bad on his test I'm joking You don't have to keep saying Harun over and over and over again, right? After you say Harun the first time You say Harun came to the masjid Then
[SPEAKER_00] he did terrible on his test Then he asked bad questions in class I'm just joking So you don't have to say Harun over and over again You say he, right? After you say his name once You say he in order to shorten the conversation So the same thing in the Arabic language And every other language as well You have pronouns that shorten the conversation That are referring back to the original name that you had mentioned Or the name that you had mentioned Or original thing that you had mentioned So in Arabic, there's only two sets of pronouns, right? Male or female, right? So we also So huwa is for Is the male pronoun, okay? It means he We're just doing a review We already did this whole thing last time too But we're just doing a quick review right now, okay? So huwa means he So ayna muhammadun huwa fil ghulfa Al ghulfa means room,
[SPEAKER_00] right? So fil ghulfa means in the room He is in the room, right? So that's a complete sentence It's the answer to the question Ayna muhammadun, right? So instead of saying Ayna muhammadun muhammadun fil ghulfa Repeating the name in the response as well Since it's already understood He asked about Muhammad So you don't have to say Muhammad's name again You use a pronoun which refers to Muhammad Which is huwa Everybody seems kind of confused about it And kind of sleepy today I guess you were all expecting the test back And now you're just shocked That you didn't get it back So huwa is the Pronoun that refers back to Muhammad Okay? Wa ayna yasirun Where is? Yasir Huwa fil hammam What does that mean? Okay, good Wa ayna aminatu Hiya fil matbak Is there a saakin on the end of the word?
[SPEAKER_00] No, no You're supposed to say Sorry, I forgot to emphasize it You're supposed to say Huwa fil ghulfati Right? Huwa fil hammami Huwa fil matbaki Like, as I mentioned before earlier as well When you are speaking Especially when you get a grasp of the language When Arabs speak normally They're not going to talk like this Huwa fil ghulfati Huwa fil hammami Huwa fil matbaki They're just going to say Huwa fil ghulfa Huwa fil hammam But because we're talking about the word Learning It's very important for us to know What the haraka is at the end of each word So that's why when we're reading these We have to read every single Haraka on every single word Right? So we don't just take the easy way out And say huwa fil ghulfa We say Huwa fil ghulfati Right? I kind of got into the habit of doing it After getting the habit of speaking So, but For you guys, make sure that you say Fil ghulfati Fil hammami Fil matbaki Okay? Because the whole point is to know that Fi Fi Fi Fi Come on
[SPEAKER_00] Fi makes the word after it I only hear like three, four people Fi makes the word after it Okay, good Alright Ayna al-kitaabu What does that mean? Huwa ala al-maktabi He is on the desk Is that correct? No Why? Why? yeah so in the english language you don't use he for inanimate objects right so that's over here a difference between the arabic language and the english language um in the arabic language hua is used whether it's an inanimate object or uh inanimate object right so that whole thing previously we were talking about um things that have intellect or no intellect that only applies when we're talking about ma and man for now right it applies for some other things also but that's going to come later on for now we'll
[SPEAKER_00] only think of intellect and non-intellect for ma and man otherwise when it comes to hua it applies to everybody right so remember we mentioned what was the general rule that we mentioned right in the beginning of this class yeah every single thing object every single ism every single noun in the arabic language is either male or female right so even right this pen right in english we wouldn't describe it as having a gender because gender was only used for either human beings or animals but even in uh in in arabic even a pen will have a gender so you say hua right you will call it hua the masjid also is a male word so you would say hua um the the the sun is a female a shams so you would call it here yeah is that why we refer to allah as he yeah uh is what why like what exactly yeah you could say yeah that's a good
[SPEAKER_00] point yeah yeah okay so um yeah so who are the maktab so it won't translate as he is on the desk rather it is on the desk what does that mean now we're introduced to a new sorry we were already introduced to it earlier i forgot to note it. Hiya. Hiya means she. Which family is this part of? Which family? Right? It's part of this family. Right? So them two are related. Husband and wife. Right? So they're both part of the dama'id family. What characteristic can we give this family to remember it? What characteristic? No, that's huruf al-jar. Curious? No, because that's asmar
[SPEAKER_00] istifham. Yeah, these are pronouns. I'm asking you, like I can't think of any characteristic to explain, to remember this family. So I'm thinking, can you be creative and think of something? Copycats. Kind of, but it might get confusing though if you say copycats. But it doesn't make sense though. It's fine. Have you seen that? Where's my watch? Oh, sa'ati. Yeah. But you don't say as-sa'ati. But don't get everybody confused right now. Don't talk about that yet. When we get there, we will talk about that inshallah. Okay, forget it. Dama'id, our pronoun, just remember that. We don't have an attribute to this family for now. Can you say gender indication? Yeah. But like, it's not something that helps us remember. The reason I was mentioning an attribute for each family just so that we can remember that term. Okay. You want to use an imitator? It doesn't fully work, I think. That's fine. JazakAllah khairullah. Appreciate it. So okay, so hiya is for females. Again, it's for animate objects and inanimate objects as well. Right? So
[SPEAKER_00] we already use it for amina. Is amina something that has intellect? Yes. It's actually a female in the true sense of the word. And we use hiya for it. Then we have a sa'a, which is a clock or a watch. We use hiya for that as well. Right? So the author is just mentioning that to make it clear that hiya can be used for animate objects and inanimate objects. Okay? Meaning things that have intellect and things that don't have intellect. Is that clear? So these are some of the main things that we learned in the previous lesson. Right? Hiya ala as-sari'i. Okay. Let's go to the next. We didn't do the tamarin, right? The exercises. No, we didn't. I told you guys not to do any homework. If you guys did it, that's fine. But you'll be assigned it today. So yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Sorry. That's something we mentioned last time too. That this or
[SPEAKER_00] this. These two are called ta' al-marboota. Right? These two. Right? So if these two are at the end of a word, then the vast majority of the time, let's just take a general rule that it's going to be female. Okay? There's some exceptions, right? Some names, for example. Hudaifah. Hudaifah is a male name, a sahabi radiyallahu anhu's name, but it's for female. But forget the exceptions for now. Because if you keep the exceptions in mind in the beginning, then you're going to get confused. Just remember that when this ta' is at the end of a word, then it's female. Everybody got that? And again, that's what I mentioned last time. That's why you hear, you know, name
[SPEAKER_00] some female names. Aisha. Aisha too. Then Fatima too. Huh? Then? Khadija too. Good. Right? Amina too. Good. Good. Aliyah. Aliyah too. Good. Yeah? Every female? Not necessarily every female. That's a good question. So this almost always indicates a female, but that doesn't mean that every female word has this. You get it? You understand that? So there are many female names that don't have, for example, Zaynab. Right? Zaynab does not have a ta'am al-wuta' at the end. Right? Sorry? Mariam. Mariam. Exactly. Right? So there are many names that do not have ta'am al-wuta'. But when there is a ta'am al-wuta', then you know for sure that that's a female name. Almost for sure. Like I said,
[SPEAKER_00] there's some exceptions. But generally, you know that it's going to be a female name. Everybody got it? Okay. Just a quick question. So as far as like the ayna examples we were going through, it was like ayna Muhammadun wa ayna Yasirun. But why is it wa ayna Amina too and not Ta'am? Yeah. So we're going to do that today, inshallah. It's coming on. If you see on page... 23. Right? It's going to explain exactly that. But that's a very good question. I like that you're analyzing these things. Right? It's very important to pay attention to detail when we're learning Arabic to note these small things. Very good, mashallah. Okay. So his question was, if you guys weren't listening, that if you look at all the other names, it says ayna Muhammadun, ayna Yasirun. But then when it says Amina, it says ayna Amina too, not Amina tun. Right? Why is that the case? So we'll learn that on the next page, inshallah. So as homework, we're not done with the class. I'm just telling you for now. Do on Tamreen number one, which is at the bottom of page 21.
[SPEAKER_00] Ajib come from Jawab. You guys know what Jawab means? Right? Respond. Right? So ajib is a command saying answer the following questions. Al-as'ila come from su'al. In Urdu, it's also sawal. Right? So in Arabic, al-as'ila. Al-atiyah means the following. Right? So ajib an al-as'ilat al-atiyah means answer the following questions. So the question is, ayna al-kitab? So you, from your own side, you come up with an answer and you write it down. Okay? That's the homework. Everybody got it? So ayna al-kitab, you would say, huwa ala al-maktab. That's the easiest answer, but you can be creative and think of another answer if you want. Okay? And likewise, you answer all the rest of the questions up to number 11. Then you see number two, it says, iqra waqtub. Right? Iqra means read. Uktub means write. Right? Iqra waqtub ma
[SPEAKER_00] 'a dhabti awakhil kalimat. Read and write along with the haraka at the end of each word. Right? So when you read it, you also read it with the haraka at the end of the word. So you say, al-madrasa. You don't have to say al-madrasa. You say, al-madrasatu. Right? Then you say, fil madrasa. T. Right? So the whole thing is they're trying to see if you got the picture of what a harful jar does. Right? You guys remember, what does a harful jar do? Why is there only one person in the class? What does a harful jar do? There's only three people in the class. What does a harful jar do? What does a harful jar do? Yeah. And in terms of the Arabic sentence, what does it do? Makes the next word have a kasra at the end. Right? So, fil madrasa. T. Right? So they're trying to check in this tamreen if you're able to do that. So when you read it, you read it properly. And when you write it down, then
[SPEAKER_00] you write it with the haraka at the end. Right? So if you want, you can write it out again in your book if you want more writing practice. Otherwise, in your book itself, you can just write, is it al-madrasatu or T. Right? You can just put a line as a haraka. Yeah? A long time ago, I heard that every word by default ends with a comma. Is that true? You could, if you can, if you want to, that'll make it easier to understand. Yeah, you could think of it like that. Yeah. The default is that it starts as a bomma or a pesh. Right? Then it'll only change if there's other factors that come in play. So you can understand it like that. Yeah. But if you want to get very, very technical, then there's a lot more to it. But if you want, just to understand, that's a good way to look at it. Yeah. That the default is that it's going to be a bomma or a pesh. Only if something else comes along, then it'll change it to something else. Okay. Now, let's read. This is the next part of the lesson. Right? Read and write. This is not homework now. This is,
[SPEAKER_00] we're continuing the lesson. So who wants to read? You don't have to wait. Basically, pesh is another way of saying bomma. You know, like a bomma, like on top. Yeah, you know bomma. It's just a word in Urdu that denotes the same thing. But some of the brothers are not familiar with the word bomma. So I say pesh too. But it's the same thing. Yeah. All right. Who wants to read? Somebody who hasn't read. Yeah. Go ahead. Brother Ali. By the way, I want everybody to know everybody else's name. I know there's more than 50 brothers in the class, mashallah. But we should all be familiar with each other. So inshallah, maybe one day we'll have a test on the names of the brothers in the class, inshallah. Sorry? Oh, yeah. So this is Brother Ali that's speaking right now. Yeah. Make sure you say the last haraq at the end. Sorry? Yeah, it's fee
[SPEAKER_00] because of the fee, right? Good, mashallah. Okay. That actually leads me to a point I was supposed to introduce you to this in the last lesson. I don't know if it'll get too technical. We can try. If you don't get it now, no problem. You can pick it up later, inshallah. So there's an alif that I wanna show you. Here we go. I have an alif. One alif that's significant for e topic or a topic and clan. A means if you need a qu popula law. It means if you know your tribe. So it means if you learned and you're good at learning. Nice question. Now, I wanna highlight something I want to confirm other people's ideas available. There's some things about alif. This composition of alif where these alif people, means, when we say alif, we also mean when we get related. Okay. So, it means when we get to explain something, or we move, we see that there's a way in which we connect the names of a tribe. We have, for example, a friend that adds al grade to excuses and it turns into a class Erta which We only know that this type of alif that comes in al It's called You don't have to remember the name if you don't want to But it's called
[SPEAKER_00] Hamzatul wasli Wasli means to connect So it's the hamza that connects So what does that mean? So if you look at it at the beginning of a word Then you say al You say it like a normal alif or a hamza You say al But if it's in the middle of a sentence Then all of a sudden it becomes silent I don't know if you ever noticed that when you're reading Quran But it becomes silent So for example over here We don't say You just pretend that hamza doesn't exist It's just there to connect it That's why it's called hamzatul wasli You just say Okay? Everybody understand that? Usually when you're learning Tajweed You get this concept already, right? But anyway it's
[SPEAKER_00] good to know And now we know the terminology for it It's called hamzatul wasli So it's a special type of hamza That only appears You only pronounce it when you're Pronouncing at the beginning of a sentence But when you're in the middle of a sentence Or the middle of a word Or something Then you It's basically a word that's in the middle of a sentence It's basically silent Okay? So like for example You say But then when you say Then you say You don't say You get it? You see the difference? You say You're saying the hamza But when you say Then you say And that's like Everybody got that? Okay? So that's why this hamza that comes Whenever you say The hamza is called Hamzatul wasli Which is Which is only pronounced When you pronounce it in the beginning Otherwise If it's in the middle Then you don't pronounce it Everybody got that? Okay Alright
[SPEAKER_00] It's good to know But yeah If you don't If you can't If it's Like see it depends, right? Everybody's at different levels And some people You know it's been a long time Since they've been in a classroom Right? So for them All these terms are going to be like You know It's a lot going on Right? So for them you know It's fine if you don't Really pick it up Because you just want to get The main thing Right? But For those who are Maybe younger And you know They have a lot of zeal Maybe have some time as well Especially the hufad For them it's They already Mashallah have a lot of It's easy for them to memorize things And pick things up For them I would expect them That you should know it Right? And later on Once we get Right? Everything's not going to stay Like this ABC You know Alif, ba, o, ma, ha, da You know Very easy things, right? It's going to get difficult And we're going to start Speaking in Arabic And we're going to start Mentioning all these Arabic terms And when you're breaking down The Quran Right? When you're When you're actually Going through an ayah of the Quran You can't just understand it like that You have to break it down In a grammatical way Right? When you break it down I'm going to be saying Like okay This is a harful jar So what does that do? Right?
[SPEAKER_00] So if you're like Oh You know Harful jar is like Is that like the demeaning family? And then you're going to be like You know If you're thinking like that Then you're going to be stuck Right? So eventually You're going to need to know it If you don't know it now I don't mind so much Because As long as you understand the concept But as we move on We're going to start using I'm going to start using these words And even if you look in books Right? Tafseers for example They're not going to be telling you The demeaning family The one that puts you down Right? They're going to use the term Harful jar In the tafseer books So you better understand What that means You get it? So that's why Learning terminology is important But not necessarily At this stage in time But if you pick it up now Then it's much easier For you later on Everyone understood? Okay Sorry What was the name of that That Hamza That lives in the Jamia Here Hamza al-Wasim That's in the beginning You said this Hamza al-Wasim Is for the life That starts in the beginning Of the word You know It's called Hamza al-Wasim All the time But Hamza al-Wasim Is only pronounced When it's at the beginning Of a word Otherwise it's
[SPEAKER_00] silent When it's in the middle Or in the middle of a sentence I thought you said It has a No the name is still the same Yeah What's the simple definition Of Hamza al-Wasim? I don't know It's Yeah I don't know How to define it It's I mean You could define it By the rule that I mentioned Right You mean a translation What was the rule? Connecting Hamza The rule is that If Hamza al-Wasim Comes in the beginning Of a sentence If you're reading it In the beginning of a sentence Then you pronounce it As a Hamza Al With a Hamza with a fatha on top A But If it comes in the middle Then you don't pronounce it It's silent Okay You can read now Now read it Read it According to what I just mentioned About the Hamza al-Wasim According to Very good Mashallah Very good Alhamdulillah What does that mean? Okay sorry Let me tell you what Al-Jami'ah Al-Jami'ati means Al-Jami'ah I'm sorry
[SPEAKER_00] Al-Jami'ah is University Okay Al-Jami'ah is University I think And it's used in Pakistan as well For some universities Right? Right? Especially Oh okay For women's university Sorry? Oh okay It's used for that Okay Sorry So Al-Jami'ah is A university Okay So Al-Talibu Fil-Jami'ati How do you What is that How do you translate that Wait no Don't answer Let's see Brother Al-Jami'ah Al-Talibu Fil-Jami'ati For the ilm How do you translate this? Al-Talibu Fil-Jami'ati No there's no going right? We didn't mention anything about going Al
[SPEAKER_00] -Talibu Fil-Fi What does Fi mean? Yeah The student is in the university Yeah Good Mashallah Alright Alright Number two Okay Can anybody remind Brother Ali What mistake he may have made? Yeah very good Mashallah Al-Rajulu Right So remember we learn about Hruf Shamsiyah And Hruf Qamaliyah So Ra is from the Hruf Shamsiyah So you say Yeah Alright Good Mashallah Again if I If we correct anybody Nobody should feel bad Right You do not You cannot learn If you don't make mistakes And you're not corrected Right If you end up feeling So shy You never want to read In class Because you know You feel like you're going to make a mistake And you're also never going to get Your mistakes fixed Right So it's very important for us To make mistakes Because that's part of the learning process Okay So yeah Sorry What does that mean? Let's see Sameer what does that mean?
[SPEAKER_00] Al-Rajulu Fil-Masjidi Something Al-Rajulu Something Oh yeah Like you don't know what it means Oh okay Okay Okay Who knows what Al-Rajul means? Who can remind you? The man The man Al-Rajul means the man The man is in the masjid Okay Good Mashallah Al-Rajulu Fil-Masjidi Okay Sorry? That's plural Re-Jab Re-Jab Yeah Plural yeah Okay Alright Number three Read Aina Al-Rajulu Yeah Again don't pronounce the Hamza Because it's in the middle right? Aina Okay So Aina Is it Aina Al-Taj Yeah But then also there's this Harf From the Huruf Shamsiyah So that's what you say Aina Al-Taj Al-Taj Say it Oh Aina Al-Taj Yeah good Mashallah Aina Al-Tajiru Right You don't say Aina Al-Tajiru You say Aina Al-Tajiru
[SPEAKER_00] Aina Al-Taj Okay Good Fid Fid Dukan Fid Dukan Okay Fid Fid Fid Fid Because remember the Alam is silent too So in this scenario the Alif and the Alam are going to be silent You get it? Yeah So when you have Huruf Shamsiyah in the middle of a sentence Then both the Alif and the Alam are going to be silent Okay Okay Say it again Okay Okay Aina Al-Tajiru Huruf Shamsiyah Huruf Shamsiyah Huruf Shamsiyah Huruf Shamsiyah Okay good Mashallah Okay Translated Where is the merchant? He is in the store Very good Mashallah Where is the merchant or the businessman? He is in the store Okay Very good Let's have some Let's have somebody else read Brother Sheraz
[SPEAKER_00] you want to read? Say it again No because the Qaf is not from the Huruf Shamsiyah So you just say it with the Alam Yeah good Okay Okay Okay Okay Okay Okay Okay Okay Okay Good Okay Al-Mekteb Okay Al Qalamu Alal Mektebi Okay now, it's getting a little bit harder because there is no Zabar Zariah and there is no Fatah Kastradhama Right But that's because you already learnt this word Right Once you learnt the word They are not going to put the Fatah Kastradhama again It's to train you that I should automatically recognise this word now and I should automatically know because again Again, as
[SPEAKER_00] I pointed out to you in that book, that when you're reading an Arabic book, there's not going to be any Fathaka Saddamah, right? So you have to know the word in order for you to actually be able to read it, right? Maybe at the end of the class, I'll show you guys that without looking at the book and maybe checking a dictionary, I'm going to be able to read the page without looking beforehand. That's what the author is expecting you to do, right? So in the same way here, that's why, again, this book is very nice because it gradually trains you to get to that level. You don't even realize it, right? It just pulls the harakat away and you're like, wait, where did it go? But then it's to such an extent that sometimes you don't even realize it and you're gradually already learning it, right? So again, over here, ala al-maktabi, right? We already learned al-maktabi means desk, right? So al-qalamu ala al-maktabi means the pen is on the desk. Okay, good, mashallah. All right, brother, can you read the next one?
[SPEAKER_00] Okay, translate it. Okay, where is Zaynab? She is in the room. Okay, good, mashallah. All right, let's see, brother Basel, Hafiz Basel, sorry. Okay, translate. Okay, good, mashallah. Did we do al-warak before? Okay. All right, I thought Basel just knew it from before, mashallah. Okay, so in al-warak, where is the paper? Hu al-al-maktabi, it is on the desk. Okay, simple. Let's see. Brother Saqib, Saqib, right? I know Madhabis now. Mm-hmm. Who have the falsi. Fil falsi. Li, good, very good, mashallah. Translate, please. Oh, sorry, brother Yasir, you translate. Translate. Where is teacher? Yeah,
[SPEAKER_00] where is the teacher? Who is the teacher? He is... Sorry, I didn't, we never learned falsi yet, so al-faslu is the classroom, okay, new, new vocabulary word, al-faslu is the classroom, okay, al-faslu. So huwa fil-fasli means, translate it, brother Yasir. He is in the classroom. Good, all right, he is in the classroom, okay. All right. Is it aynda al-mudarrisu or... No, aynal-mudarrisu. Because of the da? Because of this Hamza, yeah, because of Hamza al-wasl, yeah, because of that special Hamza. Okay, so the laam is not pronounced because of the da as well, right? Whoa. No, it is pronounced. Aynal-mudarrisu. Because the meme is there, right? So, yeah. Is that like another Thai one? For which one, the Hamza? Yeah. No, it's not. Yeah, it's just, it's
[SPEAKER_00] just a harf, it's just a letter. Okay. All right. I have a difficult question that I have a hard time explaining. So you need to listen to this word here, al-majroo, that's the beginning of the word. But in the ayah, why does it begin with the khasla and not the... Yeah, so it's the same, that's also Hamza al-wasl over there, ittabi'u, but it's different because that's something... It's a specific type of form, which we'll learn later, inshallah. For that, the default is, it's also Hamza al-wasl, but for the default for that is that it's a kasra. Or, well, it depends on the context. If it's, I don't want to confuse you, right? But it's either going to be a kasra or a dhamma, right? For example, uqtulu, right? Uqtulu comes in the Quran too. So that starts with the dhamma, right? It's also the same format, but it depends on certain factors. So this
[SPEAKER_00] Hamza al-wasl can be a fatha, kasra, or dhamma, right? But that's in other contexts. For al, it'll only be a fatha, so you don't have to worry about anything else. So everybody else just don't pay attention to what I just said, just flush it out of your brains because otherwise you're going to get confused. I was just answering the brother's question, but for Hamza al-wasl, for al, it's either going to have a fatha on it, or it's just not going to be pronounced at all, depending on the context. Yeah, fasl has many different meanings. But in this context, it means classroom. Are you asking me what those other meanings are? Yeah, yawm al-fasl is like the day the decision is made, right? Okay. All right. Who else didn't read it? Sorry, I forgot your name. Ayaan, okay. Is it number
[SPEAKER_00] seven? Number eight. No, no, that's number nine. Number eight is before that. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, but that's a meme over there. That's another thing that might be a little confusing for us, especially if you're used to the desi script, the Indo-Pak script, and all the... The meme, you might just ignore it, might not know it exists, right? Right? Over here it says, So that meme looks like a tiny little dot. It looks like it doesn't even exist. So that's why a lot of times, we might even just skip the meme and not know it's there, right? But that's how it looks when it's written in this script, right? Everybody understand what I'm saying?
[SPEAKER_00] So that's why I noticed some other brothers also, when they're reading this, they just skip the meme because they think it just goes straight to the raw, right? So just make sure you know that that's how the meme looks in this script. So for example, the previous number seven, So the meme over there, again, it's just a small little line, right? So it's easy to miss it. So just know that that's how it looks in the script. The way the meme's written, it doesn't matter. It doesn't mean anything special. No, yeah, it's just different convention. Yeah, it should be in a Yasirun. Yeah, good question. All right. Aina Yasirun. Huwa fil mirhadhiyya. Can you translate, brother Ayan? Oh, sorry, I didn't say mirhadhiyya. Mirhadhun means bathroom, right? But specifically means toilet. So the difference between hammam and mirhadhiyya, there's something. That's kind of, I
[SPEAKER_00] guess, different in modern Arabic. Hammam is just used for bathroom, like actually using the toilet. But hammam, if you want to be more precise, Hammam refers to where you actually take a shower, right? But mirhadhiyya is actual toilet, right? So if you want to say I'm using the bathroom, then mirhadhiyya would be more useful than saying hammam. Although in modern Arabic, if you go to Ammiya and stuff, you just say huwa fil hammam. Like he's in the bathroom. But you only say that if somebody's taking a shower in Fusaha Arabic. Okay. Okay, good. Very good. Where is Yasir? He's in the bathroom. Okay, let's get done. Brother Hussain? Hafiz Hussain? Quick, quick, quick, quick. As-Sama' means the sky. As-Sama' means the sky. This comes in a lot of places in the Qur'an. Can anybody give me? Can you give me an example?
[SPEAKER_00] Very good, mashaAllah. And in the sky is your sustenance, your rizq, your provision. Any other example of As-Sama'? Allah is swearing by the sky and its structure. Yeah. So similar also, Allah is swearing by the sky. Yeah. That's plural of sky. But yeah. To Allah belongs. Allah belongs everything that is in the heavens, in the skies and the earth. As-Sama'. Okay. As-Sama' means the sky. So, As-Shamsu wal Qamaru fi As-Sama'. What does that mean? Somebody else translate it. Um. Um. Um. Um. Um. Um. Um. Um. Um. Um. Um. Um. Um.
[SPEAKER_00] Um. Um. Um. Um. Here we go. Right? Yeah. Yup. It's very simple. Very good mashaAllah. Nobody tell him please When the decision is made Yeah no The decision People shouldn't That was their fault not your fault Because people are asking about other meanings of Fasl Forget the other meanings right now Right now we're worried about Fasl means classroom In our context Yeah No man means No no Yeah who's in the classroom So man is from which category Which family is it from Yeah they're nosy They're questioning So man is when you're asking a question Who is in
[SPEAKER_00] the classroom Somebody want to answer the question Who is in the classroom Somebody answer the question Good Or the other word for teacher The teacher is In the classroom In the classroom Okay That took longer than I thought That we would be able to Okay we should We have Everybody mind if we go to 920 and 921 Sure Can we do one more thing Quickly Because we didn't do much today Okay Okay over here you see On the first Everybody up to where Where it says Hamza right You know where we are Number 23 Okay On the right side there's a column It says Muhammad Kharid Hamid Yasir Ammar Sa'id Ali Abbas On the left side of the column It says Aminatou Zainabou Fatimatou Maryamou Aisha Khadijatou Safiyatou Ruqayatou Somebody tell me
[SPEAKER_00] What's the difference Between the right column And the left column Yeah The name is Just British For the girls Louder louder Oh for the girls It's just British Not double Okay good For the So one is But which side is Like Just first tell me You said the girls It's British But like So that means Which side is the girl's side And which side is the boy's side Yeah So the left Column is all girls names Right And the right column is all Boys or male names Right And then Another thing we note As Hafiz Haroon said MashaAllah That The dhamma On the females Is only one Whereas On the male names You have the regular tanween Right But for females You only have one Right So That's something we learn That For female names They don't have tanween on them Right This is the general rule Female names
[SPEAKER_00] Do not have Tanween on them Okay Everybody got that Right So Another assignment This is extra Right But if you can do it It'll be good It'll be good practice For this Is To find Five female names Or sorry There's only one female name In the Quran So So find that No no Yeah Maryam is the only female name Right In the Quran Sorry Yeah But it doesn't say her name Yeah Maryam is the only name In the Quran Okay So find Find Maryam in the Quran Any ayah And see If a tanween comes Or it's a challenge If you find it If you find a tanween On Maryam's name Anywhere in the Quran Then I'll give you A hundred dollars No no no Name A name Imrah
[SPEAKER_00] is not a name Yeah exactly Yeah So the point is that A female name Will never have Tanween on it Okay That's just something to know Maryam Wa Maryam Mabanata Imran It doesn't say Maryaman Ibnata Imran Right Any other place That Maryam comes in the Quran Hufald Come on Hufald Come on Where's Maryam Come in the Quran Huh Very good Wa thkur fil kitabi Maryam Mamumi What is it Good Very good Wa thkur fil kitabi Maryama Maryama Sorry Maryama Right So if it was a male name It would have been Maryaman Right But because it's a female name It has a special characteristic Where it does not accept Tanween Right Women
[SPEAKER_00] are stubborn So when they don't want something They don't want it Right So women do not accept Tanween Right So Any woman name Does not have Tanween on it Okay Right No no Not objects Only for female names Yeah Because if you look Just in the Sorry that has We can't even see it But you'll see later on It'll come That you'll have Let me just think of An ayat of Quran Yeah Lam yalbathu Illa sa'atan Minal nahar Right Wa yawma yahshurhum Ka'al lam yalbathu Illa Sa'atan Right So it says Sa'atan What does it mean You get it So
[SPEAKER_00] it shows that If there's a female Item Not a female name Then A feminine item Then That is not It does have Tanween on it So this is only for Female names Everybody got it Okay Okay Even the word Woman or No it'll It'll still be Yeah Only for specific names Like Fatima Khadija You get it No no You don't have to do that homework You can scratch that homework out Because I forgot There's only one female name In the whole Quran So You don't have to Do that Otherwise you guys Would be up all night Looking for What about How Oh we can end the class I'm sorry But it's not mentioned In the Quran What's the word you got Hawa'u Yeah Hawa'u Yeah Alright I thought I thought the The masculine I
[SPEAKER_00] thought Names in general Don't have tanween No Look at Muhammadun Khalidun Right Muhammadun Rasulullah Muhammadun Rasulullah As it comes to the Quran itself Muhammad has tanween So The name is Yeah so We'll get there Don't worry Yeah I don't want to confuse anybody Okay Alright Everybody understood that So we can do This next tamreen as well For homework Right Read and write these Along with mentioning Write the last harakah At the end of each word Okay Page 23 on the bottom Right Page 23 on the bottom All you have to do is Read and write The last harakah Right So is it Hamidu Or Hamidun Right So you just write that Either if you want to Just write in the book Through the easy way out Or if you want to Actually write down Each one in your Notebook separately And then write the harakah At the end Alright The next part From page 24 We will do Next class inshallah And inshallah Inshaallah I'll have your Tests
[SPEAKER_00] graded By Monday Inshaallah Ta'ala Again also If you can Find examples In the Quran of What was it Fi An'ala Right Fi An'ala Okay Subhanallah Bi hamdi Subhanakallah Wa bi hamdika Shalwa La ilaha Illa Tana Astaghfirullah Wa atubu ilayk Subhanallah Rabbika Rabbil Izzat Ya Umma Yasafun Wa salamun Ala Al-mursaleen Alhamdulillahi Rabbil Alameen