[SPEAKER_00] If somebody could just take responsibility to remind me to record, because I forgot to record from the beginning, inshallah. Alright, where should I keep the... here? Alright. Alright. Now we turn to page 5. We can skip the introduction. Alright. Who volunteers to read? Read loud. Everybody has to hear all the way over there. This is a house. This is a mosque. This is a door. This is a book. This is a pen. This is a key. This is a library. This is a bed. No, read
[SPEAKER_00] the whole thing. Key, library. Don't take a shortcut. This is a library. This is a bed. This is a book. Okay, we can stop here. So, first let me just explain what is going on here. So, the author is teaching a basic sentence structure. We won't go into the sentence structure just yet, because, again, this book is designed to be gradual. So, it's not like... I'm not going to give you a whole bunch of rules. Sometimes, when some teachers are teaching this book, they'll go to this first lesson. They'll go into detail about... there's three things. There's an ism, there's a fair, there's a harf. Those are the three different types of categories in the Arabic language. And then this is a jumlah ismiyah, and this is a muqtada, it's a khabar. So, technically, I could explain that. Right now, because that's what he's introducing, but the author didn't mean for that all to be explained at this point in time. That's going to be explained in more detail later on. But the main thing that the author is trying to explain in this chapter is the word hadha.
[SPEAKER_00] Hadha means this, right? So, do you need a whole chapter just to learn this? No. So, this, obviously, you can just learn a translation and say, okay, hadha means this, right? But what does this really entail? Right? You have to learn what it entails in the Arabic. Because there are some differences between the word this in the English language and the word hadha in the Arabic language. What are those differences? The word hadha, so first and foremost, there's a very important rule to know in the Arabic language. That in the Arabic language, everything, every noun, we all know what a noun is, right? What's a noun? Somebody? Nobody? No, not, yeah, person, place, or thing. A noun is a person, place, or thing. So, any noun in the Arabic language can be either male or female. It's only going to be male or female. There's no such thing as gender neutral or gender fluidity in the Arabic language. Right? So, it's
[SPEAKER_00] either male or it's female. There's no third gender. Right? So, in the English language, we don't have, objects don't have a gender. Right? A pen doesn't have a gender. The musket doesn't have a gender. But in the Arabic language, everything has a gender. Right? So, the musket. The word masjid is mudhakar. It is masculine. The word shams, which is sun, is feminine. Right? So, every single object, every single thing, every single noun, it has a gender. So, now when we say hadha, this is something called, first, we explain what it means. It means this. Right? But just to explain it a little bit more, this is from a family called ism al-ishara. I'm calling it a family, but it's basically like a category in the Arabic language. It's called ism al-ishara. Ism al-ishara means words that are used to indicate toward things. Ishara, those who know Urdu as well, ishara also means to point at something, to indicate towards something in the Urdu language as well.
[SPEAKER_00] So, ishara, ism al-ishara is a noun that's indicating towards something. Right? So, this is a whole family. We're going to be introduced to each member of the family as we go along, inshallah. So, hadha is the first member of the family that we're being introduced to. Of isma al-ishara, the ism al-ishara, those words that are indicating towards things. So, hadha is this. So, when we say this, usually you're referring to something which is close to you. Right? If I was pointing at brother Shamik in the back, I wouldn't say this is Shamik. I would say that is Shamik because he's far away from me. But brother Javid, I would say this is Javid because he's right. Right? So, that's the difference between this and that. So, the same thing in the Arabic language. We'll learn that later on. But hadha is this. So, the first thing it's indicating towards is something which is close rather than something which is far. Right? That's one thing that we get out of hadha.
[SPEAKER_00] The second thing is that it is singular. Right? If you were to point at two things which are male and the close, you would use a different word. If you were pointing at three or more things that are close and male, then you would use a completely different word too. Right? So, hadha is only used for something which is singular, meaning one and male. Right? That's two things now we learned from hadha. Right? First of all, that it's male. And, sorry, I gave you guys the third one. First of all, that it's close. And second of all, that it is singular. The third thing that it gives us is that it is male. Right? So, baitun. Now we learned that bait is actually a word that is... Male in the Arabic language. Masjid, similarly. All these words that are mentioned here, now we know that they're male because the word hadha is being used to describe them. If you were to be using... If you were to be describing something which was female, then you would use a different
[SPEAKER_00] word which we're going to learn very soon, inshallah. So, now who can tell me what are the three things we learned from the word hadha? Tell me one thing. Male, okay. Anybody else? Close, good. Singular. Very good. Very good, mashallah. So, that's what we get from the word hadha. And if any one of these three things change, then we'll be using a different word. And we'll learn each of these words gradually as time goes on. But the author is starting with the easiest, hadha. And so, that's what we're starting with. So, now, the author is assuming that you're next to a house. And he's saying... And you're telling them, this is a house. Or, he's saying, you're looking at the book, so this is meaning a picture of a house. Right? So, hadha. So, all this vocabulary, you just need to memorize it. Right? There's no other way to learn it. As we mentioned in the beginning, in the beginning, vocabulary has to be memorized. As time goes on, then you can naturally acquire more vocabulary as well. But in the beginning,
[SPEAKER_00] when you're first learning a language, there's no shortcut around memorizing vocabulary. Unless you're going about it through a complete immersion route, like little children learn. But that's only if you'll be able to spend time in an environment where... Everybody speaks only Arabic, which won't be possible for us. That's why we're sitting here in class. Otherwise, we would have done that a long time ago. So, in a situation that we're in, the only way we can acquire vocabulary is first and foremost to memorize. Then we'll see, inshallah, while we're learning, going through this book, some words would be repeated in different contexts so much. Maybe in the first time, we'll have to ask what it means the second time. But after a while, it'll be repeated so much that it'll automatically come to our mind. That's also another reason why I like this book. Because it helps you to... Acquire vocabulary naturally. Okay. So, now all this... And it's pretty easy to figure out what they mean because I don't even need to translate it for you because the picture of it is there. So, This is a house.
[SPEAKER_00] This is a masjid. This is a door. This is a book. This is all very simple. Do I need to translate any of these for you? Anybody? Can you make out what the picture shows? Yeah, so that we're going to get into more detail, inshallah, why they end up with tanween, right? Why is why are we not saying hadhal masjidu, right? Why are we not saying al-masjidu? Why are we saying masjidun, right? And what's the difference between saying al-masjidu and masjidun? That's going to come in a future lesson. We don't want to get confusing because we just want to this main point, which is being indicated towards here, which is ism al-ishara. Hatha refers to what things? Yeah, what was it? Yeah. Sorry? Yeah. Hatha is singular. Yeah. How do we figure out the vocabulary alone?
[SPEAKER_00] Oh, so that I mean, for now, I'm going to be telling you all the vocabulary in the beginning, right? Once we progress a little bit, then inshallah, I'm going to have everybody get a dictionary that Brother Hussain asked about. In the last class, once you get that dictionary, you can't just use it, there's a way you have to learn how to use it. It's a bit of a process. That's why I'm not telling you guys now, because it's only once you guys get a little bit of grasp of the language, we'll be able to even use that dictionary. There's other dictionaries, too, but they're honestly not really great. I've used multiple dictionaries and that dictionary is the best one, but you cannot use it right now. As a beginner, you're going to be completely lost once you learn the basic some basic concepts and self, then inshallah, you'll be able to access. That dictionary and be able to look up words yourself, so I don't even have to sit here and tell you, you'll be able to just look it up in the dictionary. But for now, you just have to rely on me. All right, so all these I don't need to translate these, right? Column is pen, hatha miftahun is a key,
[SPEAKER_00] hatha maktabun is a desk, hatha sirirun, this is a bed, hatha kursiyun, this is a chair. Everybody got all that, right? But everybody understand the concept of hatha, right? So what I say? Hatha Umar, would I say hatha Umar? No. Why? Because he's further away from me, right? Would I say hatha Zeeshan? Yes, because he's much closer to me. Would I say hatha Mustafa? Yes. Would I say hatha Shiraz? No, because he's further away. Obviously, it's kind of relative. Somebody could say he's actually pretty close to you, so you can say hatha. It's not a big deal, but it makes more sense. When we're talking about further things, right? But this is just to explain to everybody in the class. All right, this is still part of the first lesson. We're going to get to the next part now. You can turn the page to page six. Well, I just realized I have the
[SPEAKER_00] markers. I didn't even write those three things down. But hopefully all of you already wrote them down, inshallah. All right, ma hatha. Who wants to read now? Somebody else. All right. No, you don't have to translate. You can just read it. Ma hatha. Hatha baikon. Hatha baikon. Hatha baikon. Hatha. Hatha. Tabitha. Hatha. Hatha. Sarirun. La. Hatha. Hursiyun. Hatha. Niftahun. La. Hatha. Talam.
[SPEAKER_00] Ma hatha. Hatha. Najmun. Okay. I feel bad. I should have realized since most of us don't have the book, we should have maybe had it on the PDF on here or something. Okay. So everybody could follow. Follow along what's going on. But inshallah from next class, everybody will have the books, inshallah. But I didn't. It was an oversight on our part. We should have had something to make sure everybody's following along. I didn't realize everybody didn't have the book. Anybody wants to follow along? You could get the PDF on the book. Yeah. PDF is easily found online. If you want to figure out what's going on in class right now, just search up Medina books, Medina course, PDF, volume one, and you can easily find it. Very easily. There's multiple PDFs online, or you could just write Arabic course or whatever. There's multiple names that this series is known by. It's a very famous series. So if you want to follow along on, on PDF, you can easily find it online, inshallah. Okay. Now what is being explained over here?
[SPEAKER_00] As we can easily see with the question mark at the end. Now, before it's just an affirmative sentence. You're just saying something, you're stating something. Hatha Baitun. This is a house, right? You're just stating it, right? You're stating a fact. Ma hatha. Ma hatha. Now it's a question mark. Now it becomes a question. And in Arabic, this is another family that we're being introduced to, right? The first family we were introduced to was? What was the first family that we were introduced to? Ism al-ishara. Right? The family that likes to point fingers at other people, right? The family that indicates towards others, right? Now we're coming to a family that loves to ask questions, right? So, these are called ism al-istifham, ism is the singular and asma is plural. So if you want to be more technically accurate, you can say asma al-istifham, those words that indicate towards a question. Or you can say asma al-ishara for the first family,
[SPEAKER_00] which is those words or nouns that are indicating towards something, pointing at something. What's the second one? Asma al-istifham. Al-istifham. Al-istifham means to ask a question, to ask about something. So, again, these technical terminologies will come in handy later. Right now, you just need to understand the basic terms, but it's still good to write these things down because, again, like I said, as we progress later, later on, we're going to start, I'm explaining things in English, but slowly, slowly, I'm going to start explaining things in Arabic. I'm going to use Arabic terms for things. And then at some point, inshallah, just as my teachers, what they did towards the end, towards the end of this book, towards the third volume, they actually started teaching us in Arabic as well. So inshallah, once we get there, we hope that we are also at that point, then also we'll start teaching in, we'll start learning in Arabic, like I'll literally be teaching you in Arabic and you'll have to answer me in Arabic, right? You might think, how can that be possible?
[SPEAKER_00] But it's easily possible, inshallah. So that's why it's good to know these terms. These are the grammatical terms, the technical terms that are going to be used. And inshallah, if we want to go forward in our knowledge, if you want to start reading, reading a little higher level things, then you're going to need these terminologies. Okay. So this, now, ma hadha, he's introducing a new family here, which is the family of, that likes to ask questions, asma'ul istifham. So ma hadha, very simply, ma means what, what is this, right? What is this? So when you're asking a question about a thing, then you say the word ma, right? Now this is different from when you're asking about a person. A person who has intellect. Ma is used to ask about things which have no intellect, right? Everybody understand that? Ma is used to ask about things that have no intellect. So if you're asking about a carpet, you would use the word ma. If you're asking about the masjid, you use the word ma.
[SPEAKER_00] If you're asking about a car, you would use the word ma. Like what is that? Right? So you would use the word ma. If you're asking about Mustafa, what would you use? You would not use ma. Right? You would use a different word, which we'll get to, insha'Allah. So ma is not used to ask about people or anything with an intellect. Ma is used for, you could say objects, but better is things without intellect because even animals and stuff could be technically used for, with ma. You get it? So that's why we don't necessarily say objects. So yeah. So ma means what is this? So ma hadha. So now when you say ma, then. And what is this? And this is, when you're asking something, when you have no idea what it is, you're saying ma hadha. What is this? Then the next, then hadha baytun, right? We already learned that in the first section, which is, this is a house. Now the next question is, a hadha baytun, right? So this looks almost exactly the
[SPEAKER_00] same as the previous sentence, but the only difference is what? The a, right? The Hamza. So what does that Hamza do? It's very simple. That Hamza is also part of this ma family. So you can add it to that family. We got introduced to a second member of the Asma'ud Istifham family that loves to ask questions, which is the Hamza. So what does the Hamza do? It just turns a normal sentence like this, in which somebody's indicating towards something into a question, right? It turns whatever sentence, it doesn't have a specific meaning in and of itself, right? So ma is different. Ma has a meaning, which is what, right? You're asking about something specific about an object. A doesn't have a meaning in and of itself. All it does is it turns that sentence into a question, right? So for example, hat over here, yeah, sorry to interrupt, but I have to go, yeah, no problem. Yeah, we're going to, inshallah, we're going to wrap up in a minute or just once I explain this last thing, then the lesson is over. So a,
[SPEAKER_00] the Hamza, this is called Hamzatul Istifham, right? It is the Hamza that causes the sentence to turn into a question, right? So now you're saying, ahadha baytun, right? So now let's say you're pointing at a building, you're saying, ahadha baytun. So that means you're not a hundred percent sure, it's not like you don't have any idea what it is. You're, you have a general idea that it might be a house, but you're not sure. So you're asking to make sure, right? So ahadha baytun, is this a house? Then the answer is what? Naam, right? Everybody knows what naam means. Everybody, when they try to act like they know Arabic, they all say this one word, right? Naam, right? You go to Saudi Arabia, you talk to the guard, naam, naam, naam, you try to act like you know what we're talking about, right? So naam, hadha baytun, yes, this is a house, right? So it's pretty straightforward again, ahadha baytun just means, is this a house? It just turns whatever sentence it comes into
[SPEAKER_00] a question. So is this a house? Naam, hadha baytun. Now ma hadha hadha khamis, that's simple. Is this? This is a shirt. Now the next question, this is important, this is slightly different, ahadha sarirun, he's pointing at this picture over here, right? He's asking ahadha sarir, if you remember from the previous page, sarirun means bed, right? And I want everybody, inshaAllah, part of the homework, if somebody can write it down, you can write it down, part of the homework is to memorize all the vocabulary in this lesson so far, up to pages five and six. Whatever vocabulary is there. I want you to, everybody to memorize it, inshaAllah, alright? So sarir means bed. So now, ahadha sarirun, is this a bed? Everybody look at that picture, is that a bed or not? No. No. I'm not sure how somebody could even mistake that for a bed, but anyways, the purpose is for us to learn,
[SPEAKER_00] right? So the person asks, ahadha sarir? The answer is, la. Right? Many, hopefully all of us know what this means as well. La means? No. Right? Hadha kursiyun. Like I'm also trying to teach, trying to teach my kids Arabic, but I keep getting lazy and forgetting to talk in Arabic, but the one thing they know is naam and la, right? Some simple easy things, right? So la means no. No. So you're answering the question, he's asking, is this a bed? And the answer is la. No. Hadha kursiyun. This is a? What is a kursi? Chair. Chair. Alright. Then, ahadha miftah? Is this a? Key. Miftah means key. So now over here, it's a little less straightforward. You need to know the vocabulary to know what's going on over here. In the previous one, you don't even need a vocabulary because the picture is right above it. But now over here, you need to know the vocabulary because you need to know what's being asked and what is actually the case. So ahadha miftah, he's asking, is this a key? So everybody look here
[SPEAKER_00] at that picture. Is that a key? No. No. So what would be the answer? La. La. Hadha? Qalamun. Qalamun. This is a pen. And then the last question was, ma hadha? Right. So anybody know this? Najmun. Mashallah. Very good. So how would you give the full answer? Hadha najmun. Hadha najmun. Very good. This is a star. Alright. So, alhamdulillah we have finished that, the first part of the first lesson. Part two of the first lesson is on page, starts on page ten. If you see. Ma hadha hadha masyun man hadha hadha tajus. Introducing another word, but that we'll do in the next lesson inshallah. So for now we finish this first part of the first lesson. So again homework is, memorize all the vocabulary and I will be asking you about the vocabulary next class inshallah. We have all the way till Monday. And then you see where it says tamreen. Tamreen means practice.
[SPEAKER_00] So tamreen means practice exercises. So we're going to be doing all the tamreen. It means all the practice exercises, not like school where teacher will tell you, okay, you can do the first one, second. We're going to do every single practice exercise inshallah. So likewise, we want to do the tamreen numbers one, two, and three, right? Which is on page seven, eight, and nine, the top of page nine. So what, what is a tamreen? Right? It's very simple. The first part of the, I'm just explaining how to do the homework, right? This will also help you practice your Arabic writing, right? Because we mentioned that if you really want to master a language, you need to read, write, and speak the language, right? So we need to practice writing as well. So this will help your practice writing. So this, you can easily just fill in, in your book itself. That's the easiest way to do the homework unless you're some, some people, they, they're really against writing in books. You know, they want to, they don't want to touch their books. I'm someone who writes in their books all the time, writes notes and everything in
[SPEAKER_00] their books. But if you want to keep your book clean and nice and new, then you can write it in your notebook inshallah. So the question here, it says, so then it shows a picture. So you have to just answer the question, right? And once you memorize the vocabulary, it should be easy for you to answer the question, right? Then it shows a book, so you have to answer the question. This is a blank, right? It shows that picture. You have to figure it out. Um, and the pictures are pretty accurate, so you don't have to be like, what is this even showing? Yeah, exactly. Then tamreen number two is, they're asking you to answer the question, right? They're asking you, it's showing a masjid over there, and it's asking, what does that mean? What does mean? Yeah. Is this a masjid? So the answer would be, no, this is, no, if the question is, then the answer would be, right? So in the same way, you finish the other questions.
[SPEAKER_00] Lastly, um, the tamreen number three. Three, it just says, we all know means? Read. means to write, right? So it's ordering, it's telling us to read and write this, right? I think it just, this is not so important. It just wants us, I guess, to practice our writing, right? So it's not so important. The more important ones are, tamreen number one and two. So make sure you complete tamreen number one and two, and memorize all the vocabulary. That's your homework for this upcoming week, inshallah. And also to memorize the rule, right? We just, we didn't memorize. There, there wasn't too many rules this time, right? Just hadha is part of which family? And then what are the three things that it teaches us, right? Then ma, right? Which family is that part of? And what does it indicate towards? And then ah, hamza, right? What does that indicate towards? And that's basically it for today, inshallah. Everybody got that? Any other questions? Is there a difference between like, you know, on
[SPEAKER_00] the first page, it says, so, I would say, so we have to say, so yeah, so technically, if you're like, normally when, when Arabs or even anybody who's speaking Arabic or reading Arabic, they don't normally pronounce the last the, especially with the, at the end of a sentence, you don't normally pronounce the, the, the at the end, right? But however, even my teachers would recommend and many ulama, they recommend that when you're learning the language. Okay. One of the most important things in Nahu and when you're learning grammar is to know what is the harakah at the end of the word, right? So because of that, just to practice so that you know what the harakah is at the end of the word, you should read it all out completely. So you should say Najmun, right? That's when you're learning, but on a regular basis, if you're, you know, reading a book, if you're doing all the things, then you don't necessarily have to read the last harakah of it. Any other questions?
[SPEAKER_00] I only read Arabic once. Okay. So with the Indo-Pak script, so is there a way to figure out, like, the meaning of the presentation? Oh, uh, meaning, meaning, oh, I was just saying, this is confusing to read for you? Yeah, yeah. Oh, okay. Uh, so, because this is the Arab style, that's why you're saying, I'm not sure if they made this book in that other style. Uh, so that's a good question. Uh, honestly, if you, if it'll take a little bit of time, but it's just, it's, it's, it's, it's not too hard to pick up, inshallah, just, just keep at it, inshallah, and you should be able to do it, inshallah. That's a good point, though. I never thought about that. Sorry? Uh, you can ask brother Mustafa, brother Omar, brother Hassan, these are the organizers, so inshallah, they can help you with that, inshallah. Uh, somebody, uh, brother, you had a question? You had a question, brother? Anybody else have any questions? Uh,
[SPEAKER_00] we can end the class for today, inshallah, and, uh, hopefully you'll see all of you, or most of you on Monday, inshallah. Subh'anaHu Wa Ta-A'la be-P profundis, Subh'anaHu Wa Ta-A'la bi