[SPEAKER_00] As-salamu alaykum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatuhu Bismillah ar-Rahman ar-Rahim wa rahmatullahi wa barakatuhu Rasulullah salli ala rasulul kareem amma ba'al Sorry? What did you say? I had the handkerchief MashaAllah, what is this called in Arabic? For all the Gen Z brothers This is what a handkerchief is This is Al-Mandeel This is Al-Mandeel, yes Al-Mandeel al-Nazifun, MashaAllah Zakat for bringing that artifact Okay We spent some time checking the homework Because I'm just trying to make a point that I want everybody to be doing the homework I want you to feel bad if I ask you Did you do the homework and you didn't do it So please, whoever is not doing it Please start doing it Because otherwise you're not getting anything out of this class If you really want to benefit Then you have to do the homework Otherwise you'll And
[SPEAKER_00] I'm already seeing it You'll quickly start seeing that those who are doing the work And putting in effort outside of class They're going to be way ahead of you And you're still going to be struggling to pick up the concepts And then slowly, slowly Shaytan will put in your mind Ah, you're not getting much out of this anyways So just drop out And then you're not going to fulfill your goal of learning Arabic And two years later You're going to see MashaAllah these brothers Talking to each other in Arabic And reading the Quran and understanding They're going to be crying in Salatul Taraweeh And you're just going to be there like Oh man, I should have done my homework So don't be like that And do your homework inshaAllah Okay So And whoever I didn't get to check their homework InshaAllah if you want you can show me after class Or if you don't have time after class I don't mind You can even take a picture of your homework And send it to me You all have my number It's on the group So you can even take a picture of your homework And send it to me inshaAllah And I can check it for you inshaAllah Alright So What was the main Point That
[SPEAKER_00] we learned In Ad-Dursa Tharith Lesson number three Can somebody explain? Can you come here and explain to us As a teacher? Come on Can I say it? Okay, you can say it Like The The new word The The, okay Like If it's House in the Okay And then If you're saying The house Then The The door Goes into Like a So how does that happen? Yeah, so it turned into a Because you take away the The Is when you have And once you take one away It becomes one And you don't have the Sound anymore It just becomes Right? Okay, and what What does that signify In terms of meaning? Right? When we take away the What difference does it make? Indefinite What does that mean though? Explain to me In a sentence
[SPEAKER_00] Or explain it to me Like what that means General General, okay General or It's not something Which is specific Or known to the person Who's talking It could be It could refer to any For example If you're saying Rajulun Man It could refer to any man Can somebody give me an example Not in Arabic But in English Of how we would differentiate Between A person Versus the person Like Explain a scenario Not a scenario That I explained But Something new New slide Let's see if you understood The concept Okay Very good Mashallah The empire state building And the building Okay That's good But Actually you said The building Or a building A building So you would say A building Right? Yeah Okay, that works too But that's also Like you're Differentiating between A proper noun And just a regular noun Right? Bring another example Of a word Which is not a proper noun And you're Using it for A specific
[SPEAKER_00] thing And also An unspecific Yeah, but like You have to explain The context behind Both, right? Like Like I explained to you To you guys, right? Remember how I explained it? Sorry? Yeah But like Think of like An example Like a type of conversation Or Yeah Yeah, so like Can I mention The example you mentioned? Like back then So No, a different example Different example Alright, so I'll talk about Like this book Like say I gave them I gave like my friend This book to use And then tomorrow I'm meeting up with them I ask them Do you have the book? The book, okay Yeah, so it's Known in context Okay, very good And then A general example is You have a book Right? It could be like any book Can I borrow Like a book? Yeah There's no context behind Which book we're talking about So Okay So you're just bored And you want to read something You don't know what you want to read So then you say Can I
[SPEAKER_00] borrow a book? So yeah Good, mashallah Okay A school Is a location Where students learn The school where I go to Is a very long school Good, mashallah So if you're like If you're just talking in general To a group of people You know A school But then When you say the school And you're referring to That specific school That you go to Right? So the idea is Everybody understands That al is something Which is specific And when it doesn't have Al on it And it only has tanween on it Then this is something Which is unspecific And I gave multiple examples From the Quran So hopefully that concept Is understood, inshallah Then also We learned a lot of new vocabulary So I'm going to say the word in English You guys tell it to me in Arabic Big Kabirun Good, mashallah Small Sagirun Good, mashallah Heavy Saqilun Good, mashallah Light
[SPEAKER_00] Okay, broken Good, mashallah New Old Good, mashallah Hot Harun That's kind of easy It sounds like Har Like, you know It's hot Then Beautiful Jameelun Okay I know a lot of brothers Are going to try To say this I'm going to use this Word for something Don't use jameelun Use jameelatun Because that's for female, right? Okay Dirty Okay Cold Good, mashallah Close I'm hearing less and less voices Everybody else forgot or what? Close Close Okay, far
[SPEAKER_00] Okay, good Honestly, mashallah There's so many students It's hard for me to pick out specific people And usually only the same people Raise your hand over and over again So that's why I'm just letting everybody speak Rock or stone Good, mashallah Boy Okay, teacher Okay Imam Okay Okay Okay Okay Okay Sugar Sugar Sugar Okay Milk Milk Okay, good Donkey Okay How many of you guys use this On your siblings or somebody? Okay Horse Okay Bed Okay Camel Okay Okay Doctor Doctor
[SPEAKER_00] Student Student Two students Okay Key All right House Shirt Star Mashallah If you think about it You guys have learned already a lot of words Mashallah And as I mentioned to you We were mentioning examples last time from the Quran All these words Almost all of them are used in the Quran In the Quran too Right, so already it's only been a couple of weeks And you're already Memorizing a lot of vocabulary, mashallah So by the end of the first book You'll have made solid progress, inshallah I was trying to write the Arabic without looking So without looking And I just remember it's tabeebu Doctor's tabeebu So it's with toy, right? Ta, yeah Ta, right? But I started with the Ta So how do I know which one to use? That's one example, right? And then swa then si Again That's
[SPEAKER_00] another example So every time I know how to say it But when I write it I would use interchangeably Either ta, you know Very good question, right? Everybody understood the question? Yeah Right? So the answer is This is why I had mentioned a couple of classes ago That the ideal would be That before everybody started this class That everybody studied tajweed at a higher level, right? One is just generally Just knowing how to read, right? We all, mashallah When we were younger, most of us We learned how to read Arabic But the thing is A lot of times we don't learn it with tajweed Which is like the correct pronunciation Of each of the Arabic letters, right? Especially in the Indian subcontinent When we learn the Arabic language In Urdu, for example Ta and ta are like In pronunciation It's completely indistinguishable, right? It sounds exactly the same Ta and ta, right? They both sound like ta, right? And then Same thing with dha, baad, and z Right? They all sound pretty much the same, right? But when you
[SPEAKER_00] say it in Arabic The pronunciation is very different Dhaad is this, right? Then Dha is this Okay, I don't know what's wrong with the marker The marker is finally finished, so Now we have a marker to use Naam, ahsan Qalamun jadeedun Okay Dha And Za, right? And let's add dhal there, right? So in Urdu All four of these letters would pretty much sound the same Right? Right? So, and that's why Sometimes when you hear brothers From the Indian subcontinent reciting And maybe they haven't studied tajweed They will say like Right? Because All four of these letters sound exactly the same in Urdu But in Arabic They're very different, right? And it's very precise Like if you learn tajweed It tells you exactly where you put your tongue to make this sound Where you put your tongue to make this sound So this is Dhal
[SPEAKER_00] Za Dha And Dhaad Right? So they're very distinct letters Distinctly pronounced So Just by me pronouncing it For example, when we said doctor I said Tabib Right? If I was If it was To start with a dha If it was If this was a word Then I would say Tabib You get it? But I didn't say tabib I said tabib Right? So the key is in the pronunciation So That's why Again That's ideal That Even if you didn't learn it beforehand It's not too late Right? Mashallah There are some brothers Very soon Within about a week or so Or two Inshallah They're going to start Two hufal Mashallah That are sitting here right now They're going to start a tajweed class For adults So it's going to be very limited In terms of scope Like an amount of time For students Because There's just two teachers for now So If you're interested You can speak to Hafiz Mu'min
[SPEAKER_00] Inshallah If you're interested in the class But that would definitely help you With With If you're If you haven't learned tajweed before It would help you be able to Distinguish between The different You know Letters Inshallah But yeah So tajweed is basically the The answer as to how you would be able To differentiate Okay The bottom Oh It splits it Yeah This The meaning exists Sorry Both of them No this is This is This doesn't exist This word doesn't exist Yeah I just gave examples Saying that This is the actual word But if it was to be with a ta Because the brother was saying that When he wrote it He wrote it with a ta Right So he was asking me How do I know So the answer is The way you pronounce it It's ta Okay So yeah So we finished And hopefully everybody Did their homework Inshallah Now it's not the end of the lesson Sometimes in this book He'll divide a lesson Into two parts So it's basically like Two in one
[SPEAKER_00] But because they're related He won't have A completely separate lesson So let's start the second part Of the lesson Who wants to read We're on page sixteen On the bottom No no No below that Below that This is This is just the word box The new words Shua Where it is Shua Shua Shua Shua Shua Shua Shua Shua Shua Shua Shua Shua Shua Shua Shua Shua Shua Shua Shua Shua
[SPEAKER_00] or do you want me to say the last word? Okay. Alright. So, one very important thing that we're learning over here. This is also similar to what we learned before that as soon as you put in the alif naam, then what happens? Yeah, the mean goes away and you're left with only one haraka which is the dhamma, right? One pesh, one dhamma. And so you go from najmun to an-najmu, right? But there's another key thing that's being highlighted here which is that if it's pronounced correctly, then over here, the laam in the al, the laam is becoming silent, right? Silent. Like, you know, in English, you have sometimes letters that become silent. Give me an example of a word in which a letter is silent.
[SPEAKER_00] Known. Known. Very good, mashallah. Known, right? So, so if somebody's learning English for the first time, they learn all the alphabets and then you tell them to read this, what would they read it as? Known, right? But we all know that's not how you pronounce it. It's pronounced without the K, right? If you were to ask why, does anybody know the reason? No, not really, right? So similarly in Arabic, right, there are many things, that will be silent sometimes in pronunciation. So for amongst those things, is the laam in al, but not all the time. Only before specific letters. And that's what we're going to learn in this lesson, inshaAllah. Is that al-kharuf al-shamsi al-qamariya? Yeah, al-kharuf al-shamsi al-qamariya. I'm starting to get suspicious. I think you've probably studied Arabic before, haven't you? Alright, mashallah, it's good though.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay, so that's what we're going to learn today. What are the letters, before which al, the laam in al, becomes silent? And what are the letters, before which the laam in al, does not become silent? Alright, is that a tongue twister? Shall I repeat? So in certain words, whenever you have al, sometimes the laam is pronounced, and sometimes it's not pronounced. Okay? So in the previous part of the lesson, let's go back two pages, to page 14, right? If you read all those words that have al on them, let's see. Al-baytu, al-kitaabu, al-qalamu, al-jamalu, al-qalamu, al-baabu, al-waladu, al-mudarrisu. All these words that have al, is the laam silent or not? No, it's not silent. Now going back to where we were right now, page 16. Al-najmu, al-rajulu, al
[SPEAKER_00] -deeku, al-taalibu, al-najmu, al-rajulu, al-sukkaru, al-taalibu, al-deeku. So instead of actually pronouncing the laam, you're not pronouncing it, and then you're adding a shadda. You guys know what a shadda or a tashdeed is? Right? It basically indicates that you're kind of doubling the emphasis on that word, right? Or that letter, sorry. So this is called a shadda or a tashdeed. So instead of pronouncing the laam for these letters, you don't pronounce the laam, rather you go directly to the next word, the next letter, sorry, and that letter becomes emphasized with the shadda. Everybody got that? Okay. So what are the letters in which the laam becomes silent and what are those that it does not become silent? That's on page 19. Page 19. Those who studied tajweed probably have already studied this, right? You guys know this? Everybody who followed,
[SPEAKER_00] you guys know this? Or I guess it just became second nature once you started reading, right? Sorry? Yeah, so look at page 19. Everybody on page 19? So it says, Qamar means what? What does shams mean? Sun. The shams means the sun, right? So you can just make it easier for yourself. The moon letters are the letters in which the laam does not become silent. Meaning, you still pronounce it. And the sun letters are those words in which the laam does become silent. Okay? So basically, the only way to really know this is to just memorize it, right? Know which letters are qamariyya and shamsiyya. But there's a trick, right? You don't have to memorize all, because how many letters in the Arabic language? 28. 28 letters in the Arabic language. So
[SPEAKER_00] it's exactly half, half of them are shamsiyya and half of them are qamariyya, right? So what would be easier would just be to memorize one of the two, right? If you want to memorize the ones that become silent, then you can memorize that. Or if you want to memorize the ones that don't become silent, then you memorize that, right? But once you memorize one of them, then you got the other automatically, right? So it's kind of hard to memorize, but for those who have studied Hif or anything like that, how did you start to be able to differentiate? It's like second nature. Yeah, just because you continuously... I just said Hif, but I heard that the Shams letters have the tip of the tongue. Yeah, very good point, yeah. Sorry, I forgot to add that point, yeah. JazakAllah khayran for reminding me. So the letters in which the tongue is involved, either the tip of the tongue or the sides of the tongue, those are the letters in which it actually makes contact with the teeth.
[SPEAKER_00] Then those are letters that become Shamsiyah, meaning the tongue becomes silent, right? Instead of saying Al-Tajiru, you say At-Tajiru, right? And what's the reason behind this? The reason behind this is because the Arabs would hate Takalluf. They would hate, you know, kind of twisting your tongue and making it difficult to speak. There's so many things in the Arabic language that may seem strange and they're like exceptions to the rule. They only make those exceptions because the Arabs like to take shortcuts and they like to keep things easy when pronouncing things, right? So over here, instead of saying Al-Tajiru, right? It's like you have to twist your tongue because the tongue has to touch it in one way and another way right after, right? So instead of saying that, it just cancels out the Laam and just goes straight to the Ta, right? So you say At-Tajiru, At-Thawbu, At-Deequ, At-Zahabu, At-Rajulu, At-Zahratu, At-Samaku, At-Shamsu, At-Sadru,
[SPEAKER_00] At-Dayfu, At-Talibu, At-Zahru, At-Lahmu, At-Najmu, right? If you look at it, the tongue is involved in all of these, right? Whereas Al-Abu, right? So Hamza is a throat letter, A. So again, right over here, Tajweed is coming into play, right? Hamza is a throat letter, so Al-Abu. So it doesn't even make sense even if you tried to make it merge like these Shamsiya letters, it wouldn't really work. Al-Abu, right? You can't really do it, right? So if you think about it, it's very natural the letters that the Arabs chose to go along with the Laam, right? Okay, even Al-Babu, right? Ab-Babu, right? It doesn't really sound right, right? So Al-Babu. So the Ba comes from the lips, not the tongue, right? So Al-Babu, right? Al-Jannah, Jannah, right? That's with the teeth. Then Al-Himar is the throat, throat letter. Al-Khubzu, throat
[SPEAKER_00] letter. Ain, throat letter. Ghain, throat letter. Fa, this is where the teeth, they touch the lips, right? Fa, Qaf, throat letter. Kaf, right? From the back of the mouth. Meem, right? Just the lips. Waw, lips. Ha, throat letter. Ya, right? From the back of the mouth. So none of these letters involve the tongue, right? So that's something that makes it easier. JazakAllah khairan to Brother Ilyas for reminding me of that. That the letters that have, that are connected with the tongue, those are Al-Huruf Al-Shamsiya. You got it? So all those letters, you don't pronounce the Laam, you just go straight and it becomes a Shadda. Yeah. Can you write out a word just real quick if you want to try to help me with one? You know, generally. Okay. Alright.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay. So Al-Jannatu, right? Over here, does the Laam become silent or not? No. Al-Jannatu. In the next one, does it become silent or not? Yes. Al-Naaru. You don't say Al-Naaru, right? If you look at it, it's so close the way, where the tongue touches for both anyways, that it's very logical for the Arabs to just not pronounce the Laam and just go straight to the Noon. Al-Naaru. Al-Naaru. Even if you say the Laam, it sounds almost like you're not saying it. Al-Naaru. Al-Naaru. Right? So it makes sense. So just, yeah, the only way is to
[SPEAKER_00] just memorize it. If you don't memorize it, then at least just know which one the letters are when you see them. Right? It's kind of easy because when they're written down, like with the and stuff, then the letters that are will have the over here on it. Right? So if you see this right after a Laam, in the , then you'll know that, okay, this is one of the . And you don't have to pronounce the Laam. Right? I want you guys, when you read the Quran, somebody give me an example of an ayah that has a letter after . . Right? Right? Not . It's . Good. . Very good. Mashallah. So, it's not . No. . You get it? . . Very
[SPEAKER_00] good. Right? You don't say . You say . Good. Mashallah. . . Very good. Mashallah. Right? So you're not saying . You're saying . There's extra emphasis on the because you're not pronouncing the Laam. Good. Your half is ? Okay. Mashallah. All right. Anybody else? . . Good. Right? You're not saying . All right. Good. Last example. . . Very good. Mashallah. So you're not saying . You're saying . Everybody got it? . Okay. So just pay attention when you're reading Quran, inshallah. Hopefully all of us, we have a daily habit of reading Quran. If not, then we should definitely do so. Not just for Arabic purpose, but more importantly for our own spiritual well-being. Right? To build our connection with Allah . To purify our hearts. It's very important for us to have a regular
[SPEAKER_00] routine of recitation of Quran. So, and the bonus is that whenever we're reciting Quran, we can start implementing all these rules and start noticing all these things. If you don't do that, then all these will be theoretical and you're going to forget it after a bit. Right? Just like how many of you guys learned Spanish or another language in high school? Majority of you guys, right? How many of you guys actually remember most, like Spanish or how to speak it or use it like one brother, right? So, do we want the Arabic to become like that? Inshallah, every week, coming twice a week, you know, and sitting in class, spending 45 minutes, but then after a few years you'll be like, yeah, I remember studying Arabic once, but like, I can't remember anything. Do you want it to be like that? No. We want it to be something that we're living and every single day, you know, increasing and becoming connected to the Qur'an and implementing everything in the Qur'an, right? So, when we read the Qur'an, then let us implement, right? How many of you guys get excited every time you see in the Qur'an now?
[SPEAKER_00] Nobody? Right? So, every time you see now all of a sudden, you know, yesterday I read right? And then I met I was like, do you know where I said and he said, yeah, I know it, right? So, just watch out if you come one of the days, right? And same thing when we're reading Qur'an, let's try to note that, oh, this has a but am I pronouncing it? No. Okay. So, that means this is a letter. You guys got it? All right. So, yeah. So, besides the other rule that we already learned that makes it definite and leaving it makes it indefinite and has a on it. That's also something that we learned from this lesson. That before which the lamb becomes silent and those letters were in which before which it doesn't become silent, right? Now, let's read the rest of the lesson, right? Somebody volunteer or let's
[SPEAKER_00] do it turn by turn. All right. We're on page 17 now, 17 at the top. Everybody got it? Yeah, that from there. Okay, you're good. No. So, not but but Good. MashaAllah. Did you say is that saying the meaning or is it just wrong? It's just wrong. Yeah. All right. Anybody else? Quickly. Let's do it. Okay. Good. Not . It's . Okay. All right. Good. MashaAllah. . Good. Good. What is that? What is that? . Next one. . . Good. MashaAllah. . Right? . . Number
[SPEAKER_00] five. . . Good. MashaAllah. . What does that mean? Oh, sorry. We're not going to the vocabulary. Somebody translate number one. . Okay. Somebody said moon. It's not a moon. . A star. The star is far. . Number two. Brother Zuhayb, what's number... Can you translate number two? . The man is? . Oh, did we learn ? Yeah, we did. Yeah. means standing. All right. Good. MashaAllah. All right. . . Where does something along these lines come in the Quran? . . . Okay. What's the ayah? . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .
[SPEAKER_00] . . . . . . . . . . . Standing up. . . the man is standing. Okay. What does that mean? The sugar is sweet. Good. Mashallah. Alright, brother Abdul Wahab, number four. The student is sick. Okay, good. And Abdul Rahman, number five. No? Brother Ali, number five. Oh, I never told you guys what ad-dik means. Ad-dik means rooster, right? Wait, we did that. Okay, yeah, we did do that. Okay. So, no,
[SPEAKER_00] not the beautiful rooster. The rooster is beautiful, right? There's a difference between the beautiful rooster and the rooster is beautiful. What's the difference? Good. Brother Salim said one of them is an incomplete sentence. Which one is an incomplete sentence? The beautiful rooster, right? The beautiful rooster, right? The beautiful rooster, right? The beautiful rooster, right? Why is it an incomplete sentence? Because it doesn't express a thought. If I was to say, for example, this beautiful, okay, this handsome imam, then you would be waiting. What about him? Right? Right? But if I was to say this imam is handsome, then you'd be like, okay, that's a complete sentence. You're not waiting for something further. You get it? So, when you translate it, make sure you translate it as a complete sentence. So, the rooster is beautiful. Good. Do you write it differently? If you want to say the... Yeah, it's a good question. So, that's going to come, inshallah, in a few lessons.
[SPEAKER_00] How to say the beautiful rooster, right? That's going to come. Basically, as a spoiler, I'll just tell you, if you were to say that, you would say, adi kul jameeloo, al jameeloo. So, you would add al to it. All right? So, adi kul jameeloo means the beautiful rooster, but then you would require a third word to say it. So, you would say, adi kul jameeloo. So, you would say, adi kul jameeloo. To make it a complete sentence, right? For example, waqifun. Adi kul jameeloo waqifun. The beautiful rooster is standing. You get it? So, but don't worry about that right now. That's going to come after a couple of lessons. But for now, this sentence structure, you would translate it as is, right? The rooster is beautiful. Okay. Number six. Can somebody read it? Bilkhayam? Yeah. Ad dattar jadeeloo. Very good. MashaAllah. Ad daftar, it didn't come yet, right? Ad daftar means a notebook, right? Ad daftar means notebook.
[SPEAKER_00] Did somebody say office? Office. Yeah. In Urdu, it means office. So, people make that mistake usually, right? So, it's one of those times where sometimes you have awkward moments where people think, oh, Arabic Urdu, same thing, right? So, then one of my friends, he's Afghani. Actually, Mufti Rafiq, he's the Imam. So, he's Afghani. But he learned, he just picked up Urdu being around, you know, going to Jamaat and, you know, being around Ulema and stuff like that. He picked up Urdu like that. But he would, he said he would try to just take Arabic word and fit it and just hope that it's also Urdu as well. So, then one time somebody asked him that, oh, where is Sajid Sajid Moana? I haven't seen him for a while. He's like, oh, intiqal hogia, right? So, intiqal. Intiqal in Arabic means to move from one place to another. So, in Urdu, it also means that, but it's used in the context of dying, right? Because you move from
[SPEAKER_00] this life till here after, right? So, he said, oh, he moved. He was trying to say he moved away. But in Urdu, he actually said he died. So, the person was like, oh, he was so young, he passed away. And Rafiq was like, why is this guy bugging out? He just moved. And then after a while, then he was like, oh, no, no, no, no. He moved. He moved. So, translating Urdu in Arabic, trying to interchange them doesn't always work. So, just be careful. Exactly. Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. So, you use a different form. You say, exactly. Okay. So, daftar. Yeah, it's also Arabic. Yeah. Yeah. A daftar does not mean office. It means notebook, right? A daftaru jadeedun. What does that mean? Somebody translate it? A notebook is new. A notebook is new. Right. All right. Somebody new. Saqeef, yes. Good. At-tajiru
[SPEAKER_00] ghaniyun. Good. What does that mean, Brother Hassan? Yeah. Seven, seven. Sorry. The merchant is rich. Very good. Masha'Allah. The merchant is rich or the businessman is rich. Yeah. Ghani is used in Urdu, too. Yeah. Good. All right. Number eight. Brother Hanzala. Good. Good. So, you don't say al-dukkano, you say ad-dukkano, right? Okay. Who knows? Dukkan, we didn't learn yet. Ad-dukkan. But this is in Urdu, too. So, yeah, same. Let me get excited now. Dukkan means shop, right? Ad-dukkan means a shop. Okay. So, ad-dukkan means a shop and maftuhun
[SPEAKER_00] means open, right? So, the store is open. All right. So, again, you're already, the amount of vocabulary we've learned already, you can actually start having very basic conversations in Arabic, right? So, let's say, you know, Brother Hussain is trying to go to the deli, right? So, then, you say, like, you say, oh, like, everybody's like, oh, let's go, let's go get some ice cream or some drinks, right? So, then, somebody would say, oh, but the store is closed. So, Brother Hussain can be like, no, ad-dukkano maftuhun, right? Because the 7-Eleven is open till late, right? So, you can say, ad-dukkano maftuhun, right? So, we can start using these words on a regular basis, inshallah. Sorry to call you. Okay. Then, number nine. Who can read it? Okay. Al-waladu faqirun. Good. So, wait a minute. Aren't we doing Shamsi words? Why is it being wow there? Just to show the difference, right? So, al
[SPEAKER_00] -walad is not a Shamsi letter. It is not one that becomes silent. So, you say the laam, al-waladu, right? Otherwise, it would be kind of awkward, like, aw-waladu. It just sounds off, right? So, al-waladu faqirun. Brother Ilyas, what does that mean? Al-waladu faqirun. The boy is poor? Yeah. The boy is poor, yeah. So, walad can mean, depending on the context, if you're using it, like, in the context of your own son, you say waladi, my son, right? So, walad can mean son. That's a good point. Or it can mean boy. So, you just have to look at the context, right? Just in general, any little boy could be walad. Or it can mean son. If you say, if you use it in a context of Idaafa, like, but that's the next, not the next lesson, the lesson after next will be about possession, right? Yeah. So, if you say waladuhu or waladi, his walad, his boy would mean his son, right? Okay. So, but in this context, without Idaafa, then it would just mean the
[SPEAKER_00] boy is poor. Okay. Bunayya is your son? Bunayya is my son, yeah. Like in Surah Al-Kahf? Yeah, in Surah Yusuf. Yeah. Okay. You want to read? Okay, go ahead. At-tufahu lazeezun. Good. Lazeezun, yeah. And it is sweet. Yeah. Lazeezun means tasty, right? And this is also kind of in Urdu, right? Lazeez, right? But this is with a dhal. Lazeez, right? Lazeez. But yes, it also means, it means tasty, not sweet. Hulwun is tasty, is sweet. But lazeez just means tasty, right? Lekka chowz is lazeez, right? What does tufah mean? Apple, good question. At-tufah means apple, alright?
[SPEAKER_00] Where does this come in the Qur'an, Mustafa? At-tufah. What is tufah? It doesn't come in the Qur'an. Alright, alright. Number 11. Um, how many of you guys know Brother Shiraz? I don't know. Don't worry, we're ending class very soon, inshaAllah. Don't get worried. Please don't help, I want everybody to read on their own, just so they can get the concept. Good, inshaAllah. So the first one is Shamsi At-tabeebu, right? But the second one is not Shamsi, so it's Al-Mareebu. Okay? So, Tawil, did we learn it yet? No. No, we didn't learn it yet, right? Tawil means tall, Tawil. Qasir means short. Qasir means
[SPEAKER_00] the opposite, it means short, right? In this middle one, right? In that wall or here, you know, I'm not good without the hasmals, right? So how do I say that again? Which one? Wal-Mareebu. Oh, Wal-Mareebu Qasirun. So how do I know if it's a kid? Yeah, I mean, that's, we're going to start learning it slowly, how to be able to, after a while, like, towards the end of the book, you'll see that they're going to start taking it out completely, like, all the, but that's part of learning Arabic, right? Like, let me just show you an Arabic book from here. Yeah, so this is a book in Hanbali Fiqh, right? Al-Mughnibai ibn Qudamah, right?
[SPEAKER_00] So just look at it, whoever wants, you guys can pass it around, pass it around to everybody. By the end of, inshaAllah, hopefully, we'll be able to learn it. Hopefully, by the end of this course, and maybe with some more practice, you should be able to read that pretty comfortably without any Fatah Qasirun Dhamma, right? It seems like, wait, how is that possible? What is this, magic or something? But it's possible, right? That's the whole reason we're learning Arabic. That's one of the most important, essential things, right? So just take a look and pass it around. So, yeah. What is the number one? Sorry? Yeah. Al-Tawil means tall. The doctor is tall. Wa al-Mareed. Al-Mareed means? Sick person. You can say patient in this context. We're just talking about the doctor. But yeah. Mareed generally is used in the context of a sick person. Who is a patient, I guess. But not all sick
[SPEAKER_00] people go to the doctor. So not all sick people are necessarily patients, right? So, yeah. So translation is going to be, The doctor is tall and the patient is short. Yeah. Good. Because there is a waal. The doctor is tall and the sick person is short. Yeah. The doctor is, yeah, tall and the sick person, the patient is short. Yeah. Like you told us, waal is and, right? Yeah. In English. Waal is and, yes. And the sick person is, you can say patient, is short. Okay. All right. So now the homework is, and please, inshallah, I want to see 100%. I don't want to hear anybody saying, oh, sorry, I didn't do it. We're not going to accept that excuse anymore. So the homework is to, again, it's very simple. Literally, if you, even
[SPEAKER_00] if you were to sit right after, don't pray your sunnah, maybe pray your sunnah at home and just sit after. I'm not saying you should do that. I do see some brothers doing that. But as long as you do it, right, if you're doing it right before class. But even if you were to do it in that time, I think you probably could get it done, right? But obviously, it's not ideal. The better is to sit at home, concentrate, and actually be able to implement all the rules. That's the best thing. But it honestly does not take much time. Those who did the homework, how long did it take you? Somebody tell me. Twenty-five minutes. Twenty-five minutes. Okay. Anybody else? Thirty minutes. Thirty minutes. Okay. Yeah. So 25, 30 minutes. It's, remember, right? There's not so much, right, if you think of what you're getting out of it, right? But if you don't do this, then it's really going to harm you moving forward, right? You might think that, ah, I can catch up. I can figure it out. But you're not going to get much out of it. Okay. So what is the first tamreen? It's similar to the previous one. You just put the haraq at the end, right? The ideal is to rewrite it. Some brothers did it
[SPEAKER_00] in the book. That's fine too. But the ideal is to rewrite it in your notebook. Al-ba-boo, right? So. You put one dhamma, right? You would say. You would do it like this. Al-ba-boo. Make it very clear. It's only one. Right? Why is it only one? Because definitely. Because of al. Because of this, we only write one dhamma. Right? And same thing with the others. Right? So just, that's what you have to do for this one. And then the second one, you just fill in the blank. Right? So. You don't have, they don't have a word bank this time. So you just have to figure it out yourself. You just have to. What would, what would fit with ghani? Ghaniyun. Ghaniyun means rich. So what would fit with it? Al-tajiru. You could say al-tajiru. You could say al-rajulu. But something. Right? Sorry? Al-imamu. Al-imamu. If, if you've ever seen a rich imam. But yeah. I'm joking. I'm joking. Alright.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay. Number three. Ikhtar karimatan mil-qaima. Okay. So. For this one. You just have to. You know. It's like. You know. When you were younger. You used to have like. You fit this one. With that one. This one. With that one. Like. Let me give you an example. Okay. It's gonna take too long. But you just have to connect. Yeah. You just have to connect. This. Put a line. Drawing where. Which one it should connect to. Right? Which one fits with it. Would you say. At-talibu lazeedun. Lazeedun means tasty. Right? Would you say. At-talibu lazeedun. No. Right? At-talibu maksoorun. The student is broken. Maybe in certain cases. But. Not. Generally. Right? At-talibu saqeelun. Maybe. I mean. It's possible. Right? I don't wanna be judgmental or anything. Then. At-talibu maftoohun. No. Open. Not really. At-talibu mareeedun. No. Yeah. It's possible. Right? At-talibu.
[SPEAKER_00] Harun. Harun. That's how you say it. Hopefully not. Okay. So. Basically. You just put a line. And connect it to. Whatever. Where. It fits with it. Alright? So. You should end up with like a web. Like you. Used to do it in kindergarten. First grade. So, we're back at that level again. Okay. So, just learn. And learn the vocabulary. The vocabulary is all over here. Right? If you don't remember any of the vocabulary. Harun means sweet. I don't remember where that came up. But anyways. It's just. حلوة means sweet. السكر حلوة. Sugar is sweet. مريض means sick. الدكان means a store. غني means rich. طويل means tall. فقير means poor. قصير means short. And التفاح means apple. Apple. And try to, even if you don't memorize these حروف شمسين قمع, just try to get an idea. You can just look over them. Just try to get an idea. Okay, this letter I
[SPEAKER_00] have to make sure I don't connect it. Do we have to learn anything else about the شمسين قمع? Letters? I can see them how it seems in the video. No, that's enough for this lesson for now. Yeah, that's the main thing you have to learn. Okay, and then, number 20. We don't have to do that as a tamreen. I'll test you guys on it next week, right? I mean, today's what, Monday? Sorry, on Wednesday. Sorry? The quiz is next Monday, inshallah. Yeah. So remember, guys, anybody start making a vocabulary list or no? I can't make one. Okay, somebody can start, inshallah. Alright, let's end the class. سُبْحَانَ اللَّهُ بِحَمْدِي سُبْحَانَكَ اللَّهُ مَنْ بِحَمْدِيكَ نَشْدُوَ لَا إِلَهَ إِلَهَ إِلَىٰ تَنَسْتَغْفِرُ فَدُوا بِلَيْكَ Yeah. What do we do on page one?
[SPEAKER_00] What do we do? On page 20, you said, do you have to test this on it? Oh, bro. Yeah, you're not going there. I mean, you just have to know. Basically, what you have to do is, they're just testing if you know it. No, if it's Shamsi or somebody. So, I'll bait you or I'll bait you. I'll give you another pen. Madam, why don't we ask you, for when you record, we have a question. Oh, for like video recording? Okay, yeah. Maybe you could consider that. I'll let you know, inshallah. Yeah. Okay. Thank you.