[SPEAKER_00] As-salamu alaykum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatuh. I feel like a lot of people in class, I feel like that last example, kind of like organic chemistry, the medical student who was walking away, so, I mean, I've obviously never done the, you know, medicine, but I've heard that organic chemistry is like the lead-up class, like if you get through organic chemistry, then you're going to make it through med school, but if you don't make it, then that's it, right? I feel like maybe this last step.
[SPEAKER_00] I kind of like that, because after the test, attendance hasn't been the greatest, so, is this going to be our class? Well, but, in short, let's try to encourage our brothers not to lose hope, despite whatever score we may have gotten, right? They should not despair of us, right? We should always find ourselves, but our original motive, like why are we studying, right? Somebody remind me, why are we studying? To speak to the security guard, right? No? Absolutely. To speak to the security guard, right? To speak to some, I mean, people at the Baha'u'llahs? No, to go overseas and teach English. Okay, that's another option, to go overseas and teach English. No, so what is our intention? Let me remind us of our real intention. Namaz and quran. Okay. Namaz and quran, yeah. So, we tell them we are coming, we're not, we're not watching the imam to finish reprying. Mm, yeah, Michelle.
[SPEAKER_00] And so that when, you know, some brothers in this class are crying, why don't we look at them like, man, I also understood what was going on, right? But at the end of the day, again, the purpose is for us to build a much stronger connection to the Qur'an. And that's a hadith that the Baha'u'llah is going to send us. And I think there's so much, so many more benefits to Arabic. I don't want to do everything, but, I mean, there's so many times where, like, I read a seer book in Arabic, and I'm just, I literally just, from the bottom of my heart, I just do shukr to Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala. Allah gave me the ability. The ability to access these treasures, because it's so amazing, like, when you guys hear it in the English language, and, like, I've heard all the speakers and what they talk about, it's like a fraction of what's in the actual books. When you actually read it, I'm like, man, nobody even, like, talks about this stuff. This is like, these are gems, these are amazing things that are in these seer books, explained upon such a deep level. And you're just, like, astounded and amazed. And again, so many times, one is your heart makes genuine draw for these ulamas. Like, what
[SPEAKER_00] efforts they did to explain upon such a beautiful, amazing way. And also, you genuinely make, you think of what Allah gave you, the access, the ability, the tools to access these amazing treasures. And even besides, even if you just leave out the Quran and Hadith, which is the main aspect, even just building a connection to the ummah at large, right? Because, just like how they say English is an international language, like, if you go to any country, you speak English. Arabic is the language of the ummah. Right? Whatever country you go to, there's going to be somebody, even if they're very small, maybe it's just scholars, there's going to be somebody that speaks Arabic. So, and like, that builds your connection to so many different parts. You can access scholarship from so many different parts of the world, whether it be their books, or whether it be even their lessons. There's so, and even besides that, you know, you can get connected through news, and so many other things, beneficial things that you can access when you have the Arabic language, that you cannot do so. Uh, in
[SPEAKER_00] English. When you're, when you only know English, then you're basically at the mercy of the translators, right? And it's not, somebody might want to be at the mercy of any kind of portrait. Sometimes they're not, not saying that all translations are bad, but when you actually learn Arabic to a much higher level, and you probably understand things, then you read somebody's translation of the Quran, translation of the Hadith, you just get shocked, like, this is conveying the wrong meaning, or this is not conveying the full picture. Um, So, the thing is, you're eliminating that, um, that middleman, right? That middleman who many times obligates you wrong. Um, So, Just some motivating things to think about, inshaAllah, and remind us that we should, inshaAllah, continue to be motivated and try to attend, and also to encourage others to attend as well, inshaAllah, if Allah is the Merciful. Okay, so, we had, so, those who have done a hundred, one more time, just remind me. There were, there were, okay,
[SPEAKER_00] one, two, three, three, and four, three also, five, one, how many were total, six, oh, six, okay, there were seven in total, right, did we get seven? Okay, so, I went to South Africa over the weekend, and I was kind of crazy, but yeah, I went to South Africa, um, that's why I wasn't here on Monday, so, um, I brought some special gifts for you guys, but unfortunately I forgot to bring it right now, um, but, um, inshaAllah, next class, I will bring it for, for God's good effort, and it's one of the main brothers, you know, Salim isn't here, so it wouldn't be right to give it without him, so, he's the means of all of you guys getting hundreds, inshaAllah, so, um, so we're waiting for him to come back, inshaAllah, um, and, uh, but yeah, it's also some good stuff that you guys will be happy, uh, inshaAllah, and the more we address you guys, inshaAllah, next time, you guys will also get hundreds, inshaAllah, right? Everybody say inshaAllah. InshaAllah. InshaAllah. Okay.
[SPEAKER_00] So what was the homework last time? A lot. Five, five, next five tasks or something. It was a lot of things, right? Up until the next lesson, I think. Okay, so where do we start? Which one are we going to be passing? Which one? Four, five, six. Four, five, six. Okay, four, five, six. Let's go through it very quickly. Okay, it should be quick. Precaution? Number one? Uh, we are passing. We are passing. We are passing. Okay, but the first one is supposed to be a question, right? Iman hada alqalamu. Good. Iman hada alqalamu. Ha? Hada alqalamu li'adil. Very good, inshaAllah. All right, that's good. Next one? I'm not sure what he was, but I'll comment too. Mita'il. Yeah, close enough. Iman hada alqalamu. Hadad alqalamu li'adil. Li'adil. Good, inshaAllah. Good. Good. Good. Good. Good. Very good. Liman hadihil
[SPEAKER_00] sayyaratu. Liman hadihil sayyaratu al-mudidi. Very good, inshaAllah. Liman hadihil bakaratu. Liman hadihil bakaratu al-minkhala. Very good, inshaAllah. iba? Uh, I forgot how to say pre-qaida. Haqeeba. Haqeeba. Haqeeba. Haqeeba. Haqeeba's bag, but it could be a general term, for the bag. So... Liman hadihil hadifatu. That was, that was one word that got everybody on a test. Yeah, I forgot. The bag of the... Was it? The bag of the... The doctor's bag. Everybody has their own doctor and their own bag. Very few people have a bag, but very few people have a bag. So, haqeeba, no prayer bag. So, liman hadhi al-khaqeebatu, and hadhi al-khaqeebatu al-mubarisi. The dhawqeeb. Didn't you go down here too? No, I feel my knee is injured. Oh, you're close. I showed you up here a bit too soon. Liman hadhi al-kursi, hadhi al-kursi bi hamari. Good. MashaAllah. Can I ask you a question? Hadhi al-kursi bi hamari.
[SPEAKER_00] Is that a rooster? The jada? Which one are you? The other one? I'm not sure. I was going to say the jada. Okay. Liman hadhi hitajatatu, and then hadhi hitajatatu bintun. No, wait. Is that bintun falahin? Yeah, but we have to say it belongs to. Oh, okay. So, how does it say bintun falahin? So, put it in the same format that all the previous ones were, right? Oh, got it. It sounded like it would be wrong. No, I'll learn it. It's a different story. Hadhi hitajatatu, ni bintun falahin. Yeah, ni bintun falahin. Okay. Yeah, good. The
[SPEAKER_00] daughter of the farmer. Okay. One moment. Liman hadha sa'atu. Hadha sa'atu? Hadhi sa'atu. I'm going to revoke your gift. I'm joking. Hadhi sa'atu, yeah. Hadhi sa'atu li bini mudiri. Yeah. Okay, continue. The question was? I was out. Okay, go ahead. Sorry, I'm going to study. No problem. The, the, the, what was the question? Liman hadha al-baytu? Mm-hmm. Hadha al-baytu ditta bini. Very good. So, from that, who knows? Good luck. Okay? Lada bal Bombay. Okay.
[SPEAKER_00] Palaloo. Palaloo. Kalaga loomme b Reaganay hain aaa yai mingani ano. Shai. Yeah. How was your day? Thank you. Great job, Lona. Feeling good? Thank you. What does it do to it, what does it make it, what happens to it? The body. The body. The body. Okay. I was just telling that I got some gifts for the brothers who got hungry from South Africa, but I was using it as an excuse because I forgot to bring it. I was like, oh,
[SPEAKER_00] it's the thing I can't do. But unfortunately it came, so now I have an excuse. Okay. I was a little bit confused regarding these two. So Hazel, Baidu, didn't you mention when the word has like a, it says , so you're going to put two lambs? Yeah. Right? That's what we got to do, right? Yeah, two lambs. So I'm going to pronounce Hazel, Baidu, Lidabibi? Hazel, Baidu, Lidabibi. Hazel, Lidabibi. Yeah. Okay. The next one is just for you to know that. Remember the general rule for the letter after it? Make it cast, all right? Make it cast, all right? Yes. For these that have , which we showed last time, is it looks like this, right? It looks like a , but without the dots on the bottom, right? So for example,
[SPEAKER_00] Musa, right? Or let's just put, yeah, Musa. So if you were to say , it would say the same. And so whether it's supposed to be cast, or , it would stay the same. It would always be Musa. So it doesn't change based on the where it comes before it. Same thing with the letter that looks like this, right? America, for example, right? America and America. So if this comes at the end, then it doesn't change no matter what. All right? So it's the rules regarding to the . Yeah, but we're going to go later. I don't want to confuse you guys. Okay. All right. That's going to be the first lesson of the third volume, inshallah. All right, next.
[SPEAKER_00] So these, you're ready to read through, right? Everybody understand this? Yes? So in this, meaning in this chapter, these are the only words? I think so. No, there's more coming up in the next, this next coming right now. There is, for example, . Okay. But I ask you to read this, my friend, I feel 좋은. Yes we do, my friend. Okay. So we've both been back here on this last session, the last ten When was the last time you was there? In July The Malored Lost hadn't gone, the first time there was. that normally, according to normal words, it'll change together . But the subsequent lines are there to show you that these are exceptions to that rule. Okay, next.
[SPEAKER_00] So again, this is just for you to understand this point, that these words don't change together . This doctor, I mean, this engineer is from America. Okay, now this last was . You have to basically read the main point that it shows here is that the love, right? What was the love for him? For example, what we previously learned was . Right? So itself is going to be , and it makes the next . The word , right? So you say , and this word indicates time or place. So means under, right? It indicates place. So and generally refer
[SPEAKER_00] to front, the front and the back, right? Or behind. It can also be used in a sense of time, right? For example, , right? So in that ayah, Allah is talking to the pharaon and telling him how he will be assigned for those who come after him. So over there, it used in the sense of time, not in a physical sense. So again, so this exercise is to show us that these words, like , they become, they have a , and they make the word after it . Everybody understand that point? Sounds like . Yes. Yes. Yes. Everybody understand? Yes. OK. All right. Next, we're going to make sentences. Can anybody make sentences from these words? Yes. OK, good. Let's go ahead. Let's hear your sentence. OK.
[SPEAKER_00] Anybody ready in the meantime? So I was a little confused about that. I put . . . Good, masha'Allah. But who are you talking about? Who that? Who went? Just mention any name. And instead of ? No, no. Put then put a name, put whatever any name you want. Oh, you mean after ? No, after . Oh, so . Good, perfect. Oh, so that one is . Yeah, exactly. . Very good. Oh, I learned the first one. No, no. Either one is fine. What did you say? I said . That's perfect, yeah. . Right? Anybody want to? Who's going to translate that for me? Maybe. Beside what they asked me. Somebody who's asked, yeah. Abdullah went to
[SPEAKER_00] the hospital in a car. Very good. Abdullah went to the hospital in a car. This is a random note, because he said a sentence. An ambulance is called . is a very good car. And an ambulance is . So that is something you can tell the guards in the column to call the . I'm just going to burn it to you or something. Now you've got another way to flex for them. That's an , right? It's . It's , yeah. But it's off. It's off. It's . Yeah. . Okay. All right. Good. Any others? Anybody else have sentences? . Very good. . Germany
[SPEAKER_00] is a beautiful country. Okay. . . Good. . . . . . . . . . . In . Very good. So are we going to translate that? That car is from . . . England, very good. That car is from England. Very good, . Two more sentences in there. What was the next lesson? . . . . . . . . Okay, Switzerland was conquered... defeated? Before yesterday. What happened then? Miranda probably lost the soccer match. Oh, okay. So maybe you should specify that, that they had to conquer or something. Some crazy news happened while I was not in South Africa or something. Okay, yeah. Alright, good. Anybody else? Last
[SPEAKER_00] one? I like this one. It's already in the book. . Okay, this is referring to you. I'm not an imam, but yeah. If I just say Switzerland, . Is that wrong? Yeah, it's right, but just switch. usually comes after the adjective. So you describe it with something. . Yeah, like, you and Jidan, he's very strong, right? . . Yeah, . . Switzerland is very beautiful. . . . . . .
[SPEAKER_00] . . . . I meant, are you. . . . . . . . . So it just happened for 20 years? Is it over? No, it just kind of informed me. No, it made me threading. . I mean normally you would use the word stab right? Soana means stab, stab someone. So you say ta'ana mu'minun wa juna bisikin. Bi ba means with. I think it's a bit of an advance in this but it's also kind of gory. I mean we just shut up. Here's a different one. Hala sakinu hala maktabi. Hala maktabi? Yeah perfect yeah. Hala sakinu hala maktabi. This is a knife on the desk. That's a very good one. Alright. Can we just go back now? Yeah sure go ahead. Yeah. Hala yasin? Oh. Um, so I just, I was a little confused about can we go back to top number four?
[SPEAKER_00] Okay. No sorry. So I just want to make sure I say this is Abdullah went to Germany and he is from England? No. Um, Abdullah went. Min al-Masih. He's from India. Yeah. He's not from India. Yeah. So Abdullah went to. Abdullah went to. What does min mean? From. From. From. Yeah. So now I'm trying to say literally word to word. Oh Abdullah is from. No below. So the one who's doing the dhaba is called the fa'a. That we'll learn in a bit inshaAllah. He's the one who's doing that, he's the doer of the action. So dhaba, Abdullah is the one who's doing dhaba, he's doing the going. So now I'm trying to say like in that way. So I'm still going to start with the pa'a. yeah yeah so you
[SPEAKER_00] only say many from in that sense like I'm from this country if you use the name so but you're saying an action that they're saying that he went from this place to that place it doesn't mean necessarily a person is from that place yeah right question from the biggest page number seven okay yeah yeah and what does that mean this so that means a farmer
[SPEAKER_00] a farmer oh it doesn't belong to a farmer but it belongs to his daughter yeah was there another question yeah I don't know I don't know the gender of these words which words like the these are all male some some of them might be it's possible for it to be female in some context but for now generally for our purposes these are all men all right just to clarify one more the same number six which page are you on sorry same page 46 is it 46 okay all right great number six number um H River I enter so what I wrote where is teacher's car mm-hmm it
[SPEAKER_00] is in front of a school yeah perfect yeah my friend but I says graciasigator who's this friend? All right, should we start the next lesson? Are you guys ready for it? You guys seem very sluggish today. Yeah, it's great. Huh? I do call it a day today. Call it a day? Next week or something. Whenever you get anywhere, we can do that. I think we should go actually introduce the concepts. I'll introduce the concept and then we'll go more in detail next class. But we should at least move forward a little bit. All right, just a minute. I don't have time at all. And don't. Hey, we get to hold on to a lot more. Yeah, you do. You hold on to a lot more. Just because you asked that, now I'm considering not reading it. This is the third time he asked after we've been talking. We'll see. We'll discuss when it comes. We're actually pretty close to a lot more. Well, what do you guys think? Guys, originally, our original plan is to have a hold on. Should we
[SPEAKER_00] uphold that ruling or should we change it maybe to like. One class a week? Yeah, one class a week and on time like a Saturday morning or something or Friday afternoon, Saturday afternoon. After. After Zohar? After Saturday after Zohar? We should extend the break. I don't think we should. I don't know. Some brothers in Rojava, they sleep till like, after. After Fajr, I think. After Fajr? Yeah. I don't mind. I don't give a damn. Saturday morning. We get after Fajr. Saturday morning after Fajr. What do you guys think? We're good. Yeah. We're good. We got Ramadan. We got Ramadan. What's wrong with, what's wrong with Zohar though? I feel like Zohar would work better now. Saturdays? Zohar is better. I work. I work. I work after. Oh, work. I work after. I work after. Huh? Hold on a sec, okay. Saturday? Yeah, Saturday. On my, on my. On my. On my. On my. On my. So Saturday after Fajr, no? No. No? I can't. I can't. I can't. Is there any time that we're working on Ramadan? No. No. No. No. No.
[SPEAKER_00] No. No. No. No. No. No. Yes. Nobody had no excuses at that time. Thank you. See. Kalaj, kalaj, kalaj. Nah, dude. Huh? So no classes in the class? No classes. No classes in the class. No classes. Because honestly, I'm kind of worried because we only had like a two week break and everybody forgot everything. Yeah. So we got off a lot. Everybody was gonna get like, like, like, K-4. We're gonna be back to like, have that major and have that. That's the point. Shay, come on. Because I'm usually the first to decide, you know, what is best for us. Shay, listen.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay, I don't That's not a bad idea. That's not a bad idea. Brother, Bob mentioned an interesting idea, kind of like a compromise in between, that we do classes on Saturdays after Fajr, but we don't do new things, we just kind of solidify the whole thing that we already learned. So that way, when people forget everything, at the same time, if people genuinely cannot do it and hold on, then they won't be missing out on new lessons. What do you guys think about that? I think we can have one big class session. I think we can have one big class session in the middle of the month, just one day. I think consistency is better, yeah. So let's do that as well. So Saturdays, the problem with after Fajr is that pretty much daily I'm going to be doing some sort of hadith after Fajr, and on Saturdays and Sundays, the plan is to get the guest speaker, that's been the way it's been working for the past few months with a few of our alums, where
[SPEAKER_00] they get a guest speaker to speak after Fajr on Saturdays and Sundays, which means it'll probably go a long time, maybe a half an hour, 45 minutes, so that won't really be feasible. So we'll just Google her now. We're not going to make it, it's just going to be a review, but we will have it recorded anyway and uploaded, so whoever misses out, they can just listen to it and show. And by the way, I think a few lessons were uploaded and she'll work on that, sorry about that. The other question I had was for Ramadan, are you going to, I know it's not talked about, but you're doing the Tharabi in one of the buildings, is there a way we can just come and attend your Tharabi inshallah? I'm not sure about Tharabi yet, but yeah. I mean, pretty much Do we have off for Eid? Huh? How long do we have for Eid? How long do we have for Eid? Just two weeks, right? We need to do like a week
[SPEAKER_00] or so off. We'll start like a week or two off. I'll mention the exact dates on the group inshallah. Okay, brother? But I think for now, I think that sounds good. Saturdays, after the globetrotters, during the wait, okay, that should work for me inshallah. Saturday after the globetrotters, and we'll give like a week or two off after Eid inshallah. Then we'll restart sometime mid-April. Okay. So what are we going to do? Are we going to have any new lessons, or just to repeat the four lines? No, we're going to be reviewing. Good job. Alright. Anyways, was that a distracting tactic? Yeah, let's go. I don't care, I'm still going to ask. Alright, I fell for it, though. Be happy. Did you know about Jalasa? What is that? Yes,
[SPEAKER_00] five more minutes. And number six. Four. Number six. Or number four. Four. Okay. So Jalasa is just another verb, right? It means to sit, right? He sat down. Jalasa. So that's a new word. We already learned a different form of the word, which is Jalism. What does Jalism mean? Sitting, right? So the verb of Jalism is Jalasa. It means to sit. That's page 46. So now we can add another member to the family of which family? The verb family. Right? So you can add it to your verb family. How many verbs do we have now? Three. What are they? Yeah. Now we have our third member of the family. That's why I'm pointing that out. Jalasa is member number three of the family. It's very obvious,
[SPEAKER_00] right? We have Mehrab, too. We didn't learn Mehrab. Mehrab is this one. Mehrab? Mehrab is that niche in the Torah. Okay. Let's quickly start the next lesson. Everybody is trying to derail me, but I'm not going to falter. No, I'm not here. Lesson number nine. Okay, who's going to read? No, you're going to derail the lesson. Are you going to actually read? Okay, go ahead. Who is this? Who is Abbas? Very good. Abbas? Are you trying to say all of that? Me? Okay. Who is this? Whose boy is this? No. What is Aladjou? Man. Who is this man? Very good. Who is this man? He is Abbas. Abbas is emerging. Abbas is a rich merchant.
[SPEAKER_00] Rich merchant. Abbas is a rich merchant. Rich merchant. Now this is a new rule that we are learning. This is a major rule. This is like, you know, the one major rule we learned before is it comes very, very, very often in Quran and Al-Faith in Arabic and German. Okay, This is another one of those major rules. That's why I want to just introduce it. And I'm going to give you some reading to do with another book. So you can get yourself more familiar with the concept. And she'll already go all in on Monday on the details of this. But this is called... So over here, you're looking at da-ji-run-wa-ni-yun. Right? So this is called mausukh and sifah. Or...
[SPEAKER_00] That's confusing. Okay. So da-ji-run-a-bas is a rich merchant. So if you were to just say, Abbas is a merchant, that's what the past script records, right? Abbas, da-ji-run-a-bas-man, da-ji-run. But since he's trying to describe what type of merchant, he's trying to add a description. So he adds... So the mausukh
[SPEAKER_00] is da-ji-run. And the sifah is wa-ni-yun. Right? Sifah means description. Okay? Sifah, if you want to literally translate it, even if it's a grammatical term, but literally translated, it means description. And mausukh means the described. You get it? So in Arabic, the description, or you can say the adjective, it comes after. You get it? For example, a beautiful woman. Right? So in English, you're going to say beautiful first. Right? You say beautiful woman. The description comes first. But in Arabic, it's the opposite. The description comes after. Right? So you say, imra'atun jameelatun. Right? Jameelatun means beautiful, but it comes after. So that's one important thing. Right? Imra'atun jameelatun. Oh, you're trying to remember that? Imra'atun jameelatun. Right? I don't know. I hope I didn't say it wrong.
[SPEAKER_00] Imra'atun jameelatun. Yeah. So sifar is description? Yeah. And the other is described? Mosleik is described. Described. Yeah. Oh, you also want to know imraatun jameelatun? No, no. Okay. All right. Yeah. So that's one example. Right? Then read next. How do we read next? All right. So, hamedun mudarison. Okay. Hamedun mudarison jadeedun. Okay. So, hamed translated? Hamed is like a student? No, opposite. Teacher? Yeah. Then next one? Hamed is, no. Hamed is, what is jadeedun again? New. Is a new teacher. Yeah. Hamed is a new teacher. Right? So let's just replace this with this. Wait, how come the, like, does it
[SPEAKER_00] make more sense for, like, Jadim to come perform with us? It only makes more sense because you speak English. But that's not how, that's not how would say it. Just, that's the main thing you have to remember. Like, you're talking in a different language. We think that English is how the world works. Right? That's just because we spoke English from a young age. But it doesn't mean that other languages have to go by the same convention. Right? So now here, look. The next example is, Hamed is a teacher. Now you want to describe Hamed as a teacher. So you describe, say, , this is the description. This is an adjective. It's called a . You get it? Yes. And the , the thing that he describes is . Now there's some grammatical rule related to this, but again we'll go into the depths of that later. Next lesson, inshallah, I'll send you money to read so that you can solidify the concept. But basically there
[SPEAKER_00] are four things, there's four things in which basically, the , and when it comes to the at the end, right, you've got to remember this is very important in Arabic grammar, to know what's going to happen to the last part of the grammar. A lot of the things that we've been talking about is related to this, right? For example, , it's all related to this, so this is very important in Arabic grammar. So, the , and the , always have to be the same in terms of this . And they also always have to be the same in terms of male or female. So, if , then this should be , right? Then they always have to be the same in terms of, what do you call it, singular, plural, or dual, right? Meaning, if they're, if they're, if they're, if they're, if they're, if they're, if they're one is singular, this also has to be singular, right? You can't say, , or , right? Or , right?
[SPEAKER_00] It has to be , we didn't learn , we'll get there, inshallah. So, that's the third thing. And the fourth thing is, in , if they're , right? If they're definite or indefinite, right? Remember, indefinite is, if it has , right? Indefinite is if it has , or if it's a proper noun. Like , or , right? So, over here, , since it's , this will also have . Everybody understand that? Again, if you didn't fully understand, I'm just giving you a basic overview of the concept. InshaAllah we'll go into this in much more depth on Monday, inshaAllah ta'ala. So, like an example of Yeah, exactly. There's many, many examples in the Qur'an, of this, of , and , right? , right? , right?
[SPEAKER_00] So, if you look, all four of those things correlate, right? A far place, right? So, is a place, and means far. So, you're describing the place as far. Everybody understand that? This is a very important concept, and it has many, many examples in the Qur'an. If you can think of some examples based on whatever few details I gave you now, then that would be nice to bring that on Monday, inshaAllah, so we can explore those a little bit more, inshaAllah. So, try to focus on this aspect and think about it a little bit more, inshaAllah ta'ala, on Monday. We will go, do a deep dive on this topic, inshaAllah. So, you said, if it's, like, a female version, then you said, the thing, it should be that one? Good, yeah. So, . Sorry? What does means?
[SPEAKER_00] means fruit. Fruit. Yeah. So, no, sorry, means apple, and means fruit. Yes. All right, so we finished for today. It wasn't so bad, right? We started the lesson, but you still missed the... You still have nine... It's still 9 to 15, right? So, according to this clock. So, until we get into class, inshaAllah, over here, I'm going to go and... ... .