[SPEAKER_00] Okay, how many of us finished our homework? Okay, I'll check some of your homeworks after class, if you could bring it to me after class, inshallah. Right now we can just start the upcoming lesson. Was there any, what was the homework exactly? Can somebody remind me? Okay, read, write, and translate. Okay, let's go over it together very quickly. Okay, number one. Sorry, the one that's just to read and write the haraqat, we don't have to do that. Hopefully we all know. The main thing is to test if we understood the concept of haraqat. What does a haraqat do? What does a haraqat do?
[SPEAKER_00] Makes the next word, kassara. Okay, all right. Now, min aina Fatima hiya min al-Hind. Min al-Hindi. Okay, who wants to translate that quickly? Quickly. Okay, good. Good, inshallah. All right, next. Hamad, can you read it quickly and translate it? Quickly, very quickly. Number two? Yeah. He went out from the classroom, he went to the pencil room. Yes. Who went out from the classroom? The student. Oh, the student, yeah. No, no, al-mudarris. Where's al-mudarris? Oh, teacher. Yeah. So, translate it again. The teacher went out from the classroom and went to the pencil room. Okay, good, mashallah. Read the Arabic too, though. Yeah, I'm going to read the Arabic. Uh, in here. Na'adi. Farajan al-madrisa. Al? Al-madrisi. No, how do you say teacher? Al
[SPEAKER_00] -madrisi? No, al-mudarris. Oh, al-mudarris. Shhh. Min al-fasli. Min al-fasli. Wa zahabi illa... Wa zahaba. Wa zahaba illa al-mudri. Ila al-mudii. Ila al-mudii. Ila al-mudii. Yeah, good. Ila al-mudii. Okay, good. All right, mashallah. All right, Harun. Huh? Read the next one, quickly. Wa zahaba al-ta'ajiru ila al-tukam. Yeah. What does that mean? Who's he? Yeah, the merchant. Yeah. The merchant went to the store. Good. Very good. Mashallah. Right. Good. All right. Kharaja means?
[SPEAKER_00] The store? Okay. Good. The toilet or? Yeah. Shower specifically. Okay. Brother Atif. Next one. Next one. Number five. The first one is man. Good. Mashallah. Al-Fasl is classroom. Yeah. What does? Yeah. What does man mean? Please. Please. When I'm asking someone, please, nobody else respond. Only the one who I ask. Good. So, now, re-translate it. Yeah. Yeah. Who left from the classroom? Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00] Very good. Mashallah. All right. Hafez Zeeshan. Next one. No. If you're leaving from something, it's going to be a place, right? So, al-mudarrisa means a female teacher. We know that's not what's going to, he's not going to leave from a female teacher, right? So, no. What do you guys think that word is? Al-madrasati. Good. So, translate it? Translate it? Well, madrasa is an Arabic word. We were translating it to English. Good. Okay.
[SPEAKER_00] What does dahaba mean? Yeah. And went to the shopping center. Good. Very good. Mashallah. So, you see how, remember, we were wondering earlier that how could someone, you know, how could we read when... They don't have haraka in all the words. They don't have fatha kasradam in all the words. So, now we can see that through the context. Al-mudarris means a teacher. Al-mudarrisa would be a female teacher. But looking at the context over here, we're talking about kharajat talib, a student left from. So, it's obviously you're going to, you don't leave from a person, you leave from a place, right? So, that's why this can't be al-mudarrisa. Rather, it would be al-madrasat. You get it? So, this is how, when you start to learn more and more Arabic, you start to be able to read these without even having the fatha kasradam, just through the context where you start to figure it out, right? In the beginning, it takes a lot of thinking. You have to figure it out beforehand. That's why, like, if you didn't read it before and I just called you on the spot, you probably won't figure it out. But if you look at it beforehand, you think
[SPEAKER_00] about it, you ponder, you think, okay, this can't be that, so it has to be this, then you'll get it. After a while, once you practice so much, it literally becomes like second nature. You're just a breeze through it. You don't even have to think about it. Inshallah, we all get to that point. Okay, number seven? Yeah? Just going back to number five. So, like you said, I had to think about this. So, since we may have dama, kasra, etc. on number five, so when there's a question, it's always going to be man, not min. Yeah, good point, yeah. So, over here, like, how do we know, is this min kharaja or man kharaja, right? We know two words that look exactly the same. So, is it man or min? So, how do we know? Like, brother, good point, brother. Yasser, he pointed out that man is used in the context of a question. And we see a question mark at the end of the sentence, so we know there's a question here. And the second min, it's clear that it's connected to kharaja, because we know that min from is usually used with kharaja. He left from a place, right?
[SPEAKER_00] So, that's how we know that the first is man, because this whole thing is a question. And remember, I mentioned a point, a rule last week, that when you're asking, when you're asking a question, then the thing that you're asking about comes first, right? So, man comes first, right? Man hadha, ayna, you know, all those questions, the asma'at istifham, the nosy people, they always come first, right? So, man kharaja min. So, that's how you can know if it's man or min, right? Sorry? Can't you, isn't min also a question? Not necessarily, no. Yeah, but the ayna is the questioning factor there, you get it? Because ayna means where, right? So, that's the actual question, from where, you get it? Yeah. So, min is not from the, that's why I emphasize the families, right? So, ayna is part of that questioning family, whereas min is not from that questioning family. It's just a hurm in huruf al-jar. You get it?
[SPEAKER_00] Just a quick question in terms of how you pronounce the beginning of these questions, the first statement. For like number six, it says kharaja. Is it kharaja? Is it the right way of saying it, or is it kharaja al-taaribu? Yeah, it's kharaja al-taaribu, based on what we learned about the Hamzat al-wasl. You guys, who can remind me what Hamzat al-wasl is? Raise your hand. Yes, brother. You know, at the beginning, you say the A, and in the middle, you say the A. Yeah, it's silent. Very good, mashallah. For Hamzat al-wasl, you pronounce it when it comes at the beginning of a sentence or in the beginning of your speech. But if it comes in the middle, then it becomes silent, right? So, over here, the Hamzat al-wasl is the beginning. Al, right? So, you say kharaja al-taaribu. You don't say kharaja al-taaribu. And also, this lam is not pronounced as well, because this is from the huruf? Shamsiyah, right? Ta is from the huruf Shamsiyah, so that's why you say kharaja al-taaribu, right? So,
[SPEAKER_00] the alif and lam both are not pronounced in this context. Okay, number seven, brother Ali. Kharaja al-taaribu. Min al-sini. Wa khalid. Wa khalid. Wa khalid. Wa khalid. Good. Min al-yabaa. Yabaa? Yabaa. Is it naanuni? Ni. Al-yabaa. Yeah. So, min, because remember, min is a hurf al-jar, so it makes the word after it. Yes, Salam. You want to translate it? Okay, khadija is from China, and khalid is from Japan. Good, very good, mashallah. All right, the next few. Okay, brother Hussain, what's number one? No, that would be fi, right? Fi means in, right? So, if you want to say khadija is in China, you say khadija fi al
[SPEAKER_00] -sini. But if you want to say she's from China, you say min al-sini. Okay. Next. Da'af al-faraghi fi ma yali harfa jarin munasibin. That place the appropriate harf al-jar in the blank. So, brother Hussain, do number one. Good, mashallah. Good, the book is on the table. Very good. Hafez, mu'min. Very good, translate. The student is in the classroom. Good, mashallah. Zahaba hamil ila... Hamidun. Hamidun ila jami'a. Jami'a. Jami'a. Jami'a. Jami'a. Zahaba hamil ila jami'a. Yeah, is it jami'a tu, ti, or ta? Ti. Yeah, good, mashallah. Very good, mashallah. Zahaba hamidun ila jami'a ti. Right, because ila makes next word, kasra.
[SPEAKER_00] Very good, mashallah. Hamid went to the universe. University. Good, mashallah. Brother Shahnawaz? Kharaj al-mudeeru. Kharaj al-mudeeru fil mudrasi. Madrasati. Al-mudrasi. Al-madrasati. Al-madrasi. Yeah. Translate it. So, he left the principal and went to the teacher? No. To the school. No, so, al-mudeer is the one who's doing the leaving. You get it? Yeah. So, kharaja is referring to the mudir. He's the one who's doing it. Principal left and went to the school. Yeah. You can say to the school or from the school. But you said fil madrasa. What does fi mean? No. It would be, not fi, it would be al. Which one? Min madrasa. Yeah, it
[SPEAKER_00] could be min or, which one? Al. Ila. Ila, yeah. So, you can use, over here you can use ila. Ila or min, depending on what the sentence means. If you're trying to say that the principal left the madrasa, then you say, kharaja al-mudeeru min al-madrasa. He came out from the madrasa. If you're trying to say he left to the madrasa, meaning he left his house or wherever, towards the madrasa, then you would say, kharaja al-mudeeru ila al-madrasa. Okay. Number five. Brother Samir? You went already? Did you go already? Okay. Who didn't go yet? Yes. Zahaba Muhammad bin Sini ila al-Yabani. Ila al-Yabani. Good. Mashallah. Very good. Mashallah. You want to translate? Yeah. Muhammad left from China and went to Japan. Okay, but is it left? No. Muhammad went from, Muhammad is
[SPEAKER_00] from. Yeah. No, that's fine. That part you translated fine, but I was asking, you said, Muhammad left, so. Went. Yeah, good. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah, kharaja would be left, yeah. Yeah, yeah, exactly right. Good. Good, mashallah. All right, alhamdulillah. And hopefully we learned all of the new words, right? I'm going to start doing, I'm going to start doing and adding to your homework. You guys are like, oh man, even more homework. But I'm going to start having you guys make sentences for each word, right? Because I think that's something which we're lacking in. We have to start building creativity. Like, I like how, mashallah, Hafiz Hussain, he was talking in the classroom. He was talking to Brother Mansour, who is a student of madrasa, so he knows Arabic. So he was talking to him. He said, So when you start using it like that, then it starts sticking in your mind that this is what these terms mean, and it really solidifies the concepts in your minds, right? So all of
[SPEAKER_00] these things that we're learning, we need to start putting it into practice. If you don't put it into practice, then it's just, it's going to become like, like how you learned Spanish in school and just forgot about it, right? We don't want it to be like that. You're going to meet a Spanish person who's like, oh, hola, si hablo espanol, and you're just going to be like, yeah, I don't know. I learned Spanish in school, but I forgot it, you know. But we don't want it to be like that, right? We want to actually remember Arabic. Okay. So yeah, the previous lesson, inshallah, hopefully we all got the main concepts from the previous lesson. Now we're going to start, which means, lesson number five. الدرس الخامس, lesson number five. Okay, the fifth, or if you want to translate it literally, it's the fifth lesson. Okay. Now this is a conversation between Saeed and Yasir. Okay. This is a very, very, very, very important lesson. And specifically one rule that we're going to learn in this lesson. We might probably spend the whole lesson just learning that one rule. But
[SPEAKER_00] we all have to make this rule very solidified in our mind. And inshallah, we're going to have plenty of practice on this rule, inshallah. But it's a very, very important rule. So make sure everybody pays attention. First, I'm just going to have someone read the lesson. And I'm going to try to point out the important points in the lesson. Who wants to read the lesson? Somebody who hasn't gone yet. And somebody who can read loudly, clearly. And yeah, loudly and clearly. Osman. Louder, louder, louder. Yeah, Yasir. There's two. Yeah, Yasir. Yeah, Yasir. Okay. Do you want me to translate? No, no. Just keep going. I'll do that. Yasir. La hadha kitabu hamidin. So while he's reading, don't just tag along. But I want you to focus and think, what are some new things that are coming up? By the end of this, I'm going to ask you guys, what are some new things that you noticed in these words?
[SPEAKER_00] Even peculiar things like, okay, why is this kasra? Instead of fathar or dhamma or, you know? I want you to notice everything and report back to me what you noticed different about this lesson. And what do you think the author is trying to focus on? Okay? Read that first sentence again. Okay, there should be a space between ya and yasiru, right? But just make it clear, that's two different words. Ya, yasir. Yasir is the name. Okay, continue. Okay, good. Sa'idun, aina kitabu muhammadin. Yasirun, huwa ala al-maktabi hunaaka. Hunaaka. Sa'idun, aina daftaru al-ma'arif. Yasirun, huwa ala al-maktabi mudarrisi. Mudarr? Al-mudarr? Al-mudarrisi. Al-mudarrisi. Yeah. Sa'idun,
[SPEAKER_00] qalamu man hadha ya'aliyu. Ya'aliyu. Ya'aliyu. Aliyu. Hada qalamu mudarrisi. Sa'idun, aina haqibatun mudarrisi. Aliyu. Ya tahtal mattabi. Okay. All right, so by a raise of hands, can somebody tell me something new in this lesson or something that you think that he's trying to point out for the author? Double kasra. Double kasra. Okay. I mean, no, we had that before. Min? No. We didn't have that? No. Then hamidun. No. Hamidun. Okay. Okay. Okay. So double kasra. Okay. That's something that we haven't come across yet. Okay. That's cheating, but okay. All right. Yeah. Brother Muqtar? Hunaka? Who said hunaka? You said hunaka? Yeah. Hunaka is a new word. Okay, good. Next. Ya. Ya. Good. We didn't learn ya yet, so that's another new thing. Yeah. Brother
[SPEAKER_00] Okasha? Hafiz Okasha? Haqiba too. Okay, good. Haqiba is a new vocabulary word. Okay. Hatha? Hatha we've done before. Yeah. Yeah. Sorry? Ta? Tahta. Tahta. Okay, very good. Mashallah. Tahta is a new word. Okay, very good. Yeah, I think those are the main new things that we have in this lesson. So good. Alhamdulillah. Okay. I want to focus. Okay, let's focus on the first line. Okay. Ah. Okay. Akitabu Muhammad. Okay. The ah is what? What is ah? Yeah. What is it called? It's... No, what is... What is it called? What is this Hamza called? Good. Louder? No, no. Anybody? Come on. Good, mashallah. We learned it in the first lesson. Second lesson. Hamzatul istifham. The Hamza of asking questions. Right? So, this turns this sentence into a question. Okay. Kitabu Muhammadin. Okay, what's
[SPEAKER_00] happening here? Right? Kitab... Why isn't it kitabun? Or why isn't it... Alkitabu. This is the first time we're seeing a word like this. It only has one dhamma, but it doesn't have an al. Because normally, if it says al, then it's going to have one dhamma. And if it doesn't have al, then it has two. But this is breaking the rule. Because there's no al, but there's only one dhamma. Right? And then the next one, Muhammadin. Okay, why is it kassara? What's making it kassara? Right? So, this is the thing we're going to focus on right now. Inshallah, there are other rules. We'll probably have to do it tomorrow. I mean, Wednesday. But let's focus on this right now. Okay. Let's take these two words separately. Okay, kitabun. Right? If you want to say a book, you say kitabun. If you want to say the book, you say... Alkitabu. Okay. Now... Sorry, what? The book. The book, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00] Muhammadun. Alkitabun. That's normally written, right? So, kitabun muhammadun. Right? So... Let's just erase. Alkitabu, okay. This is how these words look when they're separate, right? Now, when you want to indicate towards possession, that one thing possesses another thing. Okay, let's go... Forget this for a moment. Let's think of English. Okay? When you want to say that somebody owns another thing, then how do you say it in English? For example, Saim's pen. Oh, I said it already, right? You say Saim's pen, or there's another way of saying it. What's the other way of saying it? Okay, but if you want to say it in like a shorter... Saim's pen or... Yeah, the pen of Saim. Right? Huh? Sorry? Yeah, the pen of Saim or Saim's pen. Usually, in normal day-to-day English, we
[SPEAKER_00] say Saim's pen. But otherwise, we will say... The blank of blank. So, we use the word of or apostrophe S. Right? Those are two ways to translate it. That's also two ways to indicate towards possessing something. In Arabic, you use a specific type of composition, construction, in which you put two words together in a specific way, and that indicates that one of them owns the other or possesses the other. Right? Owns is probably not the best translation. Possessing is better. Right? So, if you want to... If you want to say Muhammad's book or the book of Muhammad, then what you do is you put it like the author did here. So, you write... So, this becomes one dhamma and this becomes two kasras. Okay? Right? Don't focus
[SPEAKER_00] too much on one kasra or two kasra. Right? That's not... So important. That just depends on whether it is the al. For example, if you want to say the book of the student. Let's just change this to the book of the student. Right? No, no. Don't worry. We'll get there. Inshallah. So, kitabut talibi. Right? So, right now, the main thing we want to focus on is that there's kasra here. Whether it's two kasras. That depends on which word is used. Like, remember you learned that if there's an al. What's one thing we learned? If there's a word that has al on it, then it can never have? Remember the million dollar challenge? What was the million dollar challenge that I gave you guys? I'm still waiting for somebody to come with that. I mean, huh? No, no, no. Not Maryam. Any word in the Quran that has or al and tanween as well. Right? None of you have fulfilled the challenge till today. Right?
[SPEAKER_00] So, al and tanween can never come together. Right? So, here we say, You don't say, Right? So, don't. That's why when one of you mentioned that, oh, it's the first time we're seeing two kasras. That's not really consequential. It doesn't really have much importance. Whether it's one kasra or two kasra. The point here is that it becomes kasra. Okay? Whether it's one or two, it doesn't matter. Okay? So, this construct is how we show that one is a possessor and one is a possessed. Right? So, the second, the possessed always comes second. Right? In English, it's the opposite. Right? You say, If you want to use the apostrophe S. Otherwise, if you want to say it like book of Muhammad, then it looks like this as well. But normally, people don't really say it like that. Right? So, if you're trying to say it with an apostrophe and you say, So, that's opposite. But in Arabic, the possessor will come second. Okay?
[SPEAKER_00] So, the possessor comes second. The possessed comes first. Okay? Now, let's take the same concept. Before we get to terms and things like that. And some of the technical. Just look at the concept here. In these other words. What is the response? And then we go back to the lesson. He asked, Is this the book of Muhammad? Or Muhammad's book? Or, Or, Or, No, Ya means, Oh, Like, You're talking to somebody. Hey, Like, In
[SPEAKER_00] English, We would say, You wouldn't use any word. You say, Yasir, is this Muhammad's book? But in Arabic, you say, Yeah, Yasir. When you're addressing somebody. Right? I mean, people translate it as, Oh. You can translate it as, Oh, too. But that's like archaic English. Just, Oh. One, Oh. Right? Oh, Yasir. But like, it's archaic English. Nobody really uses it like that anymore. So, you just say, Yasir, is this Muhammad's book? You get it? That's how you would translate it in today's English. Yeah. If there's this, then it's Hazar. Is the book Muhammad's? Or, Is this? Because, There's no Hazar in there. And then you're saying, Akitabu Muhammad. Muhammad. So, Without that, Without, No, no. There is, There is this, right? You're saying, for example, If you were just to say, Akitabu Muhammadin. Is Muhammad's book. But that's not a complete sentence. You get it? Is Muhammad's book? Yeah, Yasir. Like, wait, okay. What about Muhammad's book? You get it? So, is this Muhammad's
[SPEAKER_00] book? So, that's why the Hazar is here. You get it? Although, the Hazar is not there. It's understood that it's there. No, no. It is, the Hazar is here. Oh, there is the Hazar in the end. Yeah, yeah. Exactly. Yeah. I think he's trying to point out the Ahazah. But the Ah is already in front of the Kitab. Yeah, yeah. Yeah. There's a reason it's like that, but if you want to get into technicalities. I was thinking of the Ahazah, Kitab, Muhammad. Yeah, yeah. I get what you're saying. I get what you're saying. Because that's how we previously saw it in the previous lessons. But I don't want to get into the reason why it's like this. That's going to get into technicalities. But we have Ahazah here. And that's what it means here. How do you make this in order? What do you mean in order? Like, how do I know if I'm telling Yasser or I'm asking Yasser if this is Muhammad's book? Or, like, how do I kind of tell if it's... Yeah, it's a question. Wait, sorry. Can you just explain your question a little more? Like, can you say the meaning of the sentence in order? Is this
[SPEAKER_00] Muhammad's book? Yasser or Yasser, is this Muhammad's book? If you want to use O, fine. We can use O. O Yasser, is this Muhammad's book? Or you can say O Yasser at the end or the beginning. Normally in English, when you're addressing somebody, you say it in the beginning, right? You say Yasser. So when you're translating, it doesn't have to be very strict, like word for word, like exactly how it is, right? Especially because the conventions in English are different than the conventions in Arabic, right? When we're translating in English, we want to follow the conventions that are used in English. Otherwise, because the point of a translation is to convey the same meaning. So you would rather use a translation. That's why some of the translations in the Quran are a bit off because they're not using conventions that are normally used in English, right? Now, alhamdulillah, there's some good translations that have been coming out recently that have been keeping this in mind, the conventions that we actually use in English. And so it's more understandable. So anyways. If you come in Quranic Quran, then
[SPEAKER_00] we have to say... Oh, Yasser. Oh. Not necessarily... Translation in English? Yeah, you don't necessarily have to put it because there are, like I said, some translations now, the recently translated ones, they don't even put Oh. They just put Yasser, for example. For example, They were translated as Take the book with strength. Like Imam or somebody is giving khutbah, they translate like that. If it's Ya, they say Oh. Yeah, that's what I'm saying. So, yeah, that's true. Normally people do try like that. But my point was that in English, normally we don't... How many people have ever heard anybody say Oh? Like, Oh, you. No, in normal English, I'm not talking about normal English. Yeah, yeah. I'm talking about if somebody like you giving khutbah and translation of Quran, then you translate in English Ya,
[SPEAKER_00] Ya Allah, like Oh Allah. Yeah, I get your point. Yeah, but the thing is, we don't have to translate like that, right? That's just normally how it's been done. But we can also translate in a way that's more understandable for us, right? As long as it's correct and it fits the Arabic. That wasn't the point I was trying to make. Ya ayyuhal lazeena, Oh people you believe. Ya ayyuhal lazeena, Oh people you believe. Yeah. Ya ayyuhal lazeena, Yeah. Ya ayyuhal lazeena, Up here can be used Or, Or in English. Or is this Book belongs to Muhammad or belongs to Yassir? No, Book belongs to Muhammad, right? Book belongs to Muhammad or it belongs to Yassir? No, no, no. Ya is an Urdu word. If you're, if people, let's not get confused now. Ya has nothing to do with, nothing to do with Urdu, right? Because in Urdu, Ya means Or. That's not the meaning in Arabic, right? Ya only, that in Arabic, Or is?
[SPEAKER_00] Oh, okay. This is, this is Or in Urdu. And it's not a Kitab Muhammadin hadha ya Yassir. Or it's not saying that, is this Muhammad's book or, or is it Yassir's book? That's, that's Urdu, right? It has nothing to do with Arabic. Ya Yassir, it's, Oh, you're talking to Yassir, right? It is used in the sense, Ya ayyuhal lazeena. Yeah, that's the only way Ya is used. Yeah, in Arabic. Yeah. Okay, let me just use Oh because everybody's used to it. So let me just, let me just use Oh. Not necessarily, it doesn't always have to be praised. Sometimes it's used in a context, other contexts as well. Where's the eraser? So it's basically saying like it's more emphasis when you read the Adabiyah instead of English. Because like when you say Ya Allah, like when you're doing it, so it's more like profound. You're saying, because if they don't explain it in English, they just bypass it. But in Adabiyah, you see it, you hear it more. Yeah, it could be that, yeah. But I think the point
[SPEAKER_00] is more. It's about, they're two different languages. So the way you express something in each language is different. So in Arabic, you use the word Ya. In English, you just don't use the word. So, yeah. You can say Hey, but that's not, that's very informal. So I wouldn't say that fully. Yeah. Oh, exactly. Had that, yeah. Exactly. Sorry. What was that? I think that's closed one. So, yeah, we're getting to that. We're getting to that. And so we'll get, we'll get there. I don't want to confuse anybody. We're going to, we're just focusing on this. I'm not sure how we got focused on. Yeah. But. So whenever you're addressing something with someone's, then the first word or like the end of the word turns like into, what's that called? A page? No? Not necessarily. We're getting there. No. But the main thing we want to focus on here is.
[SPEAKER_00] Is it's neither Tanween nor does it have Al. Okay. That's the main thing we want to focus on here. It's neither Tanween nor Al. And the second is, is going to be Kesra. Okay. That's the main thing we want to focus on here. Okay. Now I just want to go through the next few lines and we want to address, we want to point out where are the, where's the similar construction being shown here. No. This is. Translated please. No. This is. Hamid's book. Right? So it's the same, look at the same type of construction. Right? Kitabu Hamidin. It's not Al Kitabu Hamidin. It's not Kitabun Hamidin. It's Kitabu Hamidin. Right? Okay. Kitabu Hamidin. Hamid's book. Okay. Aina Kitabu Muhammadin? Where is? Muhammad's book. Okay. Kitabu. It's not Al Kitabu. It's not Kitabun. It's Kitabu. And then Muhammad is not Muhammad.
[SPEAKER_00] It's Muhammadin. Okay. Kitabu Muhammadin. Okay. Okay. We can skip that. We're only focusing on this possessive for now. Aina daftaru Ammar. What does daftar mean? Office. Right? No. Daftar means? Daftar means? Notebook. Okay. In the vocabulary test, I put daftar on purpose just to see who falls for it. Unfortunately, many of us fall for it. But I actually give less points off because some people fall for it. Some brothers actually got confused. I think even brothers who don't speak Urdu, some of them got confused because I made that joke one time. I guess it just stuck into everybody's mind. So I think I shouldn't joke like that anymore. But yeah, daftar does not mean office. Daftar means notebook. When that means there? Yeah. We're going to get there though. I don't want to confuse you. Okay. Daftaru Ammarin. Ammar is the name. What does that mean? Where is the notebook? Ammar's notebook. Okay. Ammar's notebook. Daftaru Ammarin.
[SPEAKER_00] It's not al-daftaru or it's not daftarun. It's daftaru Ammarin. Then hua ala maktabil mudarrisi. Okay. So this is where we know. Remember your question was that, oh, this possessor is always going to be pish, is always going to be dhamma. We got the answer to that here. Right? It's not always going to be dhamma. Right? Over here it says ala maktabil mudarrisi. So because it has ala before it, what is ala? Maktabil. Harful jar. Ala is on, but it's a harful jar. What does it do? It makes the next word kasra. Right? So that's why maktabi. You say, you're not saying maktabul mudarrisi, you're saying maktabil mudarrisi. So it's the same concept here, except instead of a dhamma, let's just write that here. It's an important point. Okay.
[SPEAKER_00] So let's give it another try. So what's the answer? What does ala mean? Ala means what? Oh, angels say power and power. So we're going to say ala pikatori. We'll try this again. Ok. Peace. Okay So it's the same concept over here Right This is the possessed This is the possessor This is kasra This is not kasra This is also kasra But the key thing here Is that it doesn't have tanween And it doesn't have Al Same thing over here Kitab does not have tanween Nor does it have al And the second word is Kasra
[SPEAKER_00] That's the main thing we need to keep in mind About the possessed and the possessor So which one is the possessor here? Over here Quick Everybody quiet Al mudarris is the possessor And the possessed is Maktab So how do we translate that? On a teacher's desk On a teacher's desk Very good Or if you want to make it easier You can translate it as The desk of the teacher You want to translate it like that? Does that make it easier? The desk of the teacher Because then it becomes the same order as this The desk of the teacher You want to translate it like that? We can translate it like that Okay Wait so The possessor is always going to end with a zir Or like Yeah Yeah The second one The possessor is always going to end with kasra Generally The possessor will be anything but Al or Sorry? The possessed will be Will like end with anything but Al or tanween Yeah
[SPEAKER_00] So the possessed It can be Fatha, kasra, adhama We're not worried about that But The thing we need to know about The thing that's possessed Is that It does not have al And it does not have tanween That's the most important thing You got that? Yeah Okay Possessor Huh? No the possessed The thing that comes first The possessed Will not have al or tanween Okay? No matter what If it's fatha, kasra, adhama That doesn't matter But it does not have kasra Or tanween Everybody get that? Wait so This one Sorry? Which one? This one? Yeah that would be right It depends on the context If there's something before That's making it fatha We'll get to those things That make it fatha Then it can be kitab muhammadan Right? Who can give me an example In the Qur'an of something that's يَتْلُونَ كِتَابَ اللَّهِ Right? إِنَّ الَّذِينَ يَتْلُونَ كِتَابَ
[SPEAKER_00] اللَّهِ كِتَابَ اللَّهِ How do you translate that? The book of Allah Right? كِتَابَ اللَّهِ Allah The last one Has a kasra Allah is a possessor And kitab is The possessed The book of Allah Allah's book Right? So now you have كِتَابَ اللَّهِ It's a fatha But the key thing is that It doesn't have ال Or تَنْوِين Okay? رَسُولُ اللَّهِ Right? فَقَالَ لَهُمْ رَسُولُ اللَّهِ How do you translate it? رَسُولُ اللَّهِ The messenger of Allah Right? So again Allah is a possessor رَسُول is the possessed Right? So رَسُولُ You don't say الرَّسُولُ اللَّهِ That's why it's incorrect To say الرَّسُولُ اللَّهِ Right? So somebody's trying to do An Arabic khutbah وَقَالَ الرَّسُولُ اللَّهِ Then that's wrong Right? قَالَ الرَّسُولُ اللَّهِ Right? مِلَّةَ إِبْرَاهِيم Sorry? مِلَّةَ إِبْرَاهِيم مِلَّةَ إِبْرَاهِيم
[SPEAKER_00] Good? Yeah, very good MashaAllah The مِلَّةَ The deen of Ibrahim So that would be an exception though As I mentioned Generally The possessor Will be كَسْرَ That's a general rule There are some exceptions But we don't want to go into exceptions We don't want to confuse ourselves So just We can't say بَيْتُ إِمَامٍ Yeah, you can say that بَيْتُ إِمَامٍ The house of An imam But the better would be بَيْتُ الْإِمَامِ Because we're talking about A specific imam Right? The house of The imam Good MashaAllah One of the examples you gave كِدَابُ الطَّالِبُ How do you كِدَابُ الطَّالِبِ How do you Differentiate Differentiate Between The book of the student Or a book of the student So You The book of the student Or a book of the A book of a student Or a book of the student
[SPEAKER_00] Are you asking about the book Or the student? You mean So The book of the student The book of the student Or a book of the student Both of them are the student Yeah, so Automatically If this is معرفة If it has ال Then the book will also become معرفة So you're talking about A specific book You get it? So when it's connected To a معرفة Then it also becomes معرفة How would I say A book of the student? Let's say the student Has multiple subjects I'm just talking about One of them So you would say كِدَابٌ لِلطَّالِبِ You don't use مُضَافٍ لِلطَّالِبِ In that context You would say كِدَابٌ لِلطَّالِبِ كِدَابٌ لِلطَّالِبِ A book That belongs to the student You get it? Yeah That's a good question though Mashallah So this This would be The book of the student So it would be A specific one
[SPEAKER_00] What makes the classroom The second part مَا اللَّهُ مَا اللَّهُ مَا اللَّهُ مَا اللَّهُ مَا اللَّهُ مَا اللَّهُ المُدَرِّسِي Where? المُدَرِّسِي المُدَرِّسِي This is كَسْرَ Because remember We mentioned that In this construction Of the possessor And the possessed The possessor Will always have كَسْرَ You get it? That's what we're pointing out Over here المُدَرِّسِي Now we can just Write that down As a set of rules Right From مُضَافٍ مُضَافِي Okay Sorry I don't want to Confuse you with the terms For now But Um We'll end soon, child. Let me just write these rules down.
[SPEAKER_00] No, it's fine. Okay. Okay, so in this construction, right, we'll call this a construction, right, of two words. Because now these words are joined together. So far, we've just been learning about words that are separate. Now these two words are constructed together. We're going to call it a construction. So in this construction that indicates towards possession, that something possesses another thing, the possessed will always come first, right? So kitab, the book is the thing that's being possessed. So that's why it's coming first, right? So you won't, you can't, it's not going to ever happen that Muhammadu
[SPEAKER_00] kitabin, right? We're talking about Muhammad's book, but Muhammad comes first, no. If you were to say Muhammadu kitabin, that would mean the Muhammad of the book, which doesn't make any sense because a book cannot possess a person, right? So the possession. Possessed will always come first, okay, in this composition. The second thing, the number two, sorry? Yeah, I mean, automatically, we could write that, but it's understood if the possessed always come first, then the possessor will always come second. So even when I'm talking to somebody named Muhammad, I'm like, no, Muhammad of the book, not him, the guy down the street. You still wouldn't say it like that? Say it again? Just how the brother had just said, no, you know, there's no Muhammad. Muhammad doesn't come from a book. But if I'm talking about a Muhammad, you still wouldn't say it like that? I'm like, no, I'm not Muhammad from the street. I'm talking about Muhammad, sallallahu alayhi wa sallam, from a book. No, you wouldn't say it like that. You would say, yeah, I mean, in Arabic, normally,
[SPEAKER_00] you wouldn't say it like that. You would just say, Muhammad al-bathkur fil kitab, the Muhammad which is mentioned in the book, right? Or you would just say, Muhammad rasulullah, right? Yeah, sallallahu alayhi wa sallam. Okay, number two. Okay. Okay, rule number two is, the possessed never gets al or tanween, right? We're talking about the
[SPEAKER_00] possessed here, right? This is a possessed, right? So it's never going to be al kitab generally. Okay, there's some exceptions, but I don't want to, we're not going to exceptions. So I'm just saying that, putting it out there so that somebody sees years into the future, they see something with, in the Quran. It doesn't exist, but in other forms of Arabic, like in poetry and stuff, it does come sometimes, but rarely. But anyways, we're not worried about those exceptions, right? Generally speaking, the possessed never gets al or tanween, this, right? So it's never going to be al kitab Muhammadin or kitabun Muhammadin, okay? All right, everybody understood that? Okay. Okay.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay, so the possessor generally has a kasra at the end, okay? Everybody understood that? These are the three main rules for the possessor and the possessed, okay? Okay. Also, you can add one more thing, that nothing can ever come between the possessor and the possessed, right? So it's not like the possessor's going to be here, there's a few words in the middle, and then at the end will be the possessed, right? Maybe we can just add that as a number four. You mean, never come in between? Never come in between. Nothing separate.
[SPEAKER_00] Nothing will come between them. Okay. Okay., yeah, that's not the reason. Okay. Yeah. Okay, nothing comes between the possessor and the possessed. Yeah, it's just going to be the possessor and the possessed, okay? Now that we got this general concept for
[SPEAKER_00] homework, what I want you to do is, I'll give you more homework later, but generally for now, what I want you to do is make 10 sentences, including this type of construction of a possessor and a possessed with any of the words that you know already, right? So now we need to get creative. Okay? We know a lot of words now, right? For example, , the of is, or you could, it's broken. For example, , the chair of is broken, right? So make your own sentences from all the vocabulary that we already have. Make your own sentences. But each sentence has to include at least one. Okay. All right. Thanks. Yeah. And good luck for all your homework after this, and you guys of course, so yeah, um, Now at the end I'm sorry, we're like,
[SPEAKER_00] a little late today, but this is a very important concept. I think. This is a very important concept that comes over and over every single page of the equipment, but it'll come over and over again. So it's a very, if you understand is properly and show this will help you a lot in your journey. So, um, um, if I was gonna say that. Okay. So that should be your homework insha'Allah. So just just, I'll have to ask to awaken this problem. try to come up with that and also um as extra homework you don't have to do it but if you do it it'll help you a lot is come up with 10 examples of this construction in from the quran right it should be decently easy actually if you really focus on it and in general i want all of us to now when we're reading the quran try to focus on these things right think okay this is this doesn't have a al or a kasra and the word after to be coming sorry it doesn't have a al or and the word after is becoming kasra so that means this is and you look at the translation and sure enough it's something is possessing the other thing you get it so you keep keep
[SPEAKER_00] doing this keep doing it it'll become like second nature in your mind and automatically you'll you'll understand that this this is a possessor this is a possessed it'll become like clockwork for you so lastly i just wanted to tell you the arabic terms for these things just just so you can know it if you don't memorize again it's not absolutely necessary but later on we're going to slowly have to learn it you anyways okay so the possessed is called in arabic the possessor is called okay okay okay so the possessor is and the possessed is called okay everybody got that okay we can end class here inshallah if anybody
[SPEAKER_00] wants to show me their homework yeah your question so i ask a question when you were saying muhammad is that is that is that strictly when you're talking about that he's the possessor that there's a more a stricter way of saying that that belongs to he's the possessor no yeah same concept so what is the meaning of there yeah inshallah a few other important things in this lesson but we're not doing those now i just want to focus on this this one specific thing inshallah those things we'll get we'll get to those things okay you want to ask a question what if someone wants to say this what we learn who is he so what if someone says that that's it yeah good question so for that we will use a specific we didn't learn that pronoun yet so there's there's some pronouns that are connected they're called kitab they're called so
[SPEAKER_00] you use kitab all right okay so what is is for he and also is it for that too no that that that that that that that yeah that because that yeah sorry just i was going to mention one point okay i forgot i was going to mention no this was all present tense like in the present right so it would be like if you let us see