[SPEAKER_00] As-salamu alaykum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatuhu. Bismillah ar-Rahman ar-Rahim. Naumadu wa nusalli ala rasooli al-kareem. Ma ba'al. Okay, did everybody understand the concept of ghayr al-munsarif? Yeah, sure, it's clean. Good, give me an example. Huh? You didn't do that part? Okay. But we mentioned like a bunch of examples in class. Some of them are on the board too.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah. Good, Ibrahim is an example. Alright, anybody brought any examples from the Qur'an? Oh, I mean, I read it somewhere about the Qur'an, but is Yahya, I'm not sure if you mentioned last week, but is Yahya an example? No, it's not, yeah. It is kind of an exception in the sense that it doesn't, whatever, the harakah doesn't show on it. There's not part of this group where... If it's supposed to get a kasra instead of it gets a fatha, and it can never have to mean, it's not part of that group. It's a different category. I forgot the context, but... Yes, very good, yeah. فَرَجْعَ مُوسَىٰ إِلَىٰ قَوْمِهِ غَضْبَانَ أَسِفًا Right? So, it should be غَضْبَانًا أَسِفًا But غَضْبَان is, again, the same pattern as كَسْلَان مَلْآن Right? So, it also does not get kasra.
[SPEAKER_00] Or تَنْوِين So, Allah Subh'anaHu Wa Ta-A'la describes Musa, peace be upon him, and he says, غَضْبَانَ أَسِفًا Right? So, there's no تَنْوِين because of that reason. Understand? Everybody got that? Good. Mashallah. Any other examples? I think you're thinking of the مَوْصُوف صِفَة This is examples for غَيْرُ الْمُنصَارِفِ This one. Right. So, we say that we have the same Zabr, right? I mean, that's wrong. No, no, that's مَوْصُوف and صِفَة. We're talking about غَيْرُ الْمُنصَارِفِ over here. Anybody else? So, أَيُّبَ is not there. Good. أَيُّب. Yeah. So, أَيُّبَ. Right? It should be أَيُّبَن. But, because it's part of this category, it can never get تَنْوِين. Good. So, it only applies...
[SPEAKER_00] Does it have to do with the names? No. Like, كَسْلَانُ, for example, that came up, but that's not a name. It just means lazy. Yeah, I think you mentioned that yesterday. Good. Yeah, I mean, Monday. Yeah. So, even though they should have تَنْوِين, دَاوُودًا وَسُلَيْمَانًا, but because it is part of this category of غَيْرُ مُنْصَرِفِ, therefore, it will not have كَسْرَةً or تَنْوِين. So, good. MashaAllah. Any other examples? Yeah. No, no. لُوطَ is not, actually. وَلُوطًا إِثْقَالَ لِغَوْمِهِ Right? So, that has تَنْوِين. وَمْرَأَةَ لُوطٍ Right? ضَرَبَ اللَّهُ مَثَلًا لِلَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا مْرَأَةَ لُوطٍ So, it has تَنْوِين. So, it cannot be part of this category.
[SPEAKER_00] وَإِثْقَالَ مُوسَى Yeah. وَإِثْقَالَ No. مُوسَى is not part of this category. Yeah. وَإِثْمَعِلَ وَالْيَسَعَ وَيُمُسَى وَالْمُطَعِ So, which one of them? وَإِثْمَعِلَ Okay, good. وَيُمُسَى Good. Yeah. Only those two out of those four names. Those two are the ones that are غَيْرُ مُنْصَرِفِ because they don't have تَنْوِين. And الْيَسَعَ is not غَيْرُ مُنْصَرِفِ because it has الْ. It has تَنْوِين. وَالْوُطَى وَالْوُطَنِ Yeah. تَمْ تَبُوذُ إِنَّ إِبْرَاهِيمَ وَإِسْمَعِلَ وَإِسْحَاقَ وَيَعْقُوبَ All four of them. إِنَّ إِبْرَاهِيمَ وَإِسْمَعِلَ وَإِسْحَاقَ وَيَعْقُوبَ Yeah. All of them are غَيْرُ مُنْصَرِفِ Good. This question is not an example, but is it all only masculine words that you have next to this? No. Many female words also will be like this.
[SPEAKER_00] Actually, that's actually the reason why. Remember we mentioned the rule we meant. Remember, guys, this is actually a good point. Remember in the beginning we learned a rule that female names won't have تَنْوِين That's because they're actually part of this category. Everyone understand? Let me repeat that. Remember in the beginning we learned this rule that female names will not get تَنْوِين Do you ever remember that? Right? That's because they're all part of this category. So they'll never get تَنْوِين nor will they ever get كَسْرَ Everyone understand that? So all female names? Yeah. وَفَاطِمَةُ سَيِّدَةُ نِسَائِهَا لِلْجَنَّةِ Yeah. For example, for example, um, وَمَرْيَ مَبْنَةَ عِمْرَانَ الَّتِي Right? There's no تَنْوِين there. I was saying, how can I recite it? What? Oh yeah, مَرْيَ مَبْنَةَ عِمْرَانَ Yeah. Good.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay. عَيْشَةُ Yeah. Yeah. Um, so then like, وَفَضْلُ عَيْشَةَ عَلَى النِّسَاءِ Right? فَضْلُ عَيْشَةَ It's مُضَعف مُضَفِيه The virtue of عَيْشَة is a حَدِيث. That's the virtue of عَيْشَة over all women. Uh, فَضْلُ عَيْشَةَ So I didn't say عَيْشَةٍ because it's part of this category, so therefore it cannot get كَسْرَ So that's why it gets فَتْحَ So yeah, thanks for reminding me of that question. So, female names in general will be part of this category, that's why they don't get تَنْوِين And just remember, they cannot also get كَسْرَ Got it? Alright. So hopefully, inshallah, that concept is thoroughly um, strong in our minds, inshallah. Now, um, one more thing that I want to mention, that we learned a concept, we learned the the terms مَوْصُوف and صِفَة Right? مَوْصُوف is
[SPEAKER_00] the thing that was described, and صِفَة is the adjective which describes it, right? There's another term which is used in this book, right? Which is also used, uh, if you go to page 53, it says نَعْتَ and مَنْعُوت Right? So it's exactly the same thing, right? There's no difference, it's just a different term for it. So, مَوْصُوف would be the مَنْعُوت and then نَعْت would be the صِفَة Right? That's how in Urdu, you know how you say نَعْت Right? Like, uh, it's a description, the literal meaning is just to describe. But obviously, in that context, it would be describing in a praiseworthy way. Right? So, جَدِيد is a نَعْت and بَيْت is مَنْعُوت that which is described. Right? So it's the same thing, مَوْصُوف صِفَة or نَعْت and مَنْعُوت So if you ever hear somebody using those terms, don't get confused, just know it means the same thing. But, for the purpose of this class, we will be using مَوْصُوف and صِفَة
[SPEAKER_00] Everybody got that? Alright. Now let's start from page 50. Alright. Who's ready to read? Sorry? Yeah. But I think you read last time. Let's let somebody else read this time. Just one second. Just give me a minute. Okay. Alright, so who volunteers to read? Somebody? Alright, مُدَّثِر Let's go. بِسْمِ اللَّهِ Page 50. أَيْنَ الْمُدَرِّسُ From there. Loudly, loudly. أَيْنَ الْمُدَرِّسُ Translate it.
[SPEAKER_00] أَيْنَ الْمُدَرِّسُ No. Teacher, yeah. Where's the teacher? He's in the classroom. Uh-huh. هو في الفصل He isn't in the classroom. Good. Sorry? He said في الفصل Yeah. Translate. What does جديد mean? Who can help him out? New. Good. Where is the new teacher? He's in the office. المُدِرِس Principal. Okay. Now we have a new word over here. Okay? عند
[SPEAKER_00] Okay? Everybody got that? عند Okay. So this is also a ظَرْف. Right? So you can put it under that family or category of the ظَرْف. Right? So this can indicate towards time or place, but usually it's indicating towards place. But again, it can also indicate towards time sometimes. But what it means is, the easy way to, I mean, one way to translate it is with. Right? To be with. Okay? But you can also use it for like possession. Right? For example, عندِي سُؤَارٌ I have a question. So you'll say it like this. عندِي سُؤَارٌ You go ahead. Why? يَ Because يَ indicates towards yourself. Right? عندِي سُؤَارٌ Right? That's one way you could use it. Right? For example, I have a car. عندِي سَيَارَةٌ Right? I have a car. عندِي مفتاح
[SPEAKER_00] عندِي قَلَمٌ Right? عندِي جَوَّارٌ جَوَّار is a phone. Right? عندِي قَمِيصٌ Right? So عندِي means I have blank. Got it? عندِي سَوْجَاتٌ Yes, Mashallah. Mashallah, very good. حَمْدُ اللَّهِ May Allah grant all of us سَوْجَاتٌ pious سَوْجَاتٌ Ameen. Ameen. So, five questions to ask you. Do you have a kind? Is it عندِكَ قَلَمٌ Yeah. هَلْ عِنْدَكَ قَلَمٌ Good. Yeah. هَلْ عِنْدَكَ قَلَمٌ Is this عندِي سُؤَارٌ Huh? عندِي سُؤَارٌ similar, but there's some differences, but we'll get there when we get there. Mashallah. But yeah, that's basically, you could say it's similar in terms of meaning. الظَّرْف Yeah. So it's going to be فَتْحًا and the word after it will be كَسْرًا Why? Because it's مُضَاف مُضَافِلَي Right? Just like تَحْتَ الْمَكْتَبِ and
[SPEAKER_00] خَلْفَ الْمَدْرَسَةِ and what else did we learn? أَمَامَ الْبَيْتِ This is part of that same category. So it'll make the next word كَسْرًا but not because حرف الجر but this is because it's a ظَرْف and it is مُضَاف to the word that comes after it. Okay? But when you make it a possession, how come the word after it doesn't become كَسْرًا? Make what possession? So like I think you say عَنْدِي قَلَمًا right? Like I have a penny? Yeah. So that's because the يَا عَنْدِي Right? So you're the possessor. So when you add a يَا So this يَا is a مُضَاف إِلَي and because يَا is a ضَمِير it's such a word that it doesn't it's a type of word that مَبْنِي it doesn't change. Right? So that's why it doesn't become كَسْرًا Get it? Yeah. So somebody somebody some حافظ or anybody even نان حافظ Mashallah a lot of the نان حفاظ here have better
[SPEAKER_00] memory of the Qur'an than some of the حفاظ So So So So give me an example of عِنْدَ and the word after is كَسْرًا in the Qur'an عِنْدَ صِدْرَةُ الْمُنْتَهَا Good عِنْدَ صِدْرَةِ الْمُنْتَهَا Very good Mashallah See one example right here نان حافظ عِنْدَ صِدْرَةِ الْمُنْتَهَا Right? When he was with or at the place of the صِدْرَةُ الْمُنْتَهَا This is when the Prophet صلى الله عليه وسلم went to the highest levels in the journey of Mi'raj highest levels of Jannah Good, very good Mashallah Good example عِنْدَ صِدْرَةِ Good مَا عِنْدَكُمْ يَنْفَدُوا وَمَا عِنْدَ اللهِ بَاقٍ Right? That which is with you will end will come to an end and that which is with Allah will be everlasting Right? So عِنْدَ صِدْرَةِ الْمُنْتَ ثَوَابًا مِّنْ عِنْدِ الله A reward from Allah from with Allah Good
[SPEAKER_00] He said that Yeah وَلَوْ كَانَ مِنْ عِنْدِ غَيْرِ اللَّهِ لَوَجَدُوا فِيهِ اخْتِلافًا كَثِيرًا Just talk about the Quran If it were to come for anyone besides from anyone besides Allah Right? عِنْدِ غَيْرِ اللَّهِ Besides Allah He would have found a lot of contradiction within it Good Okay Well, actually I said it I'm saying good to myself But Anybody else Any other examples? عِنْدَ الرَّحْمَٰنِ What's the ayah? عِنْدَ الرَّحْمَٰنِ Is that even coming in the Quran? عِنْدَ الرَّحْمَٰنِ عِنْدَ الرَّحْمَٰنِ Any of the Hufadh Can you guys remember عِنْدَ الرَّحْمَٰنِ عِنْدَ الرَّحْمَٰنِ Somebody's having some عِنْدَ الرَّحْمَٰنِ وَلَا تُقَاتِلُوهُمْ عِنْدَ الْمَسْجِدِ الْحَرَامِ Very good Surah
[SPEAKER_00] Baqarah See look So many non-Hufadh Are bringing examples Right وَلَا تُقَاتِلُوهُمْ عِنْدَ الْمَسْجِدِ الْحَرَامِ Do not fight them In the vicinity of الْمَسْجِدِ الْحَرَامِ Very good Mashallah عِنْدَنَا مَا مَاتُوا مَا كُفِدُوا Okay لَوْ كَانَ يَقُولُونَ لَوْ كَانَ لَنَا مِنَ الْأَمْرِ شَيْءٍ No Surah Al-Imran Surah Al-Imran Yeah لَوْ كَانُوا عِنْدَنَا مَا مَاتُوا وَمَا قُتِلُوا قُلْ فَدْرَأُوا عَنْ أَنفُسِكُمْ نَوْتٍ Is that what it is? Okay yeah Alright If they were with us Then they would not have died Nor would they have been killed These were the Munafiqun We're saying because the Munafiqun They turned back In the battle of Uhud And so they were saying about the believers That oh if they were لَوْ كَانُوا عِنْدَنَا If they were with us Right Then they would not have died Nor would they have been killed Another one إِنْدَ اللَّهِ فَوْزًا عَظِيمًا
[SPEAKER_00] وَكَانَ ذَلِكَ Very good MashaAllah وَكَانَ ذَلِكَ عِنْدَ اللَّهِ فَوْزًا عَظِيمًا Right That was according So عند can also be used in a metaphorical meaning To mean according to Allah Like in the sight of Allah Right In that case that's what it means That was in the sight of Allah A great victory فَوْزًا عَظِيمًا Good MashaAllah So everybody gets the idea right It says it's going to move مُضَاف To the word that comes after It's gonna make it كَسْرًا It generally means With But it can mean some other things That I mentioned It indicates towards a place Being in the vicinity of Or with Something Everybody understand that This is a very very common used word As you can see Many of these ayat We just recited And there's many more That we didn't recite I just don't get why How it goes from With To I have Like Like This is with me for example Like I have a pen It is with me You get it You get it So it doesn't necessarily It doesn't necessarily mean You possess it For example I
[SPEAKER_00] don't even possess this pen Pen I don't This marker is not mine It's the masjid's Right Or I don't know who bought it But I have it though You get it So it doesn't necessarily even Possession It more gives a meaning of you having it You get it Everybody understand that Okay Alright So that's an important word We just learned Okay continue So Who Translate it Good Alright Continue Good Yeah Library is office Is Library Or You can even say bookstore Maktaba Maktaba So like if you want to go to Saudi And Inshallah When Maybe some of you guys are going for Umrah Or something Sometime soon In Ramadan And If you want to go to an Arabic bookstore And Feel like you know Arabic Then
[SPEAKER_00] you can look for Al Maktaba You just type in Al Maktaba On Google Maps Maktaba And you'll find The bookstores In the area You can check On the The Rear Gate Of Medina University That's where they have A lot of very nice Arabic bookstores Most of them are over there Where The students of Medina University Get their books from The best one is Darul Naseeha If you want to go there But That's if you guys Inshallah Get a little further in your Arabic Inshallah You can go there and Spend a lot of money on books And make yourself feel like You're going to read them Inshallah Okay Dhaba ila Al Maktaba You went to the bookstore Or the The library Either one It could be either one Okay Listen Men Zalika El Rajar Il Tawil Al Madrasa Adat Who's that
[SPEAKER_00] Tall Man Okay Yeah This is Yeah This is a new word so let's let's let's get into it well the things I write are starting to get engraved into the board okay a lady this is a very very very common word in the Quran so we should pay close attention not just in the Quran in any Arabic whether it's in hadith Quran or even just in news or anything like that it's a very very very common to use word so let's pay attention over here inshallah so a lady is part of a new family we got a new family that we're introduced to here today it's part of a new family that is called
[SPEAKER_00] al-ismu al-mawsool al-ismu al-mawsool okay here al-ismu al-mawsool okay al-ismu al-mawsool so so what it is is it just if you want to translate it into Arabic it's called al-ismu al-mawsool what it is is it just if you want to translate it literally you translate it as who is or that right but it's not the same type of that as like who naka right that is huh sorry there sorry that Ika it's not the same thing as that Ika right this is for example over here where who is that tall man that left the
[SPEAKER_00] class left right now from the madrasa from the school you get it a lady is talking about that type of that not not the type where you're pointing at some anything is that no you're saying the man that did such and such you get you get the difference you understand yeah so so depending on what you're seeing a four due to say who but that only works for odd things that are like have intellect right but you can also use a lady for things that don't have intellect you get it huh exactly you say which or that right yeah so you'll find that abdoom has a lot of different things than what we know about available terms yes from other words right so of a who is also and that type of person but then there's this that butkan the other type to say who is available to one of them and so it's that regardless as a man is as hungry personality and language for him because non language Jim note are only words that sounds up and it will sound what we're used for. Yeah, which. So you can say which. Which is also in the good. Which, that, or who, right? Depending on the context, that's what it means. Sorry? Yeah, you can translate it, yeah. Okay. Who is that man, tall man, who is
[SPEAKER_00] coming out right now from the desert? Very good. Very good. Who came out right now from the madrasa. Very good. Al-an we learned, right? Or no? It means? Now. Al-an. Good. MashaAllah. All right. Yeah, good translation, mashaAllah. So, al-lazhi is a singular form, right? So this is for singular. Sorry? That's plural, though. That's al-lazeena. Right? So we're going to get there, right? So, al-lazee is singular. I mean, we'll get to the plural and stuff later, inshaAllah. The author brings them gradually, but I'll just tell you now, so you have an idea. Al-lazee is singular, and dual is al-lazani. Where does that come in the Qur'an?
[SPEAKER_00] Wal-lazani. Wal-lazani ya'tiyaniha minkum fa-aaduhuma. Right? So, that is dual, right? Wal-lazani. Then, the plural is al-lazeena. That comes very, very, very, very, very often. Right? It just means those, right? You could translate it as who or those, depending on the context, right? So, those, right? So, al-lazee is a singular version. Right? So, give me an example of al-lazeena. Somebody? Good. Good. Al-lazeena ja'al al-Qur'ana a'ilin. Ja'al al-lazeena hum a'an salatihim sahoon. They are those who are neglectful of their salah. Yeah, good. Al-lazeena aaman wa ta'tma'innu quloobuhum bi dhikr Allah. Those who believe and their hearts are calmed by the remembrance of Allah.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, al-lazeena yunul bilghayb. So, many, many examples, right? Yeah, so, So, al-lazee, al-lazani, al-lazeena. Then, the female version is al-la-tee, right? That also comes very, very, very often in the Qur'an, right? Give me an example. Al-la-tee. Good, yeah. Naar-ul-laahi al-mooqadah al-la-tee tat-tali'u al-al-af-ida. So, naar, that says to you guys, is it male or female? Female. Remember, that was one of the words that's an exception. It doesn't have a ta'amul but it's still female. Yeah. Yeah. That's why Allah, when He described it, He says, al-la-tee. You get it? Which? Tat-tali'u al-al-af-ida. It overcomes the hearts, right? Wait, so, it's wal-la-tee? Is that like the, like the plural? Yeah, I was gonna get there, yeah. So, al-la-tee, al-la-tani, and al-la-tee is a plural, right? Where does al-la-tee come from in the Qur'an? Wal-la-tee ya'teena.
[SPEAKER_00] Good. Wal-la-tee ya'teena al-fahishata min nisa'ikum. Fa-stashhidu alayhinna arba'ata minkum. Wal-la-tee, those, meaning female, plural, who basically commit an immoral deed amongst you, then bring four witnesses, right? We know what's being talked about, right? So, al-la-tee, this is a plural, right? Those females. Everybody got it? So, now we know, al-la-thi means the one who or who, you can just say who, or that, right? But we understand what it means. Then, al-la-thani, then al-la-thiena. Then, for female, al-la-tee, al-la-tani, al-la-tee. Understand? Got it? So, these are all called al-ism al-mawsool, right? Now, whatever comes after the al-ism al-mawsool is over here. For
[SPEAKER_00] example, I don't want to get too technical, so if you don't understand this part, don't worry too much. It'll come with time. Inshallah, I'm not going to emphasize it too much, but it doesn't hurt to just mention to you guys now, right? So, whatever comes, this is the ism al-mawsool, and whatever comes after al-la-thi, right after it, is called the silat al-mawsool, right? So, for example, over here, actually, I don't want to get into it. It's going to get too confusing. But what's the rule then? What are you trying to get at? Sorry? If you read the Quran, it might help to see if there's a rule. That's true. Yeah. So, basically, the point of this is to bring a sort of description of that, whatever you're describing, right? So, for example, قَدْ أَفْلَحَ الْمُؤْمِنُونَ The believers, right? Now, Allah wants to describe them more. He says, they are those who, and then He brings a description, right? So, that description is called silat al-mawsool, right? The little definition of
[SPEAKER_00] mawsool is connected word, right? So, it's a word that... That basically connects one word to its description. Do you get it? That's like the literal meaning of al-ism al-mawsool. So, that's why silat al-mawsool, sila, the word that comes after it, sila literally means connection, right? So, it is the connection that describes the original word. Do you get it? For example, over here in this example, right? من ذلك الرجل الطويل Now, they want to describe... So, that رجل الطويل, the tall man, further, right? In more detail. الذي, the one who, or who, خرج الآن من المدرسة Who, left right now from the مدرسة, the school. Everybody understand that? Right? So, that part right here, from خرج الآن من المدرسة, that whole thing, is called silat al-mawsool. You don't have to know the implication in terms of grammar yet, in terms of the نحو, the grammar
[SPEAKER_00] yet. Inshallah, that will come in its time. But just know that, that's what it's called. So, you don't necessarily have to know that either. But if you want to, then that's fine. But just know that it's a way of describing something in more detail. والذي, yeah. I mean, و just means and. So, الَّذِين, yeah. What does اسم الموصول mean? I think I just explained it, no? Like, meaning. Yeah, I said it. Yeah, it's a connected word. That's the literal, connected noun, I guess you could say. Yeah. So, can we say just, who just left the مدرسة? Left the, sorry? The man who just left the مدرسة? Yeah. Yeah. Who just left the مدرسة? Yeah. Okay. Let's see. Somebody else read. Mustafa, you want to read?
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah. Yeah. He is the, he is the new, the new headmaster. Yeah, the new headmaster. Masha'Allah, you went old English on us, right? I mean, the principal. Headmaster. Okay. All right. Yeah. ومن ومن ومن الولد الصغير Okay. So, this is a rule. I'll just tell you. I'll just tell you guys now. It'll come in handy to help you guys read, right? So, let me erase this. Yeah, this board is in pretty bad shape. I'm joking, I'm joking.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, I mean, I guess we could do that after the class, inshallah. What was I going to talk about? Yeah. So, there's a rule. So, what was the word here? Yeah. Okay. So, we're going to zoom in over here, right? ومن So, technically speaking, it's supposed to be like this. ومن الولد Right? ومن الولد Right? It's supposed to be like this. ومن الولد Because you don't pronounce when it's in the middle of a word, middle of a sentence, remember? So, this you don't pronounce. So, then, technically speaking, the next word that has a حركة is here. But in the Arabic language, it's impossible to have something called التقاء الساكينين Two seconds together. You can't pronounce it, right? How are you going to pronounce it? ومن الولد Right? You can't pronounce it.
[SPEAKER_00] You have to have at least one of them that has a حركة, right? So, if there's ever a case like this, where there's two seconds in a row, then you will see that automatically it will get a كسرة. Right? This one will become a كسرة instead. Just to make it flow. Right? The Arabs put a lot of emphasis into making things flow and making it very natural and on the tongue. Right? So, this will become ومن ال Just to make it flow on the tongue. And this is very common in the Quran too. Anybody give examples? Huh? من من من من من من من من is different, yeah. No, for example, Good. Perfect. Beautiful. And it fits with this, right? لِمَن So, technically speaking, it's supposed to be لِمَن الْمُلْكُ Right? لِمَن الْمُلْكُ اليوم Right?
[SPEAKER_00] It's supposed to be لِمَن الْمُلْكُ But, But, so this is supposed to be man, right? Man who, right? But, because there's two seconds in a row, so this one will turn into a kasra, to make it flow. لِمَنِي الْمُلْكُ الْيَوْمِ Right? Any other example? There's many, many examples in the Quran. Even though when you read the Quran, you can do this, right? Sorry? When you read Quran, there's two seconds, so that's going to be kasra. Yeah, but I mean, you don't have to bring it from your side. Like, it's going to be there already in the Quran like that. It's going to be like... But that's wrong in Arabic, though. There's no word called mana. Yeah, but the thing is, we don't make up our own
[SPEAKER_00] language, right? That's how the... We go by what the Arabs do. It's like saying in English, I'm going to say English instead of English, right? That's not how we speak English, right? Even though it's English, I'm just going to say English. You don't say that, right? So, in the same way, it's Arabic language, so we do what the Arabs do. You can't have big Arabic. Yeah. There's a rule. There's a rule. If you want to memorize in Arabic, I'm sure the Hufad can memorize in a second. Is everyone paying attention? Those who know Arabic could... Uh-oh. Oops. Nobody saw that. So, yeah. If you want to memorize in Arabic, it's... Whenever a sakin gets any sort of harakah, it will get a kasra, right? So, again, we can't just make it up and say fatha or dhamma. No, like, the rule is that
[SPEAKER_00] if you're going to make a sakin get a harakah, due to this reason, due to iltiqa or sakin, because there's two sakin's in a row, by default, it'll get a kasra. Because it flows the best. That's the best flow. Okay. So, how would you know not to say What do you mean? Yeah, you can't pronounce it as al. Because there's... You're not supposed to pronounce it. You get it? The only way... The only way... The only way you could do is either make this into a dhamma, kasra, or fatha. You could either say manul, or manal, or manil. But the correct way to do it is manil, because that's how the Arabs do it. For example, let me give you some example from the Quran, right? وَيْلُ لِكُلِّ هُمَ زَتِلْ لُمَ زَتِي نِلَّذِي If you're going to continue, you say لُمَ زَتِي نِلَّذِي You don't say لُمَ زَتِي الَّذِي That's for the same reason, right? One second. Surah Quraysh,
[SPEAKER_00] too, I think. No. Surah Quraysh, too, yeah. قُلْهُ وَاللَّهُ أَحَدُ If you want to continue the ayah, and you don't want to stop at أَحَدُ, you say it like this. قُلْهُ وَاللَّهُ أَحَدُ نِلَّهُ الصَّمَدُ Everybody got that? There's many examples, other examples in the Quran. Anybody? Anybody? Any more examples? Yeah, what was before it? أَرْسِلْهُ مَعَنَا غَرْدًا يَرْسِلْهُمْ No, no, sorry, no. إِنَّ أَبَانَ Huh? إِنَّ أَبَانَ لَفِي ضَلَالٍ مُّبِينٍ يَقْتُلُوا يُوسُوفًا أَوِيَطَ رَحُوهُ Yeah, like that. That's fine. Yeah. There's this one that comes in, I can't think of it right now for some reason, but it comes in the middle of
[SPEAKER_00] the ayah, right? But, um... Okay, but you guys get that concept, right? Huh? Yeah. Everybody got that? وَنَادَى نُوحُ نِبْنَهُ Is it? Yeah, that's the one. Yeah, you just remember the نِبْنَهُ, but you forgot the actual word. But, وَنَادَى نُوحُ The actual thing is, وَنَادَى نُوحُ نِبْنَهُ Right? But because إِبْن is also سَاكِن, وَنَادَى نُوحُ نِبْنَهُ وَكَانَ فِي مَعْزِن Who are you drawing? Is that me? No, it's not you. No, it's not you. It's not you. It's the TV
[SPEAKER_00] show. It's the TV show. It's the TV show. No, it's not you. It's not you. What is the same thing? No, that's not the same thing because it just connects to without any problem. You know, you're not supposed to draw Harun. Harun. Harun. You're not supposed to draw anime objects in general. It's a very strict حديث about it on the topic, so rip it up. Burn it. Do you have to take this tool? No, don't burn it. Just rip it up. End of the sentence, would it be من الفصلين? من الفصلين? Where? Here. Oh, it would be من الفصلين. Yeah, من الفصلين. Yeah, this is different. Yeah, good. Go on. I'm not sure though. أَلَمْ تَرَغَيْنَ فَعَلُوا أُبُكَبْ أَسْحَابِ الْفِيلِ أَلَمْ يَجْعَلْ أَلَمْ يَجْعَلْ أَلَمْ يَجْعَلْ
[SPEAKER_00] That would be أَسْحَابِ الْفِيلِ أَلَمْ يَجْعَلْ Right? Isn't there like a way you can connect the بِسْمِ اللَّهِ الرَّحْمَنِي with the أَلْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ But you just say بِسْمِ اللَّهِ الرَّحْمَنِي الرَّحِيمِ أَلْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ Yeah, I mean it already has a kassara. Alright. I don't know why, there's a few examples that were on the top of my head but I cannot remember them now from the ayah itself. But it's fine. Either way, if you're reading and you'll realize that okay, this is something that happens very often. Okay. So, that's what happened over here. وَمَنِ الْوَلَدُ الصَّغِيرُ Okay? You can continue reading. وَمَنِ الْوَلَدُ الصَّغِيرُ الَّذِي وَمَنِ الْوَلَدُ الصَّغِيرُ الَّذِي قَرَجَلْ مِنَ الْفَصْلِ And who's this small child that left the Where'd you get this
[SPEAKER_00] small child? Okay, no. Who is the small child that left the class just now? Okay. So, you see how you translate الَّذِ as that. Right? So, that's why I said that. Although you can translate as who. Right? But you also can use it as that in this context as well. Good. The small boy that left right now from the classroom. So, this خَرَجَ الْآلَ مِنَ الْفَصْلِ is the صِرَةُ المُوصُول Right? So, I mean, just to explain a little bit more for those who want to know more about what the صِرَةُ المُوصُول is. Basically, you bring الَّذِ when you want to describe somebody with a sentence. Right? For example, you use one word, you could use مَوْصُول صِفَة Right? الْوَرَدُ الصَّغِيرُ Right? But now you want to describe him with a sentence. Like, you want to describe what action he's doing. So, then that's why you bring الَّذِ to connect it to that sentence that's describing him. And then you say الَّذِ Then, خَرَجَ الْآنَ مِنَ الْفَصِي Who left right now.
[SPEAKER_00] So that, you're making that whole sentence describe him. Everybody understand that? Okay, good. Alright, continue. هو ابن المُدير الجديد He is the principal's son. The new principal's son. Good. The new principal's son. Good. In this sentence, حَمْدَةُ الْوَصُولُ أَرُفُ جَبْءًا مَوْصُولُ If we're all five in this sentence, right? Where? This one you just said هو ابن المُدير الجديد حَمْدَةُ الْوَصُولُ Okay. مُضَعف مُضَعف إليه مَوْصُول صِفَة Yeah, very good. Yeah, that's true. Good. He is the son of the new principal. Good. Mashallah. I'm a little confused on how you would know like the order like where the end of you would come. Would it have to come after the subject or if it comes like the mausolah or if it was like like
[SPEAKER_00] who and maybe it would have to be like the subject of the sentence would come first and then it would be and maybe after that it was like the whole period so it's like two half a sentence you connect them to like this that's the concept? Not exactly. I was trying to translate the question into half a sentence but I know which one comes first. Like I'm sitting Give me an example. So I'm sitting in the classroom no I'm sitting and the does he in the classroom? So Does that make sense? أنا الذي أنا الذي جالس في الفصل أنا الذي هو جالس في الفصل I am the one who is sitting in the classroom. That's how you would say it. I mean that's kind of weird way to say it. You would rather just say أنا جالس في الفصل You don't need to use الذي He is the one who is sitting in the classroom Yeah. هو الذي يجلس في الفصل So then like in this example like what if comes before that so usually
[SPEAKER_00] the subject it would come before the one who Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Because when we translate it sometimes we would say the one who before. Yeah. Okay. Continue. Oh somebody else can read because you read a lot. We're almost done. Let's just finish this lesson quickly. Let's see. Okay you can read. I have a question. No but you can read anyways. Okay. I don't know why I said لِمَنِ الْمُلْكُ الْيَوْمِ Yeah. You're trying to remind us that you gave a fire example. Okay. Wait. لَدِئْتِيَا لَدِئْتِيَا فَوْعَنَ أُوْتَوْنَ وَلِلْأَرْضِئْتِيَا وَلِلْأَرْضِئْتِيَا Yeah. Does that work? وَلِلْأَرْضِئْتِيَا No because the earth already has كَسْرَ because لِلْ The lamb is حَرْفُ الْجَرْ right? وَلِلْأَرْضِ No, no. It's not what it is. Yeah. Okay. You
[SPEAKER_00] can read. Ali, you want to read? Okay, go ahead. لِمَن لِمَن is right but what's the next half of that? Yeah, please let the brother figure it out himself and he can do it. لِلْكُ الْسَيَّارَةُ الْجَمِيعِ And whose beautiful car is that? Good. Mashallah. Alright. هِيَا الْمُدِيرِ الْجَدِيدِ هِيَا لِلْ هِيَا Okay. هِيَا لِلْ مُدِيرِ الْجَدِيدِ It is a new principle. Yeah. Good. Okay. لِمَن هَذَا الْكِتَابُ الْكَبِيرُ Uh-huh. أَهُوَ الْمُدَرِّسِ أَهُوَ لِلْمُدَرِّسِ أَهُوَ لِلْمُدَرِّسِ Okay. Translate it. And whose
[SPEAKER_00] big book is this? Good. And whose big book is this? It is the teacher's. This is still a question, right? أَ Is it the teacher's? Yeah. Is it the teacher's? Yeah. Good. Good. أَهُوَ الْطَالِبِ الْجَدِيدِ No. It is the new student. Good. Mashallah. No, it is the new student. Very good. Mashallah. أَيْنَ الْمَلَعَفَةُ مَلَعَفَةُ صَغِيرُ صَغِيرَتُ صَغِيرَتُ Uh-huh. أَيْنَ Okay. Where is the مَلَعَفَةُ Let's look. The spoon, right? Yeah, good. صَغِيرَتُ صَغِيرَتُ is a cup? No. Small. Okay.
[SPEAKER_00] And where is the small spoon? Like a teaspoon. Okay. I mean, you don't translate a teaspoon. I'm just saying that's what it means. But you translate a small spoon. You're right. قُبُ Yeah, because of فِي. قُبُ Translate it. قُبُ We learned last time it means cup. Okay. I mean, you could pretty much guess that, right? قُبُ Cup, right? Because there's no P sound, right? So they say قُبُ Yeah. Or maybe in English because I'm sure because this is not a new word. This is coming from the Qur'an. It says أَكْوَاب Right? So. It is in the cup. Yeah, good. أَيْنَ الْمَلَعَفَةُ صَغِيرَتُ مَقْسُورُ Where is the broken chair? وَهُوَ رَكَى It is there. Very good. Mashallah. Alhamdulillah. Very good, mashallah. Alright. So we
[SPEAKER_00] got through this lesson. Now we finished lesson number What number is this? Lesson number nine. Alright. There was a lot that we went and covered in this lesson. Alright. Okay. So. The difference between this part of the lesson and the previous part of the lesson is that they introduced أَل Right? In the صفة موصوف and صفة Right? The previous ones, if you looked at it, all the موصوف صفة were with تنوين. Right? طالب جديد لغة جميلة Right? But in this lesson they're all with أَل Do you understand the difference? Right? That's all they were bringing. Nothing new. Right? So let's do the homework inshallah. Today is Wednesday? Yeah, so we're going to give a lot of homework inshallah. So let's do تَمْرِين نَمْبَر Wait, where are we? Yeah. تَمْرِين نَمْبَر وَان اقْرَأْ وَكْتُرَ Read and write.
[SPEAKER_00] Just translate it. All you have to do is translate it. Okay? And if there's any new word, for example, المُستَوصَف Right? المُستَوصَف in number one means the dispensary. Dispensary. It just means a place where you get drugs. No, مُستَشْفَة If you look at the end of that word, it means مُستَوصَف No, pharmacy is صَيْدَلِيَة صَيْدَلِيَة is pharmacy. مُستَوصَف is a dispensary. What do you get from a dispensary? Huh? What do you get from a dispensary? Drugs. Okay, المِرْوَحَة is a fan. That's on number three. Right? Is there another new word? Sorry? Is it not مُستَوصَف? مُستَوصَف? Dispensary is a bandage
[SPEAKER_00] from primary age. Oh, okay. Primary age. Okay, I don't know. I just guessed that's what it was. It's a dispensary mostly for the kids. It's not a hand-to-tooth, but it's the primary age. Oh, okay. I don't know. I just guessed that that's where you get drugs from because وَصْف means to prescribe. Like the word used to prescribe drugs or anything like that is وَصَفَ. هَدْ وَصَفَ الطَّبِيبُ ذَلِكَ means did the doctor prescribe that certain such drug. So I just assumed مُستَوصَف. So I assumed that that's what dispensary means. Small hospital. Okay, all right. You go for first aid. First aid. So urgent care. Like an urgent care. Okay, perfect. All right. Brother Ali works at مُستَوصَف then. Okay. All right. Any other new words? المدرسة الثانوية. المدرسة الثانوية. Number six means secondary school, which means basically high school.
[SPEAKER_00] Secondary school, which means high school, right? Is that what secondary school is? For the brothers in the back? Junior high? Secondary, junior. Is it? Or middle school. Secondary school. Oh, it's middle school. Okay. Okay. Secondary school, which means secondary school, right? Yeah. Kassani. From Kassani, from number two. Second. Okay. All right. We got everything else. We know everything else. So just translate it. Okay. Number two. Tell me number two, guys. Pay attention. Pay attention. Number two, you just fill in the blank. All you have to do is, they already gave you what word to put in. You just have to put it in the right form to make it a sifah, right? And then مُدَرِسُ, I'll just fill in the first one for you just so you know it. What to do. So he says جَدِيدُ in the parentheses. You just take that and make it to الجَدِيدُ because you're using it to describe, right? So sifah has to have the same four things, remember? What are
[SPEAKER_00] the four things? Remind me quickly. Gender. Gender. Number. Number. حركة. And definite or indefinite. Good. So you have to make it match. So that's all you have to do for this whole lesson, which is pretty easy, right? For number two. Okay. Sorry? Sorry? Where's one? So wait. أَيْنَ الْمُدَرِّسُ الْجَدِيدُ And number three, all you have to do is translate. Okay? All you have to do is translate. Alright? So that's 25 total exercises. It should keep you busy, inshallah, till Monday. Alright. سُبْحَانَ اللَّهُ وَبِحَمْدِي سُبْحَانَكَ اللَّهُ وَبِحَمْدِي كَنَ شَدُوَا لَّا إِلَهَ إِلَّا أَنْ تَرَسُوكُ فِرُكُمْ وَتُوبُوا إِلَيْهِ