[SPEAKER_00] As-salamu alaykum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatuhu. In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful. We praise and pray for the Holy Prophet, peace and blessings be upon him. In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.
[SPEAKER_00] In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful. In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.
[SPEAKER_00] In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful. But that's the default Okay I thought it would be like Like the book of Allah Yeah So the second word Becomes Kasbah Then the book of Allah Becomes Kasbah Not the first word Yeah Okay So the Quran Anu Kitabun Yeah But you don't put the mean Right You just say Kitabun Yeah Very good Inshallah You heard that Inshallah Very good We were missing your presence
[SPEAKER_00] Inshallah Usman you heard that Qalibun min Minal mursin Right You get that So it's not Qalibun ilal mursin Qalibun minal mursin You get it You know if you were to translate that It would say Close from Right In English it doesn't really make sense But We're not going by English We're going by Arabic You get it So that's why To some extent When you're in the beginning You have to kind of Translate things from English to Arabic But we want to move away From the Arabic From that And to Deal with Arabic as it is Right As it According to its own conventions Okay So what does that translate to Uroh Hassan Or The Quran is the book of Allah Very good MashaAllah The Quran is the book of Allah Wouldn't we A Quran Kitabillah No What would make Because the The Quran Is the Is What do you call Mubaf Mubaf Allah Hit the others Okay
[SPEAKER_00] So Who can tell me whylama Is not Over here Because that's We've mentioned The rule is That the Can never have Fortunately Right Okay That's why we That's how we learned That's why we're Doing this review in the first place this technique otherwise we would just learn to rule and carry on but nobody would have even really got the concept grasped it right that's why we keep on reading more and more and more and so it keeps on applying keep on applying until it sits in our own trouble okay and
[SPEAKER_00] yeah but they do laws that was the heart of the end the big law who they do a lot of a lot he okay why is it cool I'm saying this because of because of the word for doesn't have okay but yes you said half the job that's something that makes me guess but we also have one more thing that makes the word after a customer not just half the job right so who remembers yeah a lot about the day right so the book of Hamid kitab of Hamidin okay remember say out of the moon II right the car of principle everything yeah everything right so
[SPEAKER_00] so yeah so the the possessed will generally the possessor will be second will be to have a customer right yeah so for example Abdullah II remember even your own name I'm good I need me okay so so you read me okay so happy that we can gather to yeah they will all be a guy who they will all be the guy we all know what the guy is right so trying to get out of the Chinese yeah the car that is the house called the wall right obviously in this case we don't say it's literally the house of Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala the loss of perfect loss coming and I'll be combined confined to a specific place but we say that it is
[SPEAKER_00] attributable to Allah subhanaw daad as Sh tot Tat's least to show honor of this place probably our tribildingly it's your honor to the country right alsoцom builder oh in that sense that it's a very long eternal loss in God His place where切نا tämä transfers even on the green next Muhammad sallallahu alayhi wa sallam Rasool Allahi Very good, mashaAllah. Muhammad sallallahu alayhi wa sallam Rasool Allahi, right? You want to read it? No, I mean, Muhammad sallallahu alayhi wa sallam, is it a more or a more? Yeah, good question. Sallallahu alayhi wa sallam Why? Because this is a verb. This is a fair and mildly, it's a past tense verb. For example, we learn dhahabah, right? So, sallamah is on the same, similar pattern, not exactly the same, but similar pattern, right? So, sallamah, right?
[SPEAKER_00] Sallallahu alayhi wa sallam, right? May Allah's peace and blessings be upon him. This is a past tense verb, so because of that, it's meant to be a fatwa. Sallallahu alayhi wa sallam We usually say sallallahu alayhi wa sallam because, like, when you speak normally, you don't say the last harakah, but if you were to say it, you would say, sallallahu alayhi wa sallam Okay. So, translate it. Prophet or? Rasool Yeah, rasool is? Messenger Messenger is more accurate translation. Okay. Nabi is a prophet and rasool is a messenger. You got it? So, the messenger of Allah, rasool Allahi, right? This is the first statement you say to become Muslim. The messenger of Allah. Okay. Next. Brother Ali? The teacher left from the room of the principal. Very good, mashallah. Translate. The teacher left from the room
[SPEAKER_00] of the principal. Very good. The teacher left, right? So, means to leave, right? He left. But then is the one who's doing the leaving, right? So, we translate it as the teacher left from . The teacher, right? ... The principal left. And the working house was the workplace of the principal. Just stand there. Whatください He said. It doesn't matter. This household is my house. This house is a good quality home. This is the home of Hamadi, right? Except, the only thing is that if you write it, you'd add an masculine in it, right? Oh, because it's a male name. Yeah, so you want to say it again? Good, Mashallah. And the name is Hamid. Oh, Hamid. Yeah, but that's very good, Mashallah. So translate it. This is the house of Hamad,
[SPEAKER_00] and that is the house of Balad. Very good, Mashallah. Hada is for close, and Dariqah is for far. So this is the house of Hamad, and that is the house of Balad. Very good, Mashallah. Alright, Rada Ali, next one. Ibn Ammarin, Talib. Talib, was it Taliban, Talibun, Talibin? Which one is it? Talib. Or is it Talibu? Or is it Taliba? Or is it Talibi? Or is it just Talib? Talib, Talibi. Talibu? Close. Not exactly. Yes, Talibun. Good. Remember, if there's no reason to make it Fathar Kassar, then you keep it as default as Dhamma. Right? Okay. So you said Ibn Ammarin, right? That you got right? Yeah?
[SPEAKER_00] Talibun. Good. Wabnu. Wabnu. So this is Hamdatul Wasl. Remember we learned a rule for Hamdatul Wasl? Anybody remember the rule for Hamdatul Wasl? Yeah, when this type of Hamzah or Alif, whatever you want to call it, he comes in the middle of a sentence or in the middle of what you're saying, then it becomes silent, right? That's why you say Masmuka, right? You don't say Ma-ismuka, even though you heard the way it's written. Where are the markers? It's on the chair. Oh. So technically this is how you write Masmuka, right? What is your name, right? So if you
[SPEAKER_00] were to just, if you didn't know this rule and you were to read this, you would say, oh, Ma-ismuka, right? But in terms of the way we read, that's actually incorrect. That's why we say Masmuka, right? And that's why you see Arabs, they say Masmuka, right? What is your name? We say Masmuka just to make it clear because we're learning, we want to make every letter clear, right? But to shorten it, they say Masmuka. What is your name? So Ism means name. Ismuka means your name. Remember we learned this when we were having our conversations, right? Your blank, Ismuka, right? Qalamuka, your pen. Qursiyuka, your chair. Right? Kitabuka, your book. Beytuka, your house. Right? So at the end, that means your, right? So Ismuka is your name. So Ma is what is. So what is your name? Masmuka, right? But the reason I mention this in the first place is because of this, right? This is called Hamzat al-Wasl. And you don't pronounce it when it comes in the middle, right? Another easy thing that
[SPEAKER_00] we say all the time is Wallahi, right? So generally, when we say Allah's name, we say Allah, right? We don't say Wa-Allahi, right? We just say Wallahi. We skip the Hamzah. Why? Because this is under the Wasl. So you skip it. You just say Wallahi. But when Allah comes in the beginning of a sentence, you say Allah, right? For example, Allah alladhi khalaqa al-samaawati wa al-ard. Right? But then when it comes in the middle, then you don't say it. You say Wahoo Wallahu fi al-samaawati wa fi al-ard. Wahoo Wallahu. You don't say Wahoo Allah. You say Wahoo Wallahu. Here we get it? So this Hamzah is Hamzat al-Wasl, right? We already learned that for previously when we learned it. What context did it come in? Anybody remember? Al, right? Al. So we learned that when the Hamzah at the beginning of Al, the Alif Laam, that's the Hamzat al-Wasl. So it's
[SPEAKER_00] not pronounced when it comes in the middle of a sentence. Got it? So the thing over here, Ism, right? So when we say, sorry, Ibn, right? So when we say, Ibn, right? So the Hamzah here is also Hamzat al-Wasl. So you don't say, Wa ibn, you say, Wa ibn. Yeah. Shay, question real quick. What's the difference between Wallahi and Wallah? I mean, basically it's just like, it's the same thing, right? Technically, but Wallahi is grammatically correct in a sense that you're, the wow, this is called Wow al-Qasam. The wow when you're swearing on something is also a Harful Jar. Remember we learned about Harful Jar? A letter that makes the word after it, Kasra, right? So when you're saying the wow, with the intention of it being a Qasam, a swear, an oath, then it becomes a Harful Jar. That's why you see a lot of the Surahs in the Quran, they start with Wa, and the word after it becomes Kasra. Remember, Was-Sama'i Wa-Tariq, because Allah is swearing on the sky, right? Wa, Wa-Sham-Si Wa-Duhaha,
[SPEAKER_00] right? So the wow, there's a Harful Jar because for Qasam, it's for swearing, because for taking an oath. So, Wa-Sham-Si Wa-Duhaha. So in the same way, when we swear by Allah, we say, Wallahi, you get it? Now, generally, Arabs, when they speak, again, they don't pronounce every single Haraka. Otherwise, if they were, they should be saying Wallahi, right? But they just pause it, and suddenly say Wallah. Wallah. How can you differentiate if the wow is indicating a swear, or it just means an oath? I just said it, because if what comes right after it is a Kasra, Yeah. So, the wow has specific rules, I mean, I can't go into all the details later. The wow has different rules that we will learn, inshaAllah, with regards to the Arabs and the Haraka at the end. But generally, this wow is a Harful Jar, so, yeah, so when we say Wallahi, it's you're swearing by something, you're taking an oath or something. Okay, let's get this move quickly, because I want to start the next lesson quickly, quickly.
[SPEAKER_00] Ibn al-Akbarin Qalibun Wabnu Yasirin Najirun Very good, Mashallah, good reading. Translate it for me. I'm having trouble with Ibn al-Akbarin Qalibun Wabnu Yasirin Najirin Najirin Najirin Najirin Ibn is son. Oh. You know, people say bin, right? Oh, okay. Qalib bin Walid, but technically in Arabic, there's no such thing as really bin, right? It's Ibn al-Akbarin Qalibun Wabnu Yasirin Najirin Najirin Najirin Najirin Najirin Najirin Najirin Right? Umar is the son of the student? Wait. The student is the son of Umar. No, no. No. Remember, the easiest way to translate when it's Muldaaf Al-Mudhafi, the blank of blank. The blank of blank. Oh, the son of Umar is the student. Good, yeah. The son of Umar is the student, good. The son of Yasir is the merchant? Yeah, is a merchant. Because it's not Al-Tajir, it's Tajirun, so a merchant. Very good, Mashallah. Ibn al-Akbarin Qalibun, the son of Umar, Umar's son
[SPEAKER_00] is a student. Wabnu Yasirin Tajirun, the son of Yasir is a merchant. Got it? Everybody understood that? Yeah. Okay. All right. Wabnu Yasirin? Is your son a merchant? Bayt al-Tajirin? Yeah, good. Bayt al-Tajirin? Sorry, Bayt al-Tajirin? Remember, if there's nothing that's going to make it, then there's no need, right? The general rule is going to be Dhamma. So if you're confused, it's possibly Dhamma, right? I'm not saying, I'm not guaranteeing, right? But generally, the general rule is Dhamma unless you see something, it's like a or something else to make it. So you're saying Bayt al-Tajirin? Yeah, Bayt al-Tajirin,
[SPEAKER_00] yeah. Bayt al-Tajirin? Alibun? Okay. Please. Bayt al-Mudalisi Dharimu Bayt al-Tajirin Khadimu? Hadid? The teacher house is far away and merchant house is Khadimu. Yeah, the merchant's house. Either of the house should we ask for or we just say the house of the merchant. Okay. Khadadif? Khadam is the house of the merchant. Khadadif? Good. Masha'Allah. Ayinam iftakhul bayt? Good. Bayt tahtu ti? Bayti. Good. Masha'Allah. Okay. Khadam iftakhul sayyaratin, ayinam iftakhul bayti. Okay. Translate it please. This key, this key. No. Let the brother speak. This is the car's key? Good. Masha'Allah. This is the car's key or the key of the car. Good. Masha'Allah. Where is the house key? Very good. Masha'Allah. All right. Another
[SPEAKER_00] question. Yes, sir. How do some of the words have her own meaning? I would like to ask you to tell us if there are other words that you know of, but others don't. The author just thought he'd help you out on some of the words, but the other ones he said you already know those words so you better know how to pronounce them by now. It's already been six lessons, five lessons and you already know how to pronounce them. I do know. Okay. All right. How about the next one? Min ayin? Min anta? Min? Min? Min? Min? Min anta? No, I'm asking you, is it min or waal? So, okay, finish the sentence first. Min anza ya waalil. Yeah. So, ya what, sorry? Ya waalil. Waal-il? Ya waalil. Waal-il. Di? Waal-il. Okay, all right. So, now, why is there a question mark if this is min, right? No. For there to be a question mark, there should be one of the nosy
[SPEAKER_00] family that's always asking questions, right? Which is a lot of us to count, right? Do you see any of those here? If it's min, min anza, no? I'll answer it for you. No, there's nothing like that here, right? So, that's why this is not min. If it's not min, what could it be? Man. What does man mean? Who, yeah. Okay, so who is the son? No. And who is the... What does anza mean? You. Not the real speak, please. Oh. Who is you, what? Who are you? Who are you? Oh, who are you? Who are you, yeah. Remember we mentioned that is, there's no words here, because is, so you just fill it in, right? So, you can change it to are, right? Depending on the circumstances. So, who are you? Wait, okay, and then the next sentence? Right, so I don't want to say min, like,
[SPEAKER_00] who are you? Just speak to me. Mine, I'm. Right? Oh, that's it. Who are you? Who are you? And then, yeah, like, is that like a... What does what that mean? Like student. Oh, the kid? Kid, yeah, child, yeah. And I forgot what it was. Who are you, kid? Basically, that's what it's saying. Who are you, kid? Yeah. Or if you wanted to make it more archaic, then who art thou, oh, child? Okay. Okay. And I'm not. Who are... Who are... Who are... So, okay. Say it again. Speak with me, speak with me. We're out of time. Or I am Abani Abbas. And I take me? Abani Abbas. Why is it Kessler? Because. There's no reason for it to be Kessler. Oh, Abani? Yes. Abasi. Abasi or? Abbas. No. The Kessler is right, but should it have one Kessler or two? Abbas. Sin?
[SPEAKER_00] Sin, yes. Because. Because it's a male name, so you can put a demeanor. So you're supposed to put a demeanor. Abbas. Okay. Who are you, child? Oh, child. I am the son of Abbas. Yeah, I am the son of Abbas. Okay. All right. Specifying no gender. Where? What it is... What is a male child? All right. Bint is a female child. So it is... You're specifying your gender. And also you're saying... Yeah, so is for male. If you were to say female, you say , right? So if you want to ask somebody at a public house, like, who are you? You know, if you want to get to know somebody, then say , right? No, but... No, if they're Abbasian, keep them in Abbasian. Yeah, so? They have to be Abbasian at the end. Yeah, so we don't mean Abbasian. Okay. Okay. Is it? Is it
[SPEAKER_00] what I do or what I do? You tell me. We learned this last class. What is it? What did we learn last class? Oh, it's... About... Yeah. Yeah, yeah. It moves the... And? And the word becomes... Say that... Okay? Yeah. Yeah. I guess nobody did that exercise at home. Did you? Okay. I did it. You did? Mashallah, very good. All right. Let's get moving very quick. Come on, come on. Who wants to... Raise your hand if you're ready. Everybody's ready. Let's go. Who is he the son of? Who? Who is Ibn Khadid? Who is Ibn... Who is Ibn... Sorry, the next one, right? Who is Ibn Khadid? Yeah. Again, it's the Hamad al-Basra. So you don't say, Who is Ibn? You say, Who is Ibn Khadid? Who is he the son of? He's the son of Khadid. Yeah. Very good, mashallah. Ibn Man. Right? So it gets a little confusing when you see Man like that, right?
[SPEAKER_00] The son of whom? Right? So again, it helps to put it in that format of blank of blank, right? Again, I feel like that's the easiest way to understand the Malaf, the Malaf Ilaik, the Possessor and the Possessed. The blank of blank, right? So Ibn Man, the son of whom? You get it? Is that. Is he, right? The son of whom is he? Or whose son is he? Right? Then he is Ibn Khadid. He is the son of Khadid. Okay. Alright, Brother Samir? Okay. Oh, okay. I want to ask you about this Samir, but you go ahead. I missed a few classes, so I'm not sure. Okay, so we can tell this person. No, it's okay. I'll talk to you. No, this is Masjid. Oh, Masjid. Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00] Aina Mashidu. Masjidu. Rasul al-Mari. Okay. So Masjidu. Why are you saying Masjidu? Masjid. I'm asking you why. It's right. So I'm asking you because it felt right for a reason. Because it's a Mudaf. Right? So if that's a Mudaf, then the word after will be? Yeah, which will be? Kasbah. Kasbah. Exactly. Now, read it. Read it. Aina Masjidu Rasulillahi. Very good, Mashallah. This is a very hard point when they got it, right? This is a double, he got a double Big Mac, right? Double Mudaf, Mudaf ilayh, right? So Masjid is Mudaf and Rasul is Mudaf ilayh. And Rasul is also the Mudaf and Allah is a Mudaf ilayh. So let's just write that here. Mashallah. A is to Mudaf. Okay.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay. Masjidu Rasulillahi. Right? So Masjidu, right? There's no Mudaf in here because it's Mudaf, right? The Masjid of Rasul, the Messenger, right? Now this is Kasbah, but why is there no two Tameens, right? If it's Mudaf ilayh, it shouldn't be Rasulilayh, right? But because this is the Mudaf, so the next word, so it could be Kasbah, it's Mudaf ilayh, but it's not going to be Tameen because it's also the Mudaf to the word after.
[SPEAKER_00] Get it? So the Masjid of the Messenger of Allah. You get it? So that's why it's a double Mudaf, Mudaf ilayh. Everybody understand that point? There's one rule that you said that there's nothing between Mudaf, Mudaf ilayh. Say it again? You said there's nothing coming between Mudaf, Mudaf ilayh. Yeah. There's the part right here where you said there's nothing coming between it so it's still Mudaf, Mudaf ilayh. Yeah. There's nothing coming between it. It's Mudaf, Mudaf ilayh. Does everybody understand this? The double Mudaf, Mudaf ilayh? Right? I mentioned this in another example last night. Maliki yaumid din. Right? The master of the day of judgment. Maliki yaumid. That's Kessara because it's Mudaf ilayh. Ad-Din. Right? It's Kessara because it's also Mudaf ilayh. Right? And yaumid is Kessara doesn't have Dinweem because it's Mudaf also. So there can be multiple Mudaf. Sometimes there's like there's five or six Mudaf, Mudaf ilayh like in succession sometimes in the area. So it can come like that. So good.
[SPEAKER_00] Mashallah. Okay. So so so in the masjid of Rasulullah can you translate please? Where is the masjid of Rasulullah salallahu alayhi wa sallam? Okay. Good. Who are in Medina al-Munawwarah? Yeah. Al-Munawwarah. Very good. Mashallah. Translate that. It is in Medina al-Munawwarah. Very good. It is in Medina al-Munawwarah the enlightened city when I translate it literally. Al-Munawwarah means enlightened and Al-Medina means city. Okay. Alright. Let's get that right. Yeah. Bintu Hamidin bin Matisati wa Bintu Muhammadin bin Jamil. Very good. Translate it please. Daughter of Muhammad is in the school and daughter of Muhammad is in the university. Very good. Mashallah. Daughter of Muhammad is in the school and daughter of Muhammad is in the university. Okay. Next.
[SPEAKER_00] Al-Qadir. Very good. Just a very slight mistake. Somebody want to tell him where he made this slight mistake? Yeah. Good. Wasm Al-Muhandisi. Remember the wasm? So you don't pronounce the ism. You just say Wasm Al-Muhandisi. Very good. Mashallah. Translate please. The name of the teacher is Saeed and the name of the engineer is Khalid. Yeah. Al-Muhandisi we learned previously that it means engineer. Okay. All right. Yeah. What's the name? Okay. No, no. Okay. It's a new word. All right. So I'll let you get past this new word. Amd means paternal uncle. Amd means It's not a question of master. It's just a question of mission, right?
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, it's a statement, yeah. Amd means paternal uncle. What does paternal uncle mean? It means your, in Urdu, you would say your cha-cha, right? Your father's brother. Okay? Maternal uncle would be something that would be qalm, right? But we don't get to that, right? In Urdu, it's similar to when you say qalm, right? So in Arabic, it's qalm, but right now, the paternal uncle, which is the uncle from your father's side, your father's brother, so where does this come from in the Qur'an? A plural form of it. Yeah, that's a female, though. That's amma is your father's, your pupi, your pupo, sorry, yeah, your father's sister. Yeah. You're the daughters of your father, meaning your female
[SPEAKER_00] cousins. So in Arabic, when you want to say your cousin, it's a little, it seems strange to us because we just say cousin, right? But they say ibn amm, right? The son of your paternal uncle, which means your cousin is from your father's side, and ibn al-khal means your cousin from your mother's side. So there's no generic word for cousin, rather they specify, is it from the children of your paternal uncle or the children of your maternal uncle. So in the Qur'an it says, wa banati ammikat, right? The female children of your paternal uncle, right? It shouldn't be wa banat, wa banat tu, ammikat? It's in the Qur'an, bro. It's easy because the wine comes out. Yeah, so as we mentioned, the mudhaf can be either fatrakas or dhamma, right? It doesn't matter. So you have to look at the context, what came before it. There is something at the beginning at that makes it kasra, right? If we could say
[SPEAKER_00] the beginning of the ayah, that would help. Is it the oath of the world? No, it's not the oath, no. What's the beginning of the ayah? Inna ahlal lalak azwajil kallati atay takujan ammikat, imma wala kadamir mimma fa'ad dhawari obnati ammikat. Inna ahlal lalak azwajil kallati atay takujan ammikat, umma malakat amminu fa'mimma afa' allahu alayka. Yeah, min. Because of the min, are you listening Othman? Because of the min, it became kasra. Mimma afa' allahu alayka obnati amminu. Good? Sorry? Surah Ahzab. Okay. Alright. But good question though. It's good that we should keep on thinking why is it kasra, why is it fatwa, why is it dhawma. This question should bug our mind all the time now because now we're learning Arabic, these things matter, right? It makes a big
[SPEAKER_00] difference to us now. So it's good question Othman. I was just joking, you know, don't take it. I'm just kidding. Don't do that. So when you're saying cousin, would you say ibnul khal or ibnul amm or ibnul amm? It sort of depends, right? If you're being specific, ibnul khal, then he is, this just means the son of the, but you say ibnul khali, the son of my maternal uncle or ibnul ammi, who ibnul ammi, it is the son of my paternal, so you're saying my cousin. Are you saying your cousin or say ibnul ammika, ibnul khalika, right? That's why in the Quran it says because Allah is talking to the Prophet salallahu alayhi wa salam, the daughters of your paternal uncle. You get it? Okay. Alright. Let's get done with the prayer quickly. We didn't go into it. Oh yeah, ghaniyun, what does ghaniyun mean? Rich. Right,
[SPEAKER_00] okay, so ammuk khali, ghaniyun, the paternal uncle of the student is rich. Okay. Alright, brother with us here. Yeah, ammuk khali, yes, ghaniyun. Very good, don't worry No problem, which thing which thing Fattaha it gives a meaning of opening right? That's why مفتاح is a key and it's through which it's gonna muftuh fathaha it means уِشْأَالْهاَ It's open, right? And فَتْح means to conquer something because when you conquer a city, the doors of it become open to
[SPEAKER_00] you. So it's as if you opened up the city for yourself, right? So الفَتْح is a conquering city. So the word فَتْح in general, it indicates towards opening. So مَفْتُوح means open, right? And مِفْتَح means the key, the tool through which you open something. فَتِح, right? Yeah, the opening, the beginning of the plan. So read it again, translate it again quickly. The door of your mission is open, and the door of the school is closed. Okay, very good. مُغْلَقُن, that's a new word. You guessed it, good. مُغْلَقُن means closed. So let's say somebody is late to Arabic class and they try to get in and say, يَعْخِي, they're not, الْبَابُ مُغْلَقُن, right? If they're not, يَعْخِي الْبَابُ, right? The door is closed. Open the door. You get it? So مُغْلَق means something is closed. Okay? All right.
[SPEAKER_00] Brother Hussain. Louder, louder. خَال, is it خَال? What did you say? Okay, good, yeah. خَالُ حَامِدٍ فَقِيلٌ You're going to translate? Yeah. حَامِد is what? Yeah. So حَامِد, maternal uncle, is poor. So it's like the opposite of the previous sentence, right? The maternal uncle is rich, but the maternal uncle is poor. So خَال is, in Arabic, is your maternal uncle, meaning your mother's brother. Have you ever got it? Actually, in Urdu, it would be your mamu, right? خَال is your mamu, okay? In Urdu. So yeah. Okay. Yeah, so خَال is your maternal uncle and عَمْد is your paternal uncle, right? خَال also comes with the Quran as well, but we won't go into that right now.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay. Quickly, let's see. مصطفى. Me? Okay, yeah, forget it. It's not important. I'll throw it to you. سَيَّرَكُمْ Yes, good. بِالسَّرِيُّ It's a sheen, right? بِالسَّرِيُّ Yeah, بِالسَّرِيُّ بِالسَّرِيُّ Yes, في. Right? So في makes next word, كَسْرَصَ They say بِالسَّرِيُّ So سَيَارَكُمْ عَبْبَاسِين Okay, try that again. The car or the bus. Oh, sorry, I didn't mean the word. بِالسَّرِيُّ It's a road track. It's a road track. It's a road track. It's a road track. It's a road track. It's a road track. means street okay so when you go to next time now you go to sound you can look so security guards you know
[SPEAKER_00] you can talk to security guards and tell them this street over here is a shadow and if you notice if you if you look at the the street sign you'll see that it says shadow blank buddy it's blank buddy it was a way right so they're neat like we have over your street road Avenue place court all those things right so they have slightly different words that mean the same thing so a shadow it means a street right or a road Sharia actually the word Sharia is the tidbit an interesting did it just to keep us interested Sharia come from the same the same root right Sharia is the pathway towards water right now if you think about what's the significance why is the Dean of Allah the laws of Allah's given us call the Sharia the literal meaning is the pathway to water because water is a source of life right so the Sharia it guides us towards the true source of life the true way that we can live our life in a matter that is beneficial to ourselves the way we can live the best possible way okay
[SPEAKER_00] so that's just an interesting tidbit so Sharia is literally speaking it's a path for water so in the same way just to remember that you can remember a shadow is a street and if you look at the street signs in Saudi you'll see shadow very often the streets now you'll know inshallah what it means it's feminine masculine sorry okay okay so say yeah the car is in the street good so now you can now you know how to say a part in the street right yeah right instead of saying parking remember we learned parking lot last time can remember can I remind me how to say parking lot close yeah both if we say out is the parking lot right we learn that new word in our previous session the actual session so you don't worry everybody was confused don't worry if you didn't come you didn't know both people say out
[SPEAKER_00] this parking lot so now you know how to say my car is in the parking lot and you also know how to say my car in the street right so again it might seem like we learned a little bit we actually learned a lot if you really think about it and we start applying you can actually make a lot of sentence you can have full-blown conversations now if you actually put it together and you know start losing me okay so fish daddy right it's in the street right our bus car is in the street right today even now like let's say after Juma you guys are gonna go can you drop me off my car then like oh where's your car oh say I don't need this shadow right you can say my car is in the road right so you know that you're not part of the parking lot you're the part on the street right so again we should try to start utilizing it so we can implement the shadow and then when I say that is not in the parking lot like I would say this one parking lot this one you keep my cell phone because so I say mouth you
[SPEAKER_00] know means that it's a um a shadow you're not even going to take it back so mouth yeah yeah no people say um yeah the parking lot all right okay next one very quickly this ended off brother Jibril good just two slight very slight mistakes can anybody point it out you have a little cacha um good right remember the house right so see brother Akasha made a similar mistake but now he learned from his mistakes and is preventing others right so that's how we learn right we we we make the mistake that we learn that now we're able to you know it'll stick in our brain actually
[SPEAKER_00] if you make a mistake and if you you get it fixed then most likely you won't make that mistake again right so don't be afraid to make mistakes if you're not going to raise your hand you're going to try to hide and not read in class because you're afraid you're going to be afraid of it and you're not going to be afraid of it called on or told that you're wrong, then you're also not going to learn, right? Because then you're not going to get fixed, right? Brother Qadhi just made that mistake, now he's fixing others who have made that mistake. You get it? So it's actually beneficial for us to make mistakes so that we can learn. So Brother Jubeel, say it again. So one more slight thing, right? One mistake and another. A very small mistake. You said, So again, that, Again, you don't pronounce it. So you just say, Right? See that Arabs, just a point to note here, that Arabs, they prioritize making things flow, right? That's why they didn't used to say, So
[SPEAKER_00] it's kind of like breaking the rules technically, because it's Al, right? It's Ibn, right? But they purposely would not pronounce it to make the sentence flow, right? So there's so many things, inshaAllah, we keep learning. And you realize that the Arabs really, when they spoke, they emphasized flow. That's why the Qur'an flows so beautifully, right? Altogether. So that's something to note here. That's why you have these rules there in the first place. Okay, we'll end right here, inshaAllah, very quickly. So translate it very quickly. Very quickly. Sorry, Ibn Man. Ibn Man. Translate it as blank of blank. Of blank. Sorry, Ibn means what? What does Ibn mean? Ibn means our son. Yeah, so now translate it. Ibn Man. Son of you. Son of? Of Antara. What does Man mean? From. That's Min. Say that again? Min means from, right? Man. Yeah. Who? Yeah. Whose son?
[SPEAKER_00] Whose son? Yes, very good. Whose son? Whose son is this? Anta means? Yeah, who's this son? No, what does Anta mean? You. You, right? So now translate it, Ibn Man, Anta. Who's the son of? Yeah, exactly. Yeah. Or if you want to just translate it literally to make it easier, Ibn Man, the son of whom are you, right? But yeah, whose son are you? Right? This is actually a very tricky one, right? So don't feel bad. This is kind of tricky. I like it. Yeah, the son of whom are you? Whose son are you? Right? Like, who's your dad? My dad. All right. Anta Ibn Um. Anta Ibn Um, you don't see him. Yeah. I'm the son of the teacher. Yeah, very good. Who said it was your dad? Who said it? Should we start? Oh, somebody said it. How would you say that? Like this. I've been having a problem with this actual same thing. Okay. When I asked you about the hadith, I said always start off and say, Anta, I'm
[SPEAKER_00] like, Ibn Um, I always have a bunch of them. Yeah, exactly. Okay, last one. Let's finish up. Yeah. No, not yet. Okay, let's do it again. Okay. Okay, remember last class we learned? The rule for tahtah, right? Generally, what was the rule we learned for tahtah? It's not a hafidh job, but it makes the word after kasma. Okay, that's one thing. About tahtah, it makes the word after kasma. But the second thing is? Anybody remember? Tahtah generally is a fadhaan, right? Should we say? Tahtah. Tahtah. It has a fadhaan. So that's the general rule.
[SPEAKER_00] Just remember that. Tahtah generally will have a? Just a fadhaan on it, right? Okay, so this would be? Huwa tahtas sayyara. Is it taht or teen? Teen. Teen, yeah. Huwa tahtas sayyara. Where should we translate it? Under the car. Okay, good. Yeah. MashaAllah. Yeah. Where is the? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Where is the dog? He's under the car. Yeah. He or it. You can say he too because you can talk to dogs. Okay. All right. I was hoping we would breeze through this and we would start the next lesson as well. But I think it's good. We hopefully just got solidified, inshallah. It was clear that we still needed work on it. So, inshallah. The hands-on is it, man. Sorry? The hands-on. Yeah. Yeah. So, hopefully, inshallah, we got to solidify this concept. Everybody feel like they got
[SPEAKER_00] a good grasp of it now? Yeah. We got a good grasp of it, inshallah. Okay. All right. So, let's do this homework. Did we do this homework already or not? Yeah. We did five and six. We did five and six already? Yeah. Yeah. Okay. I didn't remember that. Okay. Do number seven, right? Okay. Okay. So, read and write along with writing the hawaq at the end of the words, right? So, do you say, Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So, read it to yourself so that it solidifies and write at the end. Is it a fatha ka surah dham or what? Right? Then, the next is, Right? So, it's helping you practice this question of whose blank is this? Right? Right? How do you say, whose man's is this? How do you say that? Somebody try that. You guys already know all the words. Huh?
[SPEAKER_00] Sorry? No. No kitab. Close. Rijal is plural. How do you say it? It's singular. Very good. Right? Whose man's is this? Okay? Right? Right. But, in all seriousness, right? Kitab and manhada, this is a form, right? This is a sentence form that they're trying to teach you, right? Whose blank is this? Whose blank is this? Right? So, you just fill it in. Rijal, they gave a picture of a pen, right? So, you write, whose pen is this, in Arabic. Then, they put a picture of a shirt. You put, whose shirt is this, in Arabic. They put a picture of a house. Whose house is this? They put a picture of a bed. Whose bed is this? So, basically, they want you to translate those sentences into Arabic. Turn those into questions. Whose blank is that? Then, ism, ibn, we learned that. You don't have to know something we used to do there. Then, the last, number 32, we'll do in class tomorrow,
[SPEAKER_00] inshaAllah. I think that's it. Not much homework. But, inshaAllah, next class, we're going to do a lot. Also, alhamdulillah, the books finally came, the writing books. So, I'm still trying to think if we should start, because we have a break coming up soon. I think the 12th, or I forgot what day we had decided, but it's only in about a week or two that we decided we're going to stop classes for a month or so, because people are going to go on vacation and stuff. We'll post the details. But, we have to have a test before we have that, right? So, I'm thinking, maybe, just continue classes, maybe have a couple of review sessions for class before the test. And then, after the break, we start off by writing, doing the writing exercises, and getting our writing done properly, and then we'll continue with the book. Everything is good? Yeah, inshaAllah. Alright, so we'll have a test. I'll announce the date of the test before the break, inshaAllah. Then, you'll have a well-deserved break. You'll feel very happy to have a break, inshaAllah, after that test, inshaAllah. Alright. Alhamdulillah, inshaAllah.
[SPEAKER_00] I couldn't find a mistake in this. It's already like that. Yeah. So, the mistake is, remember we learned that the boss did not have two things to go to sleep with? Yeah. We won't have all of them. Or? All of them, or what? Other options? No. You can have one from Khuya and two from Iyunoor. Definitely one. How do you perform? All of the things were Tran have been struggling with, and todayárias man has the opportunity.