[SPEAKER_00] Bismillah ar-Rahman ar-Raheem. As I mentioned in the group, I'm not sure if everybody was able to see it. But we decided to have a short class today. Instead of cancelling the class, I thought it's good because there's a lot of barakah in having something going on a consistent basis. The most beloved actions to Allah are those which are consistent, even if they may be little. So even if we're having class for a short period of time, inshallah we'll have barakah and we'll get a lot done, inshallah. So I remember I mentioned in the last class, Bismillah ar-Rahman ar-Raheem, that we're going to go over an important concept. Does anybody remember what it was called? Mawsoof and Sifah, right? So basically the adjective and then the thing that is described, right? Mawsoof is the thing that's described and Sifah is the adjective. Meaning, adjective is obviously an English grammatical term, but an adjective describes a noun, right? So you have a noun and then you have the adjective, a word that describes that noun, right?
[SPEAKER_00] So the first example we came across was, تاجر غني So تاجر is a noun, that is a موصوف. تاجر غني So this is the موصوف. This is the Sifah. It's much easier to write on here. So yeah, I mentioned to you guys, but I don't think I wrote it down, so I'll write it down this time. That the موصوف and the Sifah, they have to correspond in four things, right? Meaning the Sifah, it follows the موصوف in four things, right? They have to be the same in those four things. What are those four things? One is gender. I'll just write it in Arabic too, just so you have the Arabic term too, for those who want to know.
[SPEAKER_00] تتكير وتتنيث تتكير means being male and تتنيث means being female. So in one word in English, gender, right? So this is تاجر غني But let's say we're talking about a female merchant, right? We live in a feminist world. So let's say we talk about a female merchant. So أمين تاجرت Then you can't leave this as غني. It has to become غنيت This concept is not foreign to us because we really learned this when we talk about مبتدأ and خبر, right? Meaning, for example, التاجرة غنيت So this is nothing new to us, but what's going to come next will be something we haven't covered yet. So it has to be the same in terms of gender. Then, there's no particular order to these, by the way. I'm just going to order them in the order
[SPEAKER_00] that I remember. The next is singular. You can just make it easy to say in number, right? That's the easy way to just do it. But basically, in the fact that it's either singular, plural, or dual, right? In Arabic, you have three categories. In English, you only have two, either singular or plural, right? Two and above is considered plural, and one is singular. But in Arabic, you have... An extra category, dual, right? Two. So that's going to come up. Don't worry about that. But whatever the case is, if this موصوف is singular, then the صفة has to be singular. So تاجرون So let's take out the ت, right? So تاجرون غنيون That's singular, right? Now, if we were to say two merchants, it would be تاجراني, right? Usually, that's the way to denote two of something. You just add آني, أليف, and نون, right?
[SPEAKER_00] So تاجراني, but you can't leave it as غني. You have to change it to غنياني, okay? So this becomes غنياني. Okay, it looks kind of ugly, but that's what it is. غنياني, right? Now, if we were doing plural, again, same thing. They have to be the same. So it would be... The plural of تاجر is تجار. Okay? تجار تجار أغنياء The plural of غني is أغنياء. Okay? تجار أغنياء Right? You couldn't say تجار غني You would have to say تجار أغنياء So it has to follow in its number. Okay? In Arabic, you can say... I mean, if you want to be technical, it would be...
[SPEAKER_00] إفراد والتثنية والجمع Meaning it being singular, because singular is مفرد in Arabic. It being dual, because a dual is مثنى in Arabic. Or الجمع, which is it being plural, right? Then the third thing that they have to match in is... Their إعراب Meaning the last حركة الإعراب Right? And the last حركة That means that... Let's say if this was... Right? كسر for some reason, right? Let's say if there's ف Even though it doesn't make sense in the... In the context, right? تاجر Let's go back to تاجر, right?
[SPEAKER_00] تاجر غني Right? So let's say if there's a ف before it, right? This becomes تاجرين Right? Then, this also will become كسر تاجرين غنيين You got it? Right? So it has to be the same. Same thing, like... If there was فتحة If it was... Yeah. If it had فتحة Then... رأيت We didn't get to this why it becomes فتحة But we'll get to that, inshallah, soon enough. رأيت تاجر غنيين Got it? Right? So, because this became فتحة This also... This also had to automatically become فتحة Right? And same thing when it's just تاجر غنيين So meaning doesn't
[SPEAKER_00] change? Meaning does change. Meaning in terms of... Because of the word that comes before it, right? But this... This specifically stays the same. It just means rich merchant. Right? It just depends on what comes before it that determines the اعراب meaning the last حركة of this word. What about the plural? Because the plural is strange Because it's just أغنياء أغنياء Yeah. So it would be تجاراً رأيت تجاراً أغنياء Yeah. But the أغنياء is not the same though. It is the same. Right? This is a technical difference. أغنياء is a special exceptional case. That's why I wanted to change it back to تاجر I hope nobody would notice but you got me. Because أغنياء is a special type of word which cannot have تنوين. Right? But it still has فتحة though. Right? So both of them still have فتحة. Okay. You get it? Okay. Yeah. But don't worry about the exceptions. It's just going to confuse you. Yeah. What does رأي فتحة
[SPEAKER_00] mean? Yeah? What does it mean رأي فتحة? I saw. I saw a rich merchant. Yeah. I mean, you don't have to worry about this part again because that's going to come. I'm just bringing this to show you that if there's something to make it فتحة then the صفة will also become فتحة. Right? The bottom line is they have to follow in these three things. Right? The last is in being definite or indefinite. Do you guys remember what indefinite and indefinite is? Yeah. So I'm going to write that. And give me an example. Yeah, exactly. So if it's then it will be Right? And also if it's a proper noun. Remember what a proper noun is? Like a name. Right? Like محالة. محمد is a name. So that's معرفة is definite because you're talking about a specific person. Right? But if it's just رجل
[SPEAKER_00] رجل then that would be نكرة that would be indefinite. Right? So now if this was again, let's go back to تاجر غنيون so we don't get confused with the فتحة and stuff. Right? So تاجر غنيون Right? So because this is نكرة then this will also be نكرة. This is probably one of the most important aspects. This is where you see the difference between what we've done before and what we're doing now. Right? So because this is نكرة this will also be نكرة. If this was التاجر then this would also have to be الغني You get it? So now this is where it will become clear the difference between this and what we've been learning. If you were to say this التاجر غنيون Right?
[SPEAKER_00] Sorry, it's bad handwriting. Right? غنيون Right? So this would not be considered موصوف and صفة Right? It would not be considered an adjective and a noun. Why? Because this is actually a subject and predicate. So you're saying Remember, we've been learning this type of sentence for a long time. How would you translate this? The merchant is. So the key word is is. Right? Over here, how would you translate this? The rich merchant. Right? And the key difference is this is a complete sentence. Right? This is not a complete sentence. Right? Just like in English. Right? If you're going to say the rich merchant then the person who's listening is going to think what about the rich merchant? Right? And you're going to tell me something about them. Right? So as soon as you add something like التاجر الغني For example
[SPEAKER_00] طويل Right? Now it's a complete sentence. The rich merchant is tall. Right? So the key difference is that this is معرفة and this is نكرة but in this case both of them are معرفة or both of them are نكرة. Right? So this is probably the most important thing but we just need to know that the موصوف and the صفة the adjective and the noun they have to correspond in these four things. Everybody got that? So how would you say if it's both are معرفة التاجر الغني Sorry, this is not supposed to be there. التاجر الغني التاجر الغني التاجر الغني Yeah. So now let's bring some examples from the Quran. So everybody understand the concept though? Right? Last week you also mentioned that موصوف comes first. Yeah, موصوف comes first. So this is, yeah. So just to remind ourselves this is
[SPEAKER_00] the difference between an adjective in English and an adjective in Arabic. Right? So again, you translate this as what? The rich merchant. Right? But غني is second. غني means rich. Right? So the way you write a descriptive like the adjective and the noun in Arabic is the opposite to what you would say in English. Right? You would say the rich merchant even though the merchant is coming first and the rich is coming second. You get it? So now, again, it sounds kind of foreign but we'll just do a whole bunch of examples and inshallah the next class we'll also inshallah drill this in. For example, next one, right? حامد مدرس جديد Right? And the next two lines after that it says حامد مدرس جديد Right? So, how would you translate that? Yes. حامد is a new teacher. So you automatically bring when you're translating just bring the جديد the new to the beginning to before the noun that you're describing and it becomes new
[SPEAKER_00] teacher. Everybody understand that? Yes? Or no? Right? That's understood? So, Yeah. That's what I'm saying. So like, I mean, it's just important to note that in Arabic though you're saying it the other way around. You get it? The way it is. The word is switched. مدرس جديد The new is at the end. Yeah. حامد مدرس جديد Okay. Yeah. It's just obvious to us because that's how we speak, right? I'm just pointing it out so you note that difference. But otherwise, if I didn't point that out you'd probably just go on translating and you wouldn't even notice that there's a difference in the order. But, everybody understand that? Yeah. Alright? But حامد isn't the most suffix? No. حامد is the because look, حامد is let's test the rules. So, Uncle Ghulam asks that is حامد the most suffix here? Let's bring the sentence here. Let's put it under the microscope.
[SPEAKER_00] حامد مدرس جديد Okay. So, they all have تنوين تنوين Right? So, could it be because one thing to know that there can be multiple صفة there can be multiple adjectives all together. Right? So, is that the case over here? What do you guys think? Do all three of these correspond in all four of these? So, what's what doesn't it correspond in? Anybody? The last حركة? No, they all have they all have حامد حامد حامد So, how is it different indefinite and definite? Because it's not specific. What's not specific?
[SPEAKER_00] Indefinite is not specific. Definite is specific with the name of a person. Yeah. So, over here, what's indefinite and what's not definite? It's definite. Very good. Mashallah. Very good. Yeah. So, look, حامد even though it has a تنوين but remember we learned that if it's a name then it's still going to be معرفة still going to be definite. Right? So, that's where that's why we say حامد is a new teacher. Everybody understand that? Right? Sorry, what if what if it was حامد and عدد رسول جد Yeah. So, in that case that's a good question, right? In that case, there's two ways to interpret it. You could say but it might make it a little confusing to you but you could either say حامد is the new teacher. Right? That's a possibility but another possibility is that you're saying حامد comma the new teacher so it's like it is a صفة of those two but then you would have
[SPEAKER_00] to say another word to complete the sentence. حامد المدرس الجديد طويل Right? You get it? Then that would complete the sentence. And also you said حامد حامد No, no. It was an accent. حامد Yeah. Okay. Now, let's bring some other examples, right? ما هذا هذا تفاح التفاح فاكهة لذيذة Right? So, let's not get to new words, right? Let's go to Quran for a couple minutes and we can end the class, Inshallah. Hopefully we understood the general concept, right? So, anybody bring an example from the Quran of something like this? I'll bring a couple just to start off. Okay, go ahead. ويأتي بخلق جديد Good. Very good. Inshallah. إن يشاء يذهبكم Sorry. ويأتي بخلق جديد Let me just erase this. بخلق جديد So, خلق
[SPEAKER_00] خلق means creation, right? And جديد means? New. New, right? So, how would you translate this? ب You don't have to translate the ب part. Just pretend this doesn't exist, right? Let's just say this, right? How would you translate this? New creation. New creation. Right? So, you guys got it. So, look. It checks all the boxes. Gender, same. Number, same. Last حركة, same. They're both كسرة. Right? And they're both indefinite. Right? So, it checks all the boxes. Therefore, this is مصوف انصفة and you translate it as such. New creation. Very good. إذا رأتهم من مكان بعيد مكان بعيد That's another example from the Quran, right? Right? Yeah. What does مكان mean? مكان means place. In Urdu, it means like a house. But it's from the same meaning. مكان means it's a general it means a place. Right?
[SPEAKER_00] So, Allah ﷻ says من مكان باري So, مكان So, باري we don't mean far, right? So, how would you translate this? A far place. Everybody understand that? So, it checks all the boxes. Both ميل Both singular Both كسرة at the end and they're both indefinite. So, it's like وَضَغْلَبِ لَا إِلَهَ لَهُ عَالِيمٌ وَالْطَيْبِ وَالْأَمِدَاءَ Next one. المَلِكُ الْقُدُّسُ Very good. Yeah. So, those are all صفة Right? المَلِكُ الْقُدُّسُ السَّلَامُ المُؤْمِنِ الْمُحِيمِ الْعَزِيزِ الْجَبَّارُ وَالْمُتَكَبِّرُ I mean, I was going to go ahead. I mean, that's the name of Allah. It's different. But, yeah. So, all those. فَاكِهَةٍ كَثِيرًا This is in Surah Waqih, right? Yeah. Right? فَاكِهَةٍ means fruit. Okay? It's coming up in this lesson too. فَاكِهَةٍ
[SPEAKER_00] كَثِيرًا We know what كثير means, right? Yeah. Too much. Okay? So, how would you translate this? Yeah, many fruits. Right? Many fruits. So, again, many comes second. But, when you translate it, you bring it to the front. And, it checks all the boxes. Yes. Gender, they're both female. They're both singular. They're both كثرة at the end. And, they're both indefinite. Okay? Just to clarify. So, number meaning, like you explained before. So, for example, I don't know if I'm making this up. So, this is going to be فَاكِهَةٍ will be plural. فَاكِه Yeah. That comes in the Quran too. فَاكِهُ كَثِيرًا Yeah. I probably got you. So, سُطْرَنَوَا وَكَوَائِبًا Yeah, that's a good example. Very good, Masha'Allah. Amazing example. So, okay. Number. Good. Both number have to be. You don't get. I don't get. Which one? Good example.
[SPEAKER_00] Well, next time, Masha'Allah. Because, I think time, we're getting kind of.