[SPEAKER_00] So that's the last test we're having for this class, because it took like five hours of my time to grade it. It took way longer than I expected. No, I'm not okay with it. Yeah, I don't know why it took so long. Sorry for the delay. And yeah, we're going to have less tests, inshallah. But inshallah, let's try to pick up the pace for class now, inshallah. Test is behind us. Hopefully we got a good revision. We have everything solid, inshallah. Although we could have done a little bit better with the test, but inshallah, some brothers did pretty good. Everybody else, let's work on it, inshallah. Do you guys see the video I posted in the group, the WhatsApp group? So we don't want that to be you, right? So please learn Arabic, inshallah. Okay, let's start. So we're going to speed
[SPEAKER_00] up a little bit. Is that okay with you guys? Even if it's not okay, we're still going to do it. Because we have to move on now, because we're not making so much progress. Okay, so we finished al-dars al-sabir? Did we finish it? Okay, but that's not, I mean, okay, just homework, right? Well, we finished the lesson itself. Okay, all right. So, all right. So I said make sentences. What did I say? Do this part and then make sentences with these new words. Okay, good. All right. So let's do that tamreen together very quick. Okay. Very quickly, I'll go from this right side. Okay. Azishan, number one. You say tilka or dhalika. It's very simple. It's not rocket science. We're med school students, bro. Come on. Tilka. Good. Tilka umman. Okay. Saqeef? Okay. Okay. Dawood? Oh, wait, where is it? Oh. Okay.
[SPEAKER_00] Brother Salim? Tilka umman. Good. Brother Salim, number two? Tilka umman. Okay. Brother Zubay, sorry. Okay. Brother Mustafa. Number six. Come on. Let's get this quick, guys. Come on. Pay attention. Pay attention. I want to get this done. Come on. Come on. Come on. Come on. Come on. Come on. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Yeah. That's a trick question. Like all the trick questions I had in the test. I'm actually kind of proud of myself for not letting any of you guys get 100. There are some brothers that just were right on the brink. And well, I mean, many brothers got above 100, but nobody got it without extra credit. So. Okay. You go ahead.
[SPEAKER_00] Brother Haqq. Who's next? Oh, Brother Akasha. Okay. Mustafa. Okay. All right. Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm. Hamad. Come on. Quick, quick. Samir. Wait, where are we? No. Before that. Good. One minute. Good. Okay. Basil. Basil. No copy, Samir. Okay. Okay.
[SPEAKER_00] Abdul Samad. about a female. And Jim is male. chyba. Last one. Come on. You got this. Good.Michael. But what is. a bottle. Iloh. Duck, okay Alright, somebody Who made sentences? Somebody read one of your sentences for Al-Mumaridah Al-Mumaridah Al-Mumaridah from India? Good Al-Mumaridah from India Can you translate it please? Good, the female nurse is from India Okay Good Good Very good, mashallah Anybody else? Sentence, quick, quick, quick Come
[SPEAKER_00] on, come on, anybody Al-Batta Good, very good Very good, the duck is in the water Good Good The muezzin is in the masjid Good Good The muezzin of the masjid is old Are you trying to say he's like an old man or Old man, he's been here for a long time Old man No, if you want to say Somebody's an old man, you say Shaykhun Kabirun Shaykhun Kabirun Where does it come in the Quran? Hmm? Yeah Very good So, the sons of Yusuf Said to Yusuf They didn't know Yusuf They didn't know he was Yusuf But they thought he was the ruler So they said He has a father who is an old man So, Shaykhun
[SPEAKER_00] Kabirun Is how you say old man Qadim is usually used for objects Or You can use it for a person too But in this context It wouldn't mean that he's old It means that he's been here for a long time Okay Anybody else? No I'm going to try this I don't know if this is right But Jalison Al-Mujdun Fil Fil masjidi Good But the only thing is That Jalison is the predicate Meaning It's what you're telling about So The Mubtada Meaning the subject Would be The mu'addin So mu'addin should come first For example Ar-rajulu jalison Right? You say The man is sitting So Even when you're formulating a sentence You should formulate it like that So you would say Al-mu'addinu jalison fil masjid Okay Because I thought It would read like English Like No, no, no Yeah The Arabic You have to Make sure you keep the The flow of Arabic Yeah But if I put in Mosin first They would like Mosin is sitting In the It would be just like English I wanted to make it opposite No, no, no Yeah,
[SPEAKER_00] exactly That was good though Good Al-mu'addinu jalison fil masjid Okay Anyway with naqa A sentence with naqa Naqatu tajiru Fil shari'a Tajiru Tajiri Yeah Fil shari'a Very good Naqatu tajiri Fil shari'a Who wants to translate that? Somebody translate it? Naqatu tajiri Fil shari'a Camel of the merchant Is on the road Very good Mashallah Camel of the merchant Is on the road Very good Mashallah Very good Mashallah See He's being creative With the words that he knows But coming up with new sentences See that's what I want you guys to do I want you guys to be able to Do that At this point You should be able to Easily Make some sentences now And start speaking Arabic Okay But if you don't do it Then You're going to be saying Ameen to Sudeh's talking about Some random Like event Some convention that happened Okay What is that? He
[SPEAKER_00] said Al baydatu Tahtat dajajati Right And no He didn't He didn't make the mistake Of saying Tahtat deek A deek is a male rooster Right You don't have Eggs under a male rooster You have Eggs under a female rooster So he said Ad dajajati So very good sentence Mashallah Okay So next time Please I want everybody To make the sentences This is how you'll benefit This is how you'll learn If you don't make the sentences Then You know The brothers who make sentences Are going to be crying in Taraweeh And you're just going to be Like just standing there Waiting for Taraweeh to end So Okay Ad-Dursa Thamin Let's start it off We have some time Let's start Ad-Dursa Thamin Thamin means Eighth The eighth lesson Ad-Dursa Thamin The eighth lesson The numbers we'll learn later Inshallah I'm just letting you know Okay Who wants to read Loudly Okay good Tabeepun Very good Hatha ar-rajulu tajirun Wa thalika ar-rajulu tabeepun Okay Anybody
[SPEAKER_00] want to translate that? This man Good This man is a businessman And that man is a doctor Okay good Next Good Good Good except you said Wa ismu How should it be? Very good Wa ismu Good mashallah Ismu tajir mahmudun Wa ismu tabibi sa'idun Very good mashallah Somebody translate it Is it a The businessman's name is Mahmood And Mahmood Mahmood It's just Doctor What is the doctor's name? Doctor's The doctor's name is Saeed Good very good mashallah Good Who's going to read the next one? Khayyam can you read it? Uh yeah Okay this is I think it's kind of erased
[SPEAKER_00] In the book It's supposed to be like this Let me just write it down That That second word Which word? The third word is Littaajiri Right It's supposed to look like this It's supposed to look like this Huh? And the PDF is like that But in the book it's not Because the way it was printed It messed up Okay Yeah You want to read it? Number four Littaajiri Very good mashallah Hadhrat al-baytu littaajiri Wadhalika al-baytu littaajiri Okay Um Yeah Translate This house is for the merchant And that house is for the doctor Good But what's a better way to translate it Than is for
[SPEAKER_00] Belongs to Yeah Good I mean the meaning is fine But I mean Normally in English We don't really say it like that So just say it belongs to Good Okay mashallah Okay Uh Zeeshan read the next one Bayt al-tajri Imam al-masjidi Imam Amam Yeah Amam al-masjidi Bayt al-tabibi Khalf al- Madrasat Madrasat Okay There's two new words here That I'll explain before you I'll let you translate it Amama means in front of Okay Amama means in front of Okay Okay
[SPEAKER_00] I'll translate it for you Okay Yeah Okay Yeah Uh Yeah And khalf Means Behind It's the opposite Khalf definitely comes in the Quran Yeah Actually in the Quran Normally Instead of For the word In front It doesn't use the word Amama It usually uses It usually means To come in front of Or before Before something But Khalf It's used in the Quran Where does it come in the Quran? Huh? Like what's the ayah? It's
[SPEAKER_00] right But Yeah So good So that's in surah Yunus Right So it's talking about The That's good MashaAllah You got it You got that That's a good example So Allah is saying about The body of Fir'aun That Today We will save your body So that you can be A sign for those Khalfaka It doesn't literally mean Behind you It means those who are Stay behind Like Stay back after you Right So khalfa can be used In the physical context It can also be used In the Chronological context Meaning It could mean like Behind you In terms of time as well Like after you Basically But shouldn't be that In the future though? Meaning he's talking about Us like The future generation Right? Yeah Like we will Make the example of your body For the future generation So we still say Khalaf
[SPEAKER_00] Khalaf Yeah Over here Khalf It means in the context of like He's leaving the The world behind him You get it? It's as if he's Exited the world So he's leaving the world behind him In that way You get it? Okay Also Very good Mashallah Amam That's coming from the Quran Alright Surah Surah Qiyamah Right Yeah Good Alright So amama means in front of And Khalf means Behind Okay So these are two important words That we learned here Okay now Somebody Abdurraqib Can you translate the sentence That Zeeshan just read? Okay
[SPEAKER_00] Very good Mashallah Perfect Okay The merchant's house Is in front of the masjid And The doctor's house Is behind the school Perfect Good mashallah Yeah They also make The word In Qasr Sorry? Oh yeah yeah yeah I forgot to tell that Good Yeah So amama and khalfa They belong Part of the family of What do you guys guess? Something that's similar To what we learned already Zarf Very good Tahta These are all part of the Zarf family This one and this one Are both part of the Zarf family Right? Which Which indicates towards Either one of two things Which two things? Time and space Yeah Time or place Right? Zarf refers to A time or place Right? So both
[SPEAKER_00] of these Can be used in the context Of time or place So it will Almost always be Mansub Right? Meaning Marfu Or like Sorry Yeah We have a fatha on it And It'll be Mudaaf To the word That comes after it You got it? So it'll make the word Comes after it Kasra I think one of the questions On the test was that Right? Tahta Right? Tahta al-maktabi Or something right? So I didn't use it In the context of The Arab But tahta Huwa tahta al-maktabi Right? So It becomes fatha It's always fatha And the word after Is going I mean not always It depends on the context For example In the Quran it comes Min khalfihim Waj'anna min bayni aydeehim Said then We have put in front of them A barrier Wa min khalfihim And from behind them A barrier Right? But over there It's khalfihim Not khalfahum Why? Min Right? Wa min khalfihim
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah this is in which surah? Yasin Right? Surah Yasin The beginning of surah Yasin So But usually though Generally if there's no min Or anything else Then it'll be fatha Okay? Everybody understood? Okay Alright Read the next one Who's gonna read the next one? Basu? Lemon? No lime Liman Liman Liman Liman Liman Liman Liman Liman Liman Liman So this is Li The harful jar Plus man You get it? Liman Right? It came before too right? Liman hadha Or something? Yeah So liman So Um Who's gonna translate
[SPEAKER_00] it? We didn't say anything yet Okay go ahead Does that car belong to you? Good Very good To whom does this car belong to? belong to and to whom does that car right so we learned all these words already nothing new here maybe just a different for uh like a order but yeah to whom this car belonged to and to whom does that tilka is referring to that car right so imagine there's one car as close and one car as far so he's pointing to the close one lemon had his sayadaw well he's supporting to the far away car okay good mashallah um good okay
[SPEAKER_00] last one who's going to read it okay go ahead with the hawk america good request everyone please don't tell him whoever's reading please don't tell them the answer the whole point is that they should figure out themselves so that everybody can get a chance to read and fix their mistakes so please don't whisper the answer to anybody okay and who's going to translate it uh this car is from japan and that car is from america very good mashallah good
[SPEAKER_00] all right so we translated the lesson can we just go back to the house are we going to translate to whom this car belongs to yeah and to whom that car to whom does that car belong to yeah yeah to him that is like if you want to do a literal translation but what's implied is is that he's asking to whom does that car belong to but that's how we're going to write yeah can you say exactly the main america right yeah oh yeah so because um yeah and now you hit it it turns out so you didn't say um the story i'll just sit here for the rest of the conversation very good one and uh whatever no was important in this question but yeah that's what we're doing it has a role so basically me na al bahani that does get bursting but america is one of those words that does not getankora sorry
[SPEAKER_00] here that's basically new is we're seeing an ism al-ishara before we would see it like this we would see that's how we were seeing it before right but over here what's happening is it's showing up like this it's like this is the style that's being introduced over here
[SPEAKER_00] right here right so there's a difference between this and this right so remember in the beginning that one lesson where everybody looked very confused they didn't know what was going on I explained about a subject in a predicate right like hadha baitun that's like a subject in a predicate al rajulu tajirun right that's a subject in predicate that's a full complete sentence right so over here this and this together will be the subject and you would translate it as this house okay you're not saying this is a house you're saying this house and even in English when you say if I say hey this house then what would you say what would you be expecting something more right because this house is not a complete sentence you have to add another word to make it make sense this house is what about you the question would come what about this house right so then
[SPEAKER_00] you do it then you would say oh this house is big you get it so that's what it means here hadha baitun right kabirun right so you add the is right over here right so again so just basically wherever the this starts the tanween starts that's where you know where you add the is that's like the easy way to understand it right right so same same thing right the example so we got hadha rajulu tajirun I mean mashallah you guys translate like that even without even knowing this right but it's kind of natural right you're gonna just figure it out so hadha rajulu tajirun this man is a businessman right it's also definite here too yeah exactly it's definite for a reason but I don't want to go it's going to confuse everybody why it's definite but when you when you want to say had one of any one of these and then
[SPEAKER_00] um the thing that it's referring to but you want to say in this way like oh this person is blank then you have to add al right right and it comes very many places like this in the Quran right right when is this promise right so you're not saying this is a promise you're saying this promise right so that's not a complete sentence when you say it like that why that's the case that's something that you'll understand later inshallah there's no just enough for now can somebody get another example something like that in the Quran where one of these is used and then a word after is used with al very good that book or this book I mean depending on how we translate it but that book is the one in which there is no doubt right so uh any other examples any
[SPEAKER_00] other examples okay good very good right the Lord of this house right you get it you guys starting to understand now let them worship the Lord of this house you get it okay but there's no it's more ishara there though okay yeah we're looking for it's more ishara like hada with a word that has al two more two three more examples and we'll we'll end the class yeah we mentioned that already very good that's a boat of the year after we make it for blank right very good another
[SPEAKER_00] two more examples and we can we can go so the huffaz you gotta if you want to leave then just get on the huffaz case huh good let's not go to that it's going to confuse people because we didn't get there it's going to be confusing but good it is from the same category but I don't want to confuse anybody going to because a different type of word one more example then you guys can go come on come on push the huffaz huh huh very good Mashallah see the huffazi put you to shame man right well actually in it can actually it can work you can understand it in two different it you can understand it in two different ways so so it works good that
[SPEAKER_00] day is the truth is the truth that day is a truth that it's a little bit different than what we're used to because But over here It would be Kind of putting even more emphasis Like the truth Do you know what I'm saying? So the extra emphasis When you say But normally If you want to put it in the way What we normally Are making these sentences It would be like Right? But because The truth That's even more emphasis Like that is the truth You get it? Good example Mashallah Very good See brother Jibri You guys should You know Give him some daps He got you guys out of class I know some of you guys Were staring at the Looking at the watch So Yeah Brothers are looking at the watch So Alright Begin the class Oh I forgot to give homework Nah next time Next time Mashallah
[SPEAKER_00] Thanks for having me Oh no problem So I have another question So for this one Why are there two lumps Like right here? No that's this one This is That's right Oh okay That was here Oh You see how it's like erased? Yeah yeah yeah That's what I was drawing over there Oh okay