[SPEAKER_00] So, before we start our normal book through Kudoha, we finally got these books that we said we were going to get for practice on how to write, because one thing that became very clear after seeing my homework and the test papers, by the way, we couldn't get the test papers back, so I have a bunch of mine, you might as well try it. It became clear that most of us, if not all of us, need work on our handwriting. And it's not your right's fault, because most of us, even if we didn't learn how to read Pohan, we never learned how to write Arabic, so that's not something we can fault anybody about. That's why I thought it would be good to supplement whatever we're doing with some Arabic handwriting practice. So, I'm looking through the book. This could look quite comprehensive. A lot of work can be done on our own,
[SPEAKER_00] but it does merit some explanation in certain points. So, if you look at the beginning, just turn to page 6, for example. It just has the Alipa Tata, right? So, then you turn to page 8. Everybody have the books out? Oh, you forgot it at home? Okay, a lot of those have forgotten at home. So, if you look at page 8, it has at least blah, blah, blah, right? So, all you have to do is you trace this, the grey one right here. Trace, trace, trace, trace. Then you write your own over here like this. just try to make it look adamant as possible like that one, right? But in the beginning, it might seem like, oh, it's so much work, but honestly, the only way to improve your handwriting is to continuously repeat, repeat, repeat, repeat until you get the hang of it, until it becomes second nature. That's how we originally learned how to write English or Urdu or Bengali,
[SPEAKER_00] whatever our native language is. That's how we learned to write, right? In kindergarten, we may have forgotten it's been two years, but kindergarten, pre-K, first grade, the teacher to make us write, write, write, write, and have books like this as well, where you write A, you trace first, and you write over and over again. So unfortunately, we're basically in pre-K again, but for Arabic, right? So we have to write, write, but we don't have to do it in class, because that would be a waste of class time. So at least for these first few, inshallah, we can all do it on our own, right, in our own time. And then once we get it done, you can let me know, or no, by basically my next class, let's try to get the alphabet done. What do you guys think? which is up to page 18 okay pages 8 to 18 never do that yeah there's too much don't worry about it I mean you can do it next week as well but is that up here fine okay general so let's try to get that out of it down the just pay close attention to the
[SPEAKER_00] exact shapes everything in show that's what you'll get the hang it in trouble again try to follow the shape of the right if you're just gonna write it like you normally write it and already and what's the point of tracing and wasting space in this book right try to look exactly right and they make that exact way so and what we'll do is I guess after our classes I can sit in this check whoever wants to show me or everybody should actually show me what they wrote Michelle and we can move forward like that with control after After that, I'll explain and we'll come back after that when we get there, inshallah. Now back to Darussin Luba, our main course book. So in the previous lesson, we did a couple of important things. Sorry, we didn't finish this lesson. That was the Sadness, lesson number 6, page 33. So we're going to talk a little bit of a thing. Can anybody remind me of one thing?
[SPEAKER_00] Hadhi. Okay, hadhi. Can somebody remind me of what are the three things that hadhi indicates? Singular, close, and feminine. Singular, close, and feminine, right? So it's just like hadha, except a female version, right? So first one, there's singular, close, and feminine, okay? But yes, I got your message from Friday. so we know we were talking about using this lesson for um you know what's it called the house so some brothers actually went and uh they're practicing everything okay so is first to singular female and close okay what was another thing we learned in this lesson when you're describing something which is female then you add Tamar Bhuta or is it up here. Tamar Bhuta
[SPEAKER_00] can either be in this shape if it's connected to something, or it can be like this, it's like a circle with two dots on top if it's not connected to something. So Tamar Bhuta makes something feminine. So for example, you wouldn't say Hadihi Jameelun. You would say Hadihi Jameelatun. right I'm gonna say she is this is beautiful or she is beautiful right so same thing we ask a lot if that tune right we don't see what before we see what before do you just add this double book anything they're just trying to make it and shall we'll see more examples of that as you move along but just note that point that whenever you're striving to do it is feminine and you use that Another thing we learned is A1. What does A1 mean? Also. So you use this when you're trying to say like, you know, you said one statement and you're trying to add that, oh, this is also blank.
[SPEAKER_00] For example, you can say, I can say, I'm in Pakistan. And Salim can raise his hand and say, I'm also from Pakistan. And Ra'ud al-Aqeel can raise his hand and say, I'm in Bangladesh. And Ra'ud al-Haq can raise his hand and say, I'm a-1 in Bangladesh. We're going to hear the country. Yeah. So likewise, anyone else. Right? So brother can say, I'm in al-Wilayat al-Mutaheeda. What is Al-Wilayat in Mutahidah? United States, right? And now we're going to say, oh, and I think it's one Al-Wilayat in Mutahidah, right? So that's how you use A1 just means, also. Okay? What else did we learn last? Okay, that's pretty much what we learned last time. Okay. We just finished reading the lesson, so we're on the bottom of page 33. Maani. Who wants to read this time?
[SPEAKER_00] good we already learned the first thing we learn from the first lesson right so I have the same thing but for female so he's seeing this strange object he's never seen before and he's like what is this right and the person who says because Hathi and Miqwaqin welcome to the 20th century, 21st century, this is an iron. Miqwaqin is an iron, right? I know it doesn't look like an iron we have today. But, you know, that's how iron is for the Gen Z people, that's how iron used to look back in the day. So, Miqwaqin is an iron that you use to iron your clothes. Okay? Somebody give it a hand? I was just wondering, how did he know it's Hathi if he doesn't know what it is? That's a good question. Good point. Because normally, if somebody doesn't know what something is, then they won't assume that it's a female, right? They'll just say, ma hada,
[SPEAKER_00] right? But anyways, the person, I guess, is a teacher that's not saying a student, so he'll be just saying, ma hada. Okay. Hadi mi kwazum to sit in iron. Okay. Next. Next page. Niman. Niman hadi. Hadidi. What is Niman? This is something new coming here now. This is something important. Somebody ask a question? Yeah, I was about to say, you could use iron, like regular iron too? No, that's different. This is only the iron that you use. It's the tool that you use to iron it close. Otherwise, the other iron, the elements, iron is hadith. Man had only man Yeah, so we're getting there So Okay, so man we know, right? What does man mean? Who?
[SPEAKER_00] But what is this lamb doing here, right? And that same lamb comes out of nowhere in Khalid What does that mean? So this is a new member of the family Which family is it part of? Haqqul Jha, right? You look at Khalid Look at Khalid what does it have at the end? Qasr Qasr, right? Qalidin Qa-lidin Okay, so this lamb makes it Qasr So the name is Qalid, so don't think that's a word Qalid is not a word, right? Qalid is a name and this lamb was added at the beginning of Qalid to make it Okay, so So if you were to just say khalid, normally you would just say khalidun, but because this laam was added at the beginning, it becomes li khalidun, right? Now what does this laam mean? Depending on context, it can mean different things, as I said about the other letters as well. Sorry, let me just tell you, this is part of the huruf
[SPEAKER_00] al-jall family, okay? So how many huruf al-jall have we learned so far? Four. Okay, what are they? all right these are for make the next word customer a proper job makes the next word customer now we have another member of the family which is last okay so that is another and it makes the word now what does it mean what does it mean it means basically it indicates that something belongs to someone else for example this belongs to Khalid to whom
[SPEAKER_00] does this belong this is so if you want to try that literally you can say for, right? Lam transits, li transits to for, F-O-R, right? So like, but it's kind of weird to translate like that, like, oh, for whom is this? Like, who is this for? The easy way to translate it is, who is this? To whom does this belong to? Right? How do you spell li and her? Sorry? How do you spell li and her? Li? It's just one word, not one letter. It's just a lamb. It attaches to the beginning of whatever word it's going to make into . You get it? So it's slightly different than min, ilafi. The harful al-jaras that we learned so far, they're stand alone. Meaning, they don't connect to the words after them. Right? Everyone understood that? They're stand alone. But this So if this noun is only one letter, it just attaches
[SPEAKER_00] itself to the parasite, it just attaches itself to the word that comes after. I just said parasite to make us understand, but it needs something to attach itself to. So it attaches itself to the word that we make. So, لِمَنْ هَذَا? To whom does this belong to? Does it have to be in this format where it's a half hijab? Can it be like a law with a fatha? Yeah, good question, very good. So, generally speaking, when it's a half hijab, it'll have a kastra, li, right? It'll say ni. But in certain circumstances, it will have a fatha, right? that's rare, right? But that's for example, if it's with a dameer like this لَهُ Right? بُقَسَمْ لَهُ Right? Like coming many ayahs لَهُ مَا فِى السَّمَاوَاتِ وَمَا فِى الْأَوْلْ
[SPEAKER_00] لَهُ مُلْكُ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَضَيْرِ So, to him, who over here refers to him, meaning Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala. So in that case, you would become a dhamma. Why? Remember I mentioned that Arabs, they prioritize things flowing, right? So saying lihu, it doesn't flow, right? That's why the Arabs would just say it as laghu. That flows much easier, right? Otherwise, the general rule is that it must be a'lam of the kasra. That's the harf of the li, right? In rare circumstances like this, because of the reason I mentioned, so it could flow better, the Arabs would say what the fadhan taught, laghu. But generally speaking, it's going to be with the Qasra. But that second example is not a Haqqa. It is. It is? Yeah. But it doesn't make the Haqqa. Yeah, that's because, remember, there's certain things that don't change no matter what. So this is a Dhammeer. Inshallah, we'll get to that point once we reach there. But this won't change as well. Everybody at that? In the Quran, there's Laman
[SPEAKER_00] Attaqa and there's also Liman Attaqa. There are two different things. So is Islam, right? It means four, means four. And is for emphasis. So that's something equally different. Okay, everybody got that? So just summarize everything that we just said right now. is for what? When we say blank, what does that mean? For, or it belongs to blank. So now how many harful jars do we have? Five. Five harful jars, just keep that in mind, okay? So basically who's is this? This is Khalid, if you want some Khalid. Okay, can you hear me?
[SPEAKER_00] So, the Hamza over there, when we say, that's what type of Hamza? right that's the one that makes the sentence into a question right so he's asking a question that's that's indicated to where the other sentence when they have a question mark right the raja is a bicycle as you can see in that picture so that's a new vocabulary where we learned that Roger for the very go the water is a bicycle okay I don't want it and I see honey okay what is anna's it's all we have some of those big yes Okay, it's supposed to be fatha. Zadab. Adab Raa Jadu. Usually they'll assume you know it
[SPEAKER_00] because it has an alif after it. You get it? If it's an alif after it, generally it will be a fatha. Zadab. Okay. Adab Raa Jadu Anasin Hadi. So Brother Zaheib, since you raise your hand, you can tell us why is Anas Kasra? Anybody else want to give it a shout? Yeah, I think Darajatu is mudaf and this is mudaf. Very good, mashallah, alhamdulillah. So you're getting it, alhamdulillah. So Darajah is mudaf and Anasim is mudaf. So how would you translate it? Is this the cycle of Anas? Yes. Is this Anas' bicycle or the cycle of Anas? Good. Is this
[SPEAKER_00] Anas' bicycle? Good. All right. Can we add? Oh, how come? How did he doesn't come first? I was thinking something similar, wouldn't it be Yeah, both of them are okay. There's a slight difference but I don't want to confuse you guys with the difference, so let's just smack over there. Okay, do you want to keep it? is it is it what is it why
[SPEAKER_00] yes very good in trouble. Same thing, so darrajatu anasin, la, hadhi darrajatu amalim, right? It's kastra because mudhaf ilay, so the bicycle of amal, amal bicycle, okay, that's why it's kastra. So hadhi darrajatu amalim, okay? No, this is amalim. Yeah? yeah oh it's always going to be the mean unless there's some exceptions but if there's no and just think the default is that it's going to be the mean except number for female names we mentioned the exception amina too right female name specifically female named people you would just say that's an exception so you It doesn't have the meaning, right? Yeah, that's one of the reasons, yeah. But you're like saying that who doesn't have the
[SPEAKER_00] meaning, still only have one. Okay, continue. Okay, Jadidatan is a new word, right? Is it? No. Oh, it came before. Yeah. Okay, but there's a different form of this, it's slightly different. What does Jadid mean? New. New. So, Hadi Jadidatan, this is new. It's female. It's female, exactly. So the reason why he's in, he didn't say Jadidun, he said Hadhi Jadidatun, because the Raja is feminine. Why is it feminine? How do we know that the Raja is feminine? That is Talabhutah. That is Talabhutah, right? This is Talabhutah at the end of it. So that's how we know that it's feminine, right? Okay. Okay, sorry. Sorry, I can read? Yeah. Okay. Sorry.
[SPEAKER_00] Anasin, the name. Anasin. Good. Good. وَدَرَّجَةُنْ أَنَسٍ قَدِيمَتٌ أَنَسٍ is بُضَاف إِلَيْهِ دَرَّجَةَ is بُضَاف That's why he didn't say دَرَّجَةُنْ أَنَسٍ دَرَّجَةُنْ أَنَسٍ دَرَّجَةُنْ أَنَسٍ He said دَرَّجَةُنْ أَنَسٍ قَدِيمَتُنْ قَدِيمَتُنْ قَدِيمَتُنْ means old قَدِيمَتُنْ is a female version of that. You just add it down to that. That's why I mentioned the United States. The two kasras, is it because it's a name, you have to have two kasras? Normally, you have one kasra, right? I understand. No, you only have one kasra if there's an al, generally. Okay. Yeah. Otherwise, the default is that if there's no al, there's no al, Okay. then there's going to be an alim. Okay. Either or, but in certain circumstances
[SPEAKER_00] or exceptions, where it can be there. Like Mubab is going to take a few other examples of both. But generally, it's either going to be Al or Talmi. Yeah. And remember we learned the rule that it can never be both, right? The one million dollar rule, that it can never be Al and Talmi in the same word. Okay. Next. Next. Okay. Okay. Now, let's just read it first. Sa'a, it means what? Watch. Watch the clock. Right? So, can you try that, brother? This is Ali's watch. Good. It's
[SPEAKER_00] sometimes hard to notice the difference between one tesh or one dhamma and two dhammas in this book. The way they write the two is just very small, but you can see it's slightly different than the one where they write one. Just keep note that. So this is Jameelatun. And from ourselves, even if it wasn't there, we should know ourselves. This is Jameelatun, not Jameelatun because of what I just told you. If it doesn't have an, then it's going to have some wings, either or, right? Okay, here, you need a toni. Jidden. Jidden means very, right? So this always stays like that, Jidden, with the fatah, right? It means very. Jidden means very. So you add it to an adjective, right? So for example, this is very, very old, so you say قَدِيمٌ جِدًّا or قَدِيمَةٌ جِدًّا It's very old. If you were to just say قَدِيم, it just means old, but قَدِيمٌ
[SPEAKER_00] جِدًّا means very old, right? Similarly, if you were to say somebody is قَغْمِ, right? قَبِيحٌ is like قَغْمِ, but قَبِيحٌ جِدًّا is like very قَغْمِ So, the same way, means beautiful, and means very, very beautiful. So, we'll ask the next time, we can say . Add some emphasis. Oh, yeah, good point, yeah, good point. There's supposed to be a shutdown here, right? For some reason, they didn't put it, that was wrong with them, because, especially because they're introducing it the first time, they should make it clear to the student. So it's Jid-Den or the Shed-Den. With the way it's written, it's Jid-An and Jid-Den, two different words. Jid-An? Yeah, because I mean, it seems like that's what's written in the book. Because the two, the one being on the Adib. Okay, so that's how
[SPEAKER_00] it's written. In Arabic, it's not written, but the two demeanor is supposed to be on the Daan. Yeah, Jid-Den. Okay. Wait, in Arabic, it's written on the one? Yeah, it's supposed to be written with the one before the alif, but like sometimes in these new Arabic books they just write on the alif. You really don't need the alif then, you can just do it. Without the alif it's still a bit jitta, right? Yeah, but that's just the way it's written in Arabic, you write it with the alif. That's how it's written in Arabic. if you notice in the Quran if you notice every time there's a truth I mean what the fuck up I'm sorry to happen means yeah two of us then it will have that I leave yeah except yeah there's no exception like to the dollar or comes up then you know otherwise generally does have exactly okay so jizz that means very you just add it to add some
[SPEAKER_00] spikes in your sentence or some exaggeration. Okay, continue. It's very, very bold. Yeah, it's very beautiful. Basically you're saying can I have it? You're asking if you can have it a lot. Okay, continue. Yeah, but you have to say . Okay, so is a spoon, is a spoon, is a pot, these are new words. okay so now that that brings us to another point
[SPEAKER_00] important point to note that as we said generally female words or nouns they're it's indicated for its feminine nature by the thama right We'll know if it's female or not, whether it has a sta'a or not. But sometimes, in certain circumstances, this is rare, right, but it does happen, where a word is feminine, but it doesn't have a da'abhul ta'ati in it, right? And why is that the case? Because that's the way Da'arabs did it, right, so don't ask me. So Da'arabs, when they would talk about qid, a ta'at, they would just use it as a feminine object, right? because females are the ones who cook, right, yeah, exactly, because females are in the kitchen, they're cooking, so because of that, the pot is also female, right, it's possible, long, long, we don't know, what we're thinking. Naab is also one of these words, right? Yeah, very good, Naab is also one of these words, good point, right, so there's other words, for example, naab is
[SPEAKER_00] fire, right, so it doesn't have any Tawabudah at the end, but it is female, very good, mashallah, I was thinking a lot, mashallah, I'm sure you're probably reading the Quran and you're looking at which words are, why is this half, for example, why they say, had he, had he now, and let he put you in the head to get the move, right? Allah didn't say, had him now, Allah said, had he now, so now you think, wait, now doesn't have a time to put that in, so maybe Abdullah was getting ready to ask me in this class that I came across this ayah, and why does this have that, but now he answered his own question over here, by realizing that not every word that's female will have a time to put that Same thing with the Haadihi Jahannam Very good, perfect. Yeah, another example. In Sulaa Yasin Allah says Haadihi Jahannam Alatihi Kunfabtu'alama So Jahannam is also female We're not going to try to come up the reason why Jahannam is female or something like that
[SPEAKER_00] Does that mean that they're going to abide Is it an emphasis that they're going to abide forever? Eternity? Say it all the time? Is the ending? I forgot what you said. Is that emphasized like eternity, unending? No, it's saying this is the Jahannam, this is the hell fire that you were promised. Tu wa'adun wa'ad, you know wa'ad, you know like we're going to say wa'adah, wa'adah, right? It means promise. Tu wa'adun means that you were promised. So, this is the hellfire that you were promised, that you used to be promised. Okay, so, yeah, there are multiple other examples, but now we know that there's some words that are female, but they don't have it, that I'm a buba, at the end. How do we know? We should have to memorize it, right? Qizr is one of them, right? Shams is another one, right? Shams is
[SPEAKER_00] a son, right? it doesn't have a ta'am at the end, but it's female. Anybody an example in the Qur'an which tells us that the son is female? Perfect, yeah, wa shamsi, wa huha, ha, right? The ha is a female pronoun going back to the shams, that indicates that it's female. so shams is a female word even though it doesn't have at the end okay everybody understood this point right so there's some words that are female even though they don't have at the end of the world maybe you could what you can do is because there are not so many you have families right so you can also have this family of things that look like they're males but they're actually females right right But
[SPEAKER_00] basically the family that, yeah, the words that don't outwardly look like they're female, but they actually are female. Why does Shams have a Qasr? Why does Shams have a Qasr? In this ayah? Yeah, why does Shams have a Qasr? Because remember, the last class I told you guys that the wow sometimes can be for Qasr, for swearing, right? And it makes the next word Qasr, like Wallahi, right? so what shamsi Allah swearing by the sun okay so yeah so everybody can make their family at the end of their book you can call it every month I'm not going to tell you how to call it but basically the word is that they don't have it down in Bulta but they're still female right so one is Qidrum we just learned right now Naarum Jahannam Shams did it for example we just came across right now is talking and as we move on we'll come across more okay so how do you know how this is a spoon and this is a pot okay
[SPEAKER_00] there's a pop okay okay all right was Do you want to read the rest? Okay, you weren't here for a free passage, right? Very good. Yeah, this is Mudaaf. Mudaafi, that's why. Good. Okay, these are two new words. Baqarah, as you can probably guess by the picture, is a cow. It's also named the longest surah in the Qur'an, surah al-Bakha as well. Okay, so Baqarah is a cow. Al-Fallah is a farmer.
[SPEAKER_00] Fallah is a farmer. Why? What does that mean? Sorry? Farmer. Farmer, yes. Can I translate it? Okay, yeah, sure. This cow belongs to the farmers. Okay, you can have to like that or easier if this is the... Farmer's cow. Farmer's cow. Or the cow of the farmer. We're going to keep that of format. Excuse me. Okay? This is the cow of the farmer or the farmer's cow. In this case, the farmer is known just as the animal, right? Yeah. Exactly, yeah. Okay. Next, I'll just hold it. Okay. okay and one means knows okay and means knows
[SPEAKER_00] Yes, perfect, very good, mashallah. You're happy? No, just not myself. Wow, mashallah. Okay, so not happy about it, subhanAllah. Alright, this is in the ayah that talks about qisas, retributive justice, which is when, let's say for example, an eye for an eye, right? So in the same way Allah says, annafsa bil-nafs a life for a life wal-ayna bil-ayn and an eye for an eye wal-anfa bil-anfi and a nose for a nose so anfi comes in the Quran anf means nose thumb thumb means mouth thumb the word mouth comes in the Quran many times in a different form right and usually the
[SPEAKER_00] plural form a fly the plural is a fly so the funnel means mouth okay okay so this is a nose and this is a mouth so notice over here take note did he say Do you say hadhi or hadha? It's a hadha. So just note that these two words are male. Because we're going to learn some other body parts that are not female. Let's see what they are. Continue on this one. Hadhi Udun. Hadhi Udun. Udun is an ir. This comes many ways in the Quran. Right? In the plural form it also comes, I think, ones or twice in the singular form. Anybody remind me where it comes? Good, yeah. That's plural form, right?
[SPEAKER_00] They used to put their fingers in their ears. They would put their fingers in their ears. In their ears. They would put their fingers in their ears. And then the singular form? Very good, the same ayah. What I'm having entry knows for knows what was been wasn't right and here for a year, okay? And come to a more place The wish people and they will make fun of the prophets of life and they will say sorry They would say In India we are pulling up with them. They were common here. I mean this year that I have long how they come here From what I remember, I think Muhammad Fasniri mentioned that because he would listen to everyone and anyone, and he would always be listening. So they would just be like, oh you listen here, listening to people all the time, and they would kind of make fun of them. So Allah rebukes and recruits them
[SPEAKER_00] for that statement of theirs. Anyways, Pudun means here. وَهَذِهِ عَيْنًا Ayin comes multiple times in the Qur'an, but over there Ayin means a river or a spring. So Ayin can also mean a spring. But Ayin in terms of the eyes, it's... Okay, good, yeah. Same on Ayin. eye for an eye no it's good that's ayn that means they have wide eyes like in a beautiful way We
[SPEAKER_00] all know what the coolers are, right? Hopefully. So the A'in, not A'in, but it comes from the same root because it refers to having wide eyes in a beautiful way. So okay, these two are female. We'll mention why after this. So it's Adi-i-ulul as female and Adi-i-anum as female as well. Okay, next. Finish reading. Why are the yadun, why are the vijud? Yadun is hand, sorry. This comes in many places in the Quran. In the plural form, in the double, dual form, because people usually have two hands. And in the singular form. Any place, anybody remember? Don't make up, don't say, because it's not Alhamdulillah, so don't make things up. Yadullahi bapa
[SPEAKER_00] 'idin. Yadullahi bapa'idin. The Hand of Allah is above their hands. What's the dual form? Just to make it easier. Yadayn. It could be Yadayni or Yadayhi. Or Yadayha. Yadayha. Yadayha. Okay, so I mean there's many different places in the Quran where the word Yad comes. right so yeah means hand okay means leg okay just one leg one yeah yeah so feets the reason but rigid is the whole leg including feet Does Rijal also mean that or does it mean that? No, Rijal can mean either men or Rijal can also mean people who are walking on their legs. In the ayah says, Allah says, فَإِنْ خِفْتُمْ فَرِجَالًا اَوْ رُقْبَانًا So,
[SPEAKER_00] Rijal means you can pray Rijal while you're walking on your legs. It comes from the same root or Rij from the legs. Or Rukban or while you're riding. men who that's not the Japanese to try to mend start referring to things to the legs okay so where is it is on the Quran good yes the plural of regional is our truth right so the word our children comes in many places in the Qur'an. Legs. So what was it having? That's a good example. On the day, which we talk about the adjournment, in which their tongues, what a-d is a plural of, a-d is a plural of yad. Yad, we just learned his hands,
[SPEAKER_00] right? So on that day, their tongues, their hands, and their legs, will testify to what they used to do. So these body parts will be testifying in front of us. It won't matter if we are asked to do it. We can deny all we want. But Allah will cause our mouths to be sealed and will make our own hands and our own tongues and our own legs testify against us. And in a place in the Quran, Allah says that you didn't think when you were doing these sins is that your own body parts are going to testify against you, right? And as if you used to think that Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala la ya'alamu kathira mima ta'ala Allah does not know what you're doing, right? And Allah says, وَلَلَيْكُمْ ضَنُّكُمُ الَّذِي ضَنَنْتُمْ بِرَبِّكُمْ أَرْتَاكُمْ That thought that you had about your Lord means that you didn't have full yaqeen and faith that Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala can see everything, is what destroyed you,
[SPEAKER_00] right? You didn't have full yaqeen in Allah and you committed these sins thinking you're in private thinking nobody can see you yet your very own body parts will testify it's going to be so anyways so yeah digital right so these are by points now what is the very quickly to end up sorry to end off what is the rule that's being explained here right for an phone which is a nose and for some use have but for these body parts use having right So now, a general rule that we can learn for body parts specifically, just specifically your body parts, don't confuse for anything else. For parts of the body that have two counterparts, right? For example, you have qadamun, yeah, we didn't know that yet, but riddun is a leg, right? Yadun is a hand. Aynun is an eye. Udun is an ear, right? Every body part that has two, right? have two ears two eyes two legs
[SPEAKER_00] that will be female you get it yes everybody part that has two counterparts that will be female fingers fingers i think it's also female yeah so uh yeah we'll get to that that's female I mean that's the finger oh it came sorry it didn't come al-isbah came on page 20 al-isbah means finger that's my good memory alright okay so those body parts that have two counterparts words that those body parts will be female otherwise gender general rule is that if it doesn't have a thama ghulta then we'll assume that it's men okay there we got that so far we learned that the
[SPEAKER_00] main thing that are about genders is that the general rule is that it's female they'll have a thama ghulta if you want to describe something that's female then you would add a thama ghulta at the end of the word that's describing it right for example if I'm to a female but you know I think Jimmy that didn't right and TJ mean I turn if you're talking to a male I would say to me and then then after that we would be talking about a an object that is generally sorry I think it doesn't have a ton of some of them they're female right was rare because I'm a hundred female that you just have to know there's no way there's no rule that we can utilize to say that this is a female word it's just you just have to know you have to be told these are words if you want to learn the technical term for it you don't have to learn it but for those who want to know it's called some
[SPEAKER_00] are you right there's certain things in Arabic which are Sama'iyun, which means that they're based on, Sama' means to listen, right? Sama' means your hearing or your ability to hear, right? Come to me this in Quran as well, right? So Sama'iyun means based on hearing, right? What does that mean? So certain things in Arabic, there's no way, there's no rule, like certain things, many things in Arabic, you can just learn through the rule, right? You just, you just know the rule, so automatically you can apply it to any circumstance. Like I said, this is Sama'abutah, right? So the general rule is if there's something which is female, you'll add up to Amruta at the end, and that makes it female. But then sometimes there's things that go against that. Why? Because you learned from the Arabs, you heard it from the Arabs, that's what they used to do with. So those exceptions, there's no way to know it, you just have to hear it, meaning you have to learn about it through a book or something. So, words that end in Hamzah, they also tend to be female, right? Like
[SPEAKER_00] Samah, Nisa... That's a good, yeah. So that's a more... There's a lot more exceptions to that rule, but that is a good point, yeah. There are many examples that have a Hamzah at the end. A very good observation. So, Hamzah, also even the Arif Maqsura, right? Arif Maqsura means the one that looks like this, right? so things that have that a lot of time you know not always oh I could there's a lot going on so you're gonna do it yes actually I think you're right please we decided that next week is reviewing great could somebody post the dates for the data you can just close out what's that group the date of the test and everything inshallah do you end here inshallah so this do the homework number one read and write. Just write it and translate it. Okay, something number one, write it and translate it. Something number two as well, the next one, ma hadha
[SPEAKER_00] or ma hadhi. You just have to answer the question ma hadha or ma hadhi for all these pictures. Okay? If it's male, you say hadha, and if it's female, you say hadhi. Okay? You don't have to identify the picture. I mean, you don't have to write about the picture, just say hadha or the same one. You should write answer the question based on the picture. How's that kind of what it's like? Exactly. There's a halafalon, halilin aafatun, halalit, talalit, talalit, talalit, talalit, talalit. There's a few words that we don't know in number one and two. Like what? Like refrigerator. It's on one. Oh, okay. It's on number six. Or thalathaja, dajaja. Okay. Thalajatun is a fridge. and that is a window the jacket we learn that right we didn't know that oh yeah we're gonna eat vegan rooster the jacket is a female of the chicken you know
[SPEAKER_00] everything in the down is meat is me Okay, so if you go to an Arab restaurant, where is the meat, right? Is that male or female? Sorry? Is Lachim male or female? Male. Sorry? Lachim? Yeah, well that can be played if you manage to move in. Okay, so these two are your homework. If you can't finish both, it's okay. The other book is more flexible, the right book is more flexible on your time, so you can just do it by next Monday.