[SPEAKER_00] As-salāmu ʿalaykum wa-rahmatullāhi wa-barakātuhu. What's up? Inna l-ḥamdu li-llāhi n-aḥmaduhu wa-na-saʿīnuhu wa-na-staghfiruhu wa-nu'minu bihima na-tawakkanu ʿalaykum wa-na-ʿaʿudhu bi-llāhi min-shūrūri an-fūsīna wa-min-tayyī'āti ʿaʿmānina man-yahdī allāhu fa-lā mu-dhillā lahum man-yuddilhu fa-lā hādīyā lah wa-na-shahidu an-lā ilāha illa-llāh wa-na-shahidu an-na-muhammadu rasūli-llāhi wa-ma-baʿāt. How many of us did the homework? Okay, I'm not going to check it. I mean, if you want, bring it after class. Inshallah, I can check the writing and stuff. But let's get some answers. So one is a previous lesson I had asked you guys to make sentences. Some of you guys didn't make it. So does anyone... Did anybody make up that homework and want to mention some sentences? Remember the previous lesson I had told you guys to make sentences.
[SPEAKER_00] So only some of you guys did it. So did some of you try to make that up? And do you want to share your sentence? I think that's probably one of the most important things for you to solidify this concept of mullah. It's fine. Okay. Besides that, what were the other lessons? What was the other homework that we mentioned to do? Okay, number two, yeah. We did that in class, but I asked you guys to write it down. So that's fine. We don't have to do it again. Number three is just to check if you understand the concept of how you pronounce the end of the mulaaf and the mulaaf ilayh. So the main thing to keep in mind is that the mulaaf will not have alif-laam or tanween. And the mulaaf ilayh will always be kassara, generally, unless there's an exception. Oh, we're not worrying about the exceptions right now. Okay. So let's just quickly read
[SPEAKER_00] that very fast. Abdul Wahab, number three. No, no. Yeah. Yeah, just read the... You don't have to read the instruction, just the actual... Yeah, but it's not mudarrasati, it's... So it's the door of what? What does it mean? School, right? So how do you say school? Yeah, good. So read it again. Good, mashallah. Alright, brother Khayyam, next one. Rajali. Rajuli. Good, mashallah. Alhamdulillah. Zeeshan? Good, hamidin. Good.
[SPEAKER_00] You say hamidin because if there's no al, then it's going to have a tanween. Good, mashallah. Brother Atif, next one. Yeah, the next one, he did the... Yeah, mudiri. Very good, mashallah. Sayaratul mudiri, which means... You know what I'm saying? Sayara, sayara, we didn't go over that actually, but sayara means car, yeah. Principle. Yeah. Yeah, the principle's car or the car of the principle, okay. Yeah. Are all the mubaf in these sentences definite or indefinite? So basically... The mubaf and mubaf ilay are considered like one unit, right? Together, it's considered like one. That's why I was calling it a construction. Mubaf and mubaf ilay together is considered as one unit. So that means that if the mubaf ilay,
[SPEAKER_00] the second word, is going to be definite, then the mubaf will also be considered definite. If it's indefinite, then it's also going to be indefinite. Everybody understood that? The brother asked a very good question, and Abdullah Hab had asked a similar question previously. So when you're saying, for example, بَيْتُ حَامِدٍ سَيَّارَةُ الْمُدِيرِ So the second one is obvious, like the mubaf ilay is obvious. حَامِد is something which is definite, meaning... Remember we learned معرفة النكرة, that which is definite, that which is indefinite, right? So حَامِد is a specific person, so we know that it's definite, right? المُدِير, because it has ال, we know it's definite. But what about the مُضَاف? When we say سَيَّارَةُ, we don't know if it's definite or indefinite because it doesn't have ال or تنوين. So how are we supposed to know if it's definite or indefinite? Do you understand the question? You get the question? So the answer is that it's based on the مُضَافِ الْي. They're both considered like one unit, right, in a sense. So it's
[SPEAKER_00] based on the مُضَافِ الْي, the second word, right? So if that second word is definite, then the first one will also be definite, right? And if that word is indefinite, then the second word is indefinite and the first will also be indefinite. مُضَافِ الْي. So for example, if he said, سَيَّارَةُ مُدِيرٍ It would mean a car of a principal. You get it? Or yeah, if it was بَيْتُ رَجُلٍ Then it would be a house of a person. You get it? So it depends on the مُضَافِ الْي. So that's all you have to pretty much know for that. You got it? So we put مُضَافِ الْي or مُضَافِ الْي. Sorry? We make it مُضَافِ الْي or مُضَافِ الْي. For which one? The one you're talking about. The car. The principal's car. Yeah. سَيَّارَةُ الْمُدِيرِ كَسْرًا Because it's مُضَافِ الْي always will have كَسْرًا generally.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah. Okay. Is everybody still confused about this concept of مُضَافِ الْي? They feel like... Okay, what's the confusion? Same thing. We were just talking about that. We want to put كَسْرًا and we want to put تَجْمِين. So when we talk about... We mentioned that we were talking about definite and indefinite. So generally, if something has تَجْمِين, then it is something which is indefinite, right? The only exception is if it's a proper noun, meaning if it's a name of somebody, right? حَامِدٌ It has تَجْمِين on it, but حَامِد is a specific person, right? So that's definite. You get it? Other than that, generally, if something has أَلْ أَلْ then it will be considered definite, right? But a name doesn't need أَلْ You already know it's definite because it's a proper noun. You get it? A name of a person.
[SPEAKER_00] حَامِدٌ Because it's a specific person, so that's definite. So a name can have تَجْمِين on it, but it will still be definite. Other than that, generally, if something that has تَجْمِين on it, generally, it will be indefinite. You get it? So a name is an exception to the rule. So that means it will always have, like I said, بَيْتُ حَامِدٍ It can't be حَامِدٍ or... No. Yeah, it will be حَامِدٍ. Yeah. Okay. So same thing for... I'm sorry, for the next one. مِنْدُلُ أَمَّارٍ Yeah, exactly. Same thing. So you already answered it, Mashallah. Good. And you can translate it too while you're at it. The handkerchief of Ammar. Okay. Any of the young brothers can tell me what a handkerchief is? Okay. Alright. I have a question. How would we string together مَوْتُحُ مُضَافِلَيْهِ What
[SPEAKER_00] if I want to say the key of the car of the man? Would it be مِفْتَحُ سَيَّامَتِي الْأَجْلِي؟ Yeah. Good, Mashallah. So like we... Last lesson we did مَا رِكِي يَوْمِ الدِّينِ That's a similar example to what you're saying, right? It's like a double مُضَافِلَيْهِ مَالِكِي is a مُضَاف Then يَوْم is مُضَافِلَيْهِ Then يَوْم is also the مُضَاف of الدِّين And الدِّين is مُضَافِلَيْهِ Don't get too confused, right? But that's just to answer your question. If you want to say like a double مُضَافِلَيْهِ Like the key of the car of the man, right? So you would say مِفْتَحُ سَيَّامَتِي الْأَجْلِ So good. Yeah, that's how you do it, basically. So why isn't it عَمَارِي رُوم Say it again. Why isn't it A and you know And then Which you're
[SPEAKER_00] talking about مِن دِيلُ Yeah. Why isn't it رُوم Because the rule Were you here for the lesson? Yeah, I haven't skipped but I might just be burnt out. Okay, so مُضَافِلَيْهِ Remember we learned the rules for this composition of two words together that usually indicates possession but as we learned last time sometimes it doesn't indicate possession but usually it means the blank of blank, right? The blank of blank, right? So in that case the second word which is مُضَافِلَيْهِ will always have a كَسْرًا generally. Yeah. Now, I had put رُوم He said رَم You know, I'm Or did I get it right? He said عَمَارِيْن with the كَسْرًا with the كَسْرًا Oh. Oh. Oh, so Okay, let's do it. So let's go to the bottom. Yeah. مِنْدِيدُ عَمَارِيْن Yeah. مِنْدِيدُ
[SPEAKER_00] عَمَارِيْن You got it? Okay. But, so So why is it مُحَمِدُون here مُحَمِدُون and another That's really my real question. I'm like when do I don't use double time double time on the on the on the So you're asking why is it عَمَّارِيْن and not عَمَّارِيْن Because this is مُضَاف and مُضَاف إِلَيْهِ Right? The handkerchief of عَمَّارِيْن Right? So in Arabic the way you denote that there's no of in Arabic the way you denote that one thing possesses the other or blank of blank is that the first word you make sure it doesn't have تَنْوِين or and the second word it has a كَسْرًا is a كِتَابُ الله Right? كِتَابُ الله كِتَابُ الله كَتَابُ الله كِتَابُ الله Exactly Yeah Yeah Okay Alright next
[SPEAKER_00] one brother حافظ حافظ أُكَشَى إِسْمُ إِسْمُ أَعْلِبِ Yeah Good The name of the student Good Mashallah The name of the student Very good Mashallah Yeah, good Good, mashallah, the house of Allah Allah's house, baytullahi We've heard that word before, right? Baytullah, right? Baytullahi So, the house of Allah Okay Let's see, brother Yes, brother, it's on Good Why is it Okay, good It's because of So, because you have The next word becomes So, don't forget now, right? Again, now is where multiple
[SPEAKER_00] rules Are being applied at once So, don't get confused, right? Make sure we have everything solidified So, always remember Which are the That we learned so far? We have four so far Ala, okay Ila Ala, okay Fi, one more Min, good, mashallah We have four harf al-jar And what do these harf al-jar do? Yeah, makes the next word kassara Good, okay So, over here Fi kitabillahi Right, and the good thing, mashallah He read, he didn't say kitabillahi Right, because again The mudhaf does not have Tanween or al Right, the mudhaf cannot get al or tanween And kitabillahi Right, why is it kitabillahi? Because the mudhaf ilayh is kassara Now, just to note that For the name Allah, right? You're never going to have tanween on it Because, I
[SPEAKER_00] mean, there's a difference of opinion But generally, the ulema say Allah is actually Al-ilah Ilah Ilahun means God, right? So, al-ilah Al-ilah, right? The God, like, He's the only actual God The God is Allah, right? So, al-ilah is used Due to some changes that happened In the word It became Allah That's one opinion, there's some opinions that say No, it's not from there, but this is the easiest way to understand it So, this is This turned into Allah Right? So, that's why, because it has al It won't have tanween Remember how we mentioned the one million dollar rule? What was the one million? The one million dollar challenge? Tanween can never work with al Good, tanween can never work with al, right? Some brothers really want that million dollars So, they remember that rule, right? There's no way for it You didn't find me the example, so Yeah, so because al can never come with tanween, right? So, Allah It has al in the beginning, technically
[SPEAKER_00] speaking Even if it's not so clear So, that's why you don't say Allahin Or Allahun Or Allahan Okay? You say Allahi Kitab Allahi Fi kitabillahi Okay? Got it? Okay Where is this exact phrase Fi kitabillahi Come in the Qur'an Wa ulu al arhami Wa ulu al arhami Ba'ad al arhami Ba'aduhum Come on, father, I'm literally giving you the answer Wa ulu al arhami Ba'aduhum Ba'aduhum Ba'aduhum Ba'aduhum Bi ba'din fi kitabillahi Which surah is that in? Huh?
[SPEAKER_00] Surah? Yeah, wait Right before Isn't it? No, this is in surah not anfar This is in surah Ahzab First page, I think Okay Okay, fi kitabillahi Okay, next Um Badr Ali Very good, mashallah So, note that he said Min baytil Because of what? Why is it kasra? Harf al-jar And why did he say Al-mudarrisi Why? Because mudaf ilay So, they're both kasra But for two different reasons, right? So, we just have to remember that Now, why did he say madrasi? Why did he say al-mudarrisi?
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, madrasa is a school And that should have a ta'mar buta at the end Because, you know Even though it doesn't have the haraka See, look We're already starting to read Without fatra kasra dhamma Remember I mentioned that Slowly, slowly The author is going to wean us off This fatra kasra dhamma He didn't even have it And Badr Ali got it, right? All of us who read these previous examples It's because we're learning the word And now we're going to learn What the haraka is at the end You get it? Okay So, now we're starting to see The beauty of this book How he slowly pulls it out Without even us noticing And before we know it We're even reading Without fatra kasra or dhamma Right? If I were to tell you In the beginning of this class October 7 when we started If I was to tell you Then you would just be like What is this? من بيت المدرس Right? You would say something like that But you're already reading it Right? Yeah, that's what he said Yeah, he said من بيت المدرس Yeah Okay Next Last one Who wants
[SPEAKER_00] to go? Brother Saqib, right? Very good, mashallah Translate Somebody remind the brother What is maktab? Table or desk Okay, good So, ala means? On So, turn that the whole sentence Good On the principal's table Good, mashallah Alright Now we're going to read The next 20 sentences Let's get it going We want to finish these Well, actually Before we do that Let's just finish the lesson Because we got caught up with مضاف مضاف في ليه And I just wanted to Have a concept to be drilled in Does everybody feel like They understand And are more comfortable With the concept now? Yeah Yeah? It's important That's why I spent a lot of time I said we don't need to rush But this is a very Very important concept Has anybody been Reading the Quran And noticing A lot of مضاف مضاف في ليه Good, mashallah Very good That's what we have to do Right? If we're not
[SPEAKER_00] Implementing these rules We're going to forget it Right? Even حرف الجر Just last week We were like I'll never make The word after حرف الجر Anything بركسرة But then this week You learn one new rule And you already forgot that Right? But the only way Not to forget it Is to keep on Practicing And also noticing Right? Focus when you're reading First you have to read the Quran If you're not reading the Quran That's a big problem Right? Then what's the point Of learning Arabic If you're not even Going to read the Quran So we should all be Reading the Quran On a regular Daily basis We should have a set routine Of reciting At least a little bit Right? Then while reading Quran Of course The main benefit Of us reading Quran Is for spiritual benefit For getting closer to Allah And also trying to learn The meaning as well So And part of learning the meaning Is to notice these things That we're learning In Arabic class And to implement it And apply it Yeah it might Make your Quran reading longer But it doesn't matter Right? It's about the benefit Sometimes If you can't read too much But you'd rather Focus on these things Then it's more beneficial Like For example Me sometimes I'll be reading And I'll be like You know
[SPEAKER_00] I want to know more About this ayah So I'll open up a tafsir That'll make my whole Quran reading session longer But it's worth it Right? Because you're Getting a deeper Understanding of the Quran Right? So in the same way Let us all Start reading I want to I only Whenever I ask Who notices When they're reading the Quran I only see like Two or three hands Right? Every single one of us Should be reading Quran And then when we read the Quran We should be Implementing all these rules We should see Mudaf mudafilay Comes on every single I could probably guarantee I don't want to Do a million dollar bet For this one But I can almost guarantee That every single page Of the Quran Has at least one example Of mudaf mudafilay And one example Of harf rujara At least Right? I could I don't want to do A million dollars But Yeah So I mean So we should We shouldn't have any excuses We should all Notice these things The people who are Implementing and noticing These things You'll see They'll go way further ahead In their understanding of Arabic They'll get it Everything will click But if you're not Implementing it It's gonna The rules are gonna Escape
[SPEAKER_00] your mind Okay So we never finished The original lesson Because we were just Focusing on this concept Of mudaf mudafilay We did read it But let's just Go through It very quickly again Okay So brother Tawheed Can you read? Loudly please Good Mashallah Can you translate that? Well we're back on The Darsul Khamis Page 27 Page 27 We're re-reading the lesson Because we stopped In the middle Right? We didn't Yeah So he's starting But he's reading From the beginning Okay Good mashallah Is this Muhammad's book So let's just Take a pause And how did he get That translation Because the The structure Of the sentence Is a little confusing Right? Because If you translate Literally in English It would be like
[SPEAKER_00] Is Book of Muhammad This Oyasir Right? So We have to think of I find it That if you want to Keep the word by word order You could say Is Muhammad's book This one Oyasir Yeah But that still doesn't Really make sense in English Right? So Is So you have to Basically Have that in English When you translate It would come before Right? Is this Muhammad's book You get it? So A kitabu Muhammad Kitabu Muhammadin This little Phrase we know That Kitabu Muhammad Book of Muhammad Right? It should be like Clockwork in our mind As soon as you see it You see something of this This Pattern Kitabu Muhammadin Sayyaratu Al-Mudiri Automatically it should come Blank of Blank That should just Pop up in our mind immediately So kitabu Muhammadin Book of Muhammad Okay Then A What does A do? What is A called? What is it called? Yeah It's a question What is it called?
[SPEAKER_00] Hamzahsifham It's part of the Nosy family Right? So It turns that This sentence into a question Right? Hatha This So is this Muhammad's book Ya Yasiru So this is something We have to learn right now Ya Yasiru Okay? So again Just to Just to make it clear For the brothers that know Urdu Ya means Or Right? But that is not What it means in Arabic Right? So let's make it very clear Ya does not mean Or In Arabic So we We did go through Over the translation We mentioned that Usually people Translate it like Oh Oh Oh Yeah Sir Right? Why some people say Ya means my No No So ya The ya that means my Is the one that comes At the end of a word For example Let's say Rabbi
[SPEAKER_00] This ya Right? Rabbi means my lord Kitabi Means my book Sayarati Means my book My car Baiti Means my house You get it? Ustadi My teacher Get it? So that's When they say ya Refers to mine It's talking about the ya That comes at the end Not Ya With the With the alif On it Okay? So let's not get that confused I mean just by the way What we'll learn later But this is A form of Mudaaf Mudaaf Right? But Don't get confused Okay So ya Yasiru Right? So normally It's translated in English Like this Oh Yasir Right? One time In Ramadan They would ask to make dua Before Before breaking the fast Here in the masjid So I would make dua When I would be making dua In English I would say Oh Allah Such and such Oh Allah Oh Allah So my uncle told me Don't say oh Don't say oh oh Because in In Punjabi Oh is
[SPEAKER_00] like A disrespect Like oh You know it's like It's not respectful So don't say oh It's like okay Alright So that's why I don't really translate A ya with oh Anymore But you can translate it like that But as I mentioned last time That in English Normally we don't really talk like that So you can just change it to like For example You're addressing somebody Right? You're saying What was the sentence That we were doing? A kitabu Muhammadin hadha ya yasir Right? You would say Like this If you want to translate it The way we speak normally You would say Yasir Is this Muhammad's book So basically Instead of saying Oh yasir You just say Yasir Kama That's normally how we speak Right? Again When you translate Arabic You don't have to translate it In an archaic And old fashioned way Right? Sometimes people think Like they'll be speaking normally And all of a sudden They're translating Arabic They'll
[SPEAKER_00] become like You know from the 18th century Or something like that So you don't have It doesn't have to be like that Right? We can translate it in a way That people can understand Today's times Okay So I'm going to be real with you So I'm going to use Ya as yo That's really But that doesn't really work When you're saying Ya Allah Right? So I mean But generally We can say Yeah If you're talking to a person Yeah that's fine Yeah So when you're making dua Don't say Yeah So So yeah So anyway Just to make it easy If you want to pick a word for it You can say Oh Oh yaasir But it just means That you're addressing It's for khitab Khitab in Arabic In English that means Addressing somebody Right? Ya is for khitab Ya yaasir Right? Or nida Right? The word for The technical term for it In Nahu Is nida Right? Harfu nida So we can add this Yeah
[SPEAKER_00] this is another family Let's add this to We have another family here Right? The family is Oh don't worry We're just getting started With the families This is going to be A lot of families Ahrufu nida'i Nida'i means To call somebody Right? When you're calling to somebody It's called nida'i So these This is the family That Is always on the phone They're always talking to people They're always calling people Talkative family Maybe you could call them Okay? So there's many of Many ahrufu nida'i There's aya Haya And things like that But they don't really come so often To Quran The main one is ya Right? So anyways Ya is harfu nida'i First you said khitab Does that have anything to do with khutbah? Yeah it's from the same root Yeah Okay so
[SPEAKER_00] ahrufu nida'i Alright So The special thing in terms of grammar When we talk about Harfu nida'i Is that The name that we mention Or even the The noun that we mention After ya It becomes It doesn't have It won't have a tanween on it Generally Okay? It will not have a tanween It will just have A dhamma Right? Ya ya siru Right? Ya Ya rajulu Right? Oh man Right? You're calling a person Ya rajulu Ya ustaz Right? Oh teacher Right? So you would say Ya ustadhu Right? Ya hamidu So normally Hamid Even the word hamid Right? If you're just saying it You would say hamidun But because of ya You don't say Hamidun Anymore You would say Ya hamidu Everybody got that? So that's a special rule That's specific to ya
[SPEAKER_00] Everybody got that? So that's why If you look at it They made it very clear Remember They're not mentioning All the harakas now But for this word They made it a point To put the One dhamma Right? Ya sir Generally if you were to put it Without ya It would say Ya sirun Okay? But because There's a ya That comes there It makes it One dhamma Ya siru Everybody got it? So Huh? Generally Yeah Yeah Yeah So now let's test you guys See if you guys are picking up Each other's names Right? So Brother Samir How would you say The brother next to you's name And you're talking to him? I said his name earlier In the lesson too So You got that wrong So you said Neyberun Neyberu Muminu
[SPEAKER_00] The main thing That we want to test is I'm asking about Yes But say Say it How I said it Good Mashallah Let's see Brother Atif How do you say the name Of the brother next to you? Well That's harder actually I'm not going to get into it His name is a little difficult Abdul Raqeeb Because it's His name isn't Mudaaf Mudaaf Ilai Abdul Raqeebi Right? So that's But that makes it confusing What's this brother's name? Salam Salam Salam Salam Salam Yeah Yeah Good Mashallah You guys know each other But at least Ignore my eye contact How do you say this brother's name? Close enough
[SPEAKER_00] Good Zubair Good mashallah Can we change the names today? Okay Let's see who else we got Okay that's enough But we get the concept right? Oh yeah perfect Perfect Alright Brother Zaheib I can't hear you His name is Salha Salha Okay So I'm saying Yaat Talbo No no So Talha has a Ta marboota at the end Talha Like this You say Yaat Talha Too But this is a rare exception Remember I mentioned that generally if a name has this Ta marboota at the end It's a female But I said there's a few exceptions One exception is Talha So don't worry Don't think you have a female name You're good You're fine Right? So
[SPEAKER_00] Talha is an exception Hudhaifa is an exception Right? A few other exceptions But generally if this Ta marboota is a female name It's a female name So that's why you don't say Talha You would say Talha too Okay So in Allah's name When you say Ya Hayyu For some of them Yaadul Jalali Walikram You say Yaadal Jalali Walikram Yaadal Jalali Walikram Yeah So I mean not to confuse you guys But when you say Ya This is the general rule right? The word after it will be Dhamma And one Dhamma Right? But then When that word is Mudaaf Mudaaf Ilai Or like I was saying Abdul Raqeef's name Right? When that When the word You're calling to Is Mudaaf Ilai Then the first The Mudaaf has to be Fatha So you would say Ya Abdal Raqeef That's why if you hear Arabs They're talking to a person named Abdullah They're saying Abdullah Abdullah Right? Because it's like they're saying Ya Abdal Lahi Ya Abdal Lahi You don't have to learn this rule We're supposed to learn this rule way later Since the brother asked Ya Yaadal Jalali
[SPEAKER_00] Walikram So that's Mudaaf Ilai So that's why you say Yaadal Jalali Walikram Otherwise generally For Allah's names You say Ya Rahmanu Ya Rahimu Ya Malik Ya Ya Ya Malik Ya Quddusu Right? So whatever name of Allah we say Generally we say But then There's one slight exception We say Ya Rabbi Why do we say Ya Rabbi? We know that When it comes to Quran Normally it says Ya Rabbi Why is that the case? Because You're saying My Lord Yeah Very good So basically Remember we mentioned that I forgot We wrote it somewhere here Um Yeah The Ya at the end right So Basically you're saying Rabbi Right My Lord So that's why you're saying that But otherwise If you were to just say Oh Lord You would say Ya Rabbu You get it? Okay So generally Whenever you say Ya Then the word after will be Dhamma Yeah Yeah exactly So Ismi
[SPEAKER_00] means my name Why isn't it Rabbana Because in the Quran Rabbana comes also Yeah So that's the same exact rule I just mentioned If it's Mudaaf Mudaafi Rabbana means Our Lord Right If you want to be Technical to put it The form that we learned Lord of us Right That's Mudaafi So like I mentioned The Mudaaf will have to be Fatha So you say Ya Rabbana It's like you're saying Ya Rabbana But don't get confused Right Because we want everybody To get confused Just remember this general rule If there's a Ya after it The word Singular word after it Will have a Dhamma And only Only one Dhamma Right Not two So when you say Ya Allah Why doesn't The word Allah Take a Dhamma It does Ya Allahu Say Ya Allahu Ya Rahman Ya Rahim We just I mean If we're being lazy Or in general Like I mentioned In Tajweed for example You know the last Letter You don't pronounce it Right You say Ya Allah For
[SPEAKER_00] example We say Alhamdulillah Ya Rabbil Alameen Right But if you look At the actual word It has a Fath on it Alameena Right But we don't pronounce it Because in Tajweed The rule is that At the end When you're taking a pause You don't pronounce The haraka of that word The reason why I say To do it in this class Is because We are learning And we want to Solidify the rules Right Otherwise you guys Are going to get away with Making all the words After harfuljar Like oh You know Alal maktab Like okay But you know The point is For you to learn It's alal maktabi Right Get it Would you accept If we did Ishmamul Rom On the last Letter If you want to Fine yeah That's fine Do you want to explain To the class What ishmamul Rom is No Do you want to explain To everybody What that means So ishmam and Rom Are more ways Of stopping on a word Like
[SPEAKER_00] It's basically Like you say The haraka Very very Very lightly Yeah We don't want to Confuse people Because they're already Going to confuse All the terminologies So anyways Alright Everybody got that concept It's pretty simple right Ya allahu Just You can literally practice By just saying Allah's name If you know the nine names Ya allahu Ya rahman Ya rahim Ya malik Ya quddus Ya salam Ya mu'min Ya muhamin Ya aziz Ya jabbar How many of us Know the nine names Seriously Come on We should all know them Who knows the nine names Who knows the hadith About the nine nine names What does the hadith say The virtue of memorizing Nine nine names Yeah There's a hadith And I think Sahih Muslim Who memorizes Nine nine names of Allah They enter Jannah Right Easy way to do it Just listen to that Nine nine names Nasheed Right As'aluka Ya man You know that Nasheed Right Just keep listening to it Over and over and over again You'll remember And then Once you memorize it
[SPEAKER_00] Then you can just say Each of Allah's names Like that Ya rahman Ya rahim Ya malik You could even make dua Like that right You can spice up your dua As we mentioned In the salah class For dua We shouldn't just say The same dua Over and over and over again Because it makes it Dull and repetitive And it takes the ruh The spirit out of it So we should change it up Right We should say The different names of Allah We should call Allah With the different attributes And beautiful names That he has So that you know It builds a special connection To Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala Right So we're using All the different names of Allah Ya rahman And we ponder about The mercy of Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala Ya malik We think about How Allah owns Everything Right Then ya quddus We think about Allah's purity And how he is Pure from all faults Right And similarly All the names of Allah And at the same time We're implementing the rule Ya maliku Ya Ya Ya muqsitu Ya jami'u Ya ghaniyu Ya mughniyu Yeah You get it So that's one way We can practice Right Or you can just Everybody you come across In the day Is like hey Ya Blank Right And say their name And
[SPEAKER_00] they're like Wait what What did you say And you're like Oh no never mind Right But that's another way You can practice But the main thing is Practice it It'll come to your tongue Automatically That's the main thing The more we practice That's why I want to do These exercises Over and over again So it becomes like Second nature It'll come to your tongue Automatically And you don't even have To memorize the rule When they use Al Al Yeah so that When you say ya Then the al goes away It just becomes Ya maliku You get it So you don't say Yal maliku You say ya maliku Okay In the case of What you said About today What changes If you're If you're doing it For someone who has Whose name is already Oh You just make the first one Fatha Say ya abdullahi Right Right Right So I mean that's That's a more advanced rule That we'll sell in later But since he asked about it I mentioned it You don't have to worry Too much about that now So you would say Ya abdullahi Right
[SPEAKER_00] The second word is Kassab Because muhafile Okay Then Okay so that's the first We just We didn't even do the first sentence Finally the class is almost over Okay Next brother Tawheed you were reading Okay brother Saqib can you translate that No This is Good Inshallah Brother Tamim can you read Next one Sa'idun Aina Kitab Abu Muhammad Okay Brother Wahab translate it Where is Muhammad's book Muhammad's book Yeah Okay Brother Haqq can you read the next one Huwa alal maktabi hunata Okay good Now is a new word Huwa alal maktabi Uncle
[SPEAKER_00] can you Does that What does that mean Huwa alal maktabi hunata Who is there on the desk Not who Huwa means He or it Because over here it's an object So you say it Yeah It is on the The desk Hunaka is a new word Which means There There Hunaka Hunaka So there's Hunaka and there's another word It's very very very similar to this Hunalika It basically means the same exact thing It means there Where does this come in the Quran Hunalika Yeah right So that's in the Quran So Hunaka pretty much the same thing Is in the Quran This is a very commonly used word in Arabic Hunaka right So Huwa alal maktabi hunaka It is there on On the notebook right So on the desk sorry yeah
[SPEAKER_00] So Hunaka There's no Shadda Hunaka No this is called al-Dharf We're gonna get to that But it's not Ism al-Ishaara Because Ism al-Ishaara You're telling about something You're saying That is blank That is blank Right But this is like You're trying to indicate Towards a position of something Right Or like where it is Right So this answers the question Where is blank Then you would say Blank is Hunak But if somebody was to ask Where is Where is Hamid Then you wouldn't answer by saying Thalika Hamidun You would say Hamidun Hunaka Hamid is over there Right Like in English If I was to ask Where is Hamid You wouldn't respond by saying That is Hamid You would respond by saying Hamid is there You get it So that you understand The difference between the two It is very
[SPEAKER_00] similar But there is There is a difference though So Hunaka is when you're talking About something That's far away Right It's there Right If you want to know What's here Even though it didn't come in this lesson But I'll just tell you Anyways because it's very easy Huna Right Huna is here And Hunaka is there Huna So Anahuna Like I'm here Right So for example If I If I'm here I'm asking Oh Ayna Ayna Hussain al-yum Like where is Where is Hussain today I didn't see him Then Hussain will be like Anahuna Right I'm here Okay So Huna means here Inshallah I'm planning I was telling the brothers that I didn't do it for today Today But I'm planning Inshallah maybe for next lesson In the beginning of each lesson I'm going to give This is This will be optional for you to learn But it will help everybody I'm going to give like Two or three sentences That we can memorize Of Of Words Or
[SPEAKER_00] sentences That we can use For your regular speech On a daily basis Until the point where After a few weeks We can even be Holding full-blown conversations Based on the rules we know And on these sentences That we That we're using on a regular basis Fine I'm sorry Can I just I have a suggestion I was thinking for the last couple of weeks So after every Maybe two sessions Can we just have like Like a class With only communication Put our books away And like you can ask questions Only in Arabic And you have to answer in Arabic That's a very good idea That's a very good idea Because the way To learn language Is to speak Yeah We are only learning Basis But we're not Speaking That's true Speaking or communicating Is very important To understand And memorize Yeah The only thing We're going very very slow But And this will make it even more slow That's why I was hoping That you guys will do that Outside the class But if you want to do it in the class Then we can do it in the class too Huh Yeah well We can change We wrote We wrote We wrote two or three years But there was an asterisk Next
[SPEAKER_00] to it So you know We can We can increase That number of years As much as we want Inshallah Okay Just the last thing Right Before we end the class We'll skip there Because we didn't get to read there Okay let me just Let me just read the rest Very quickly Ain't a So correct Translation will be Huwa Ala Ala Maqtab Manak It's gonna be E On Table There Yeah It is on the table over there Yeah Ain't a daftar Where is Ammar Daftar Is office No Notebook Where is Ammar's notebook Huwa ala maktab al mudarisi It is It is on The teacher's desk Qalamu man hadha ya aliyyu What does that mean Quickly Brother Salim Whose pen is this Ya Ali Oh Ali Or Ali Ali Yeah So whose pen is this Oh Ali Hada qalam al mudarisi This is the The teacher's pen Ain a haqiba Haqiba is a new word I told you guys last time It means Bag or book bag Right Where
[SPEAKER_00] is the The teacher's book bag Hiya tahtal maktabi Okay so this is The last thing we're learning today It'll Just give me two three minutes We'll explain this last thing Hiya tahtal maktabi Right Hiya we already know It means She or it Right For a female object So haqiba Is a female object We know because How do we know Haqiba is a female object Because of ta at the end Ta marbuta Haqibatul Right So the ta Shows us Indicates that that's a female object Right Just like sa'a Sa'a means Watch Watch or clock Right So that's also a female object Because of the ta marbuta So anyways So hiya It is Tahtal maktabi Tahtal means Under And it's part of a new family But I think we'll introduce A family next time Inshallah Tahtal means Under Just know that the word After tahtal Generally speaking Is going to be Kasra
[SPEAKER_00] Okay The word after tahtal Will be kasra But it's not a harful jar The word after tahtal Will be kasra And it will be considered As mudaf Mudaf ilay To the word after it Why? You don't have to worry about it That's just the way the Arabs use it Even though If you look at the meaning It's not like a mudaf Mudaf ilay meaning But Tahtal will make the word After a kasra If you want to consider it Like a harful jar That's fine with me But as long as When we get to the later stages You have to be Know the specifics That okay No this is not A harful jar This is actually a Whatever it actually is We'll get to the family tomorrow Because it will take too long To explain But tahtal means Under And the word after it Will become kasra Right Can I give you Can someone give me One quick example Just to end the class From Quran Where tahtal makes the word After it Kasra Tahtal shajarati Very good Tahtal shajarati Right Tahtal shajarati Where is that? Oh yeah Oh
[SPEAKER_00] yeah If you Laqad radiallahu Anil mu'min If yubayi'unaka Tahtal shajarati Okay So tahtal comes Many times in the Quran Okay So the word after it Generally will be Kasra Okay We got that So that's We finished the lesson For today From all the important things We had to learn So okay For Wednesday Some of the brothers Were mentioning that Since it's a long weekend And maybe people have Plans with family And so on So should we give Wednesday off? No No No No No No No Optional speaking class Huh? Optional speaking class That's a good idea Brother Mohan said We can have an optional Speaking class But the answer Left already though So So okay I think that's a good idea We can do an optional Speaking class Where whoever wants to come Will just have extra practice We'll just speak And discuss with each other In sha Allah Alright so no class Technically no class But whoever wants to come We can practice next
[SPEAKER_00] class In sha Allah Everybody can go SubhanAllah bihamdi Subhanakum Allah wa bihamdik Ashadu wa la ilaha illa Dara as-salam wa rahmatullahi wa barakatuh Oh for homework Oh whatever Just leave it I'll tell you guys In the morning