[SPEAKER_00] As-salamu alaykum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatuhu. Bismillah ar-Rahman ar-Rahim. Mahmadoon wa salli ala rasoolin kareem. Amma ba'al. I think somebody took my book and... Okay, yeah. Alright, Bismillah ar-Rahman ar-Rahim. Mahmadoon wa salli ala rasoolin kareem. Amma ba'al. So, alhamdulillah, last time we finished entirely the 10th lesson. Nothing left here to do. So, inshallah, we can move on to lesson number 11. But before we do that, we did have some homework. It was optional, though, but if anybody did it, then they can, inshallah, present it.
[SPEAKER_00] The homework was to basically, if anybody has examples of these dama'ir, pronouns that we learned from the Qur'an. Min ladun hu. Yeah, good. Inshallah. From him. Min ladun hu means from him. Good. Yeah. Laha ma kasabat wa alayha maktasabat. Yeah. So, the ha, the dama'ir, the pronouns going back to the nafs. La yukallifu allahu nafsan illa wus'aha lahaa. Because remember we mentioned that nafs is one of those words which, even though there's no ta'am ar-buta, but they're female. It's a feminine word. Right? So, that's why we say lahaa. Right? Laha ma kasabat. So, that ha, dama'ir is for feminine words.
[SPEAKER_00] Good. Alayka tawakkalna. Alayka is when you take ala, when you put ala, and you connect it with the ka, it becomes alayka. So, this becomes a ya. And so, you say alayka. Right? So, upon you do we trust. Alayka tawakkalna. Understood? Understood? Yes? Yes. Tawakkalna. Okay. Good. Any other examples? Yeah. Wa lam yakun lahu kufuan ahad. And there is no, there is no match for Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala, for him. Right? Or a match or anyone who is superior or who is like Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala. Yeah. Subhanaka. Glory be to you. How much?
[SPEAKER_00] Allahu illaha illa huwal hayal kayyum. No, there's no, specifically the pronoun that we were looking for are not in there. But, yeah, good try though. Inshallah. Yeah. Good. Yeah. Good. Bi rabuwa tin asaba hawa. Wa matha allatheena yunfiquna amwaala. Wa matha allatheena yunfiquna amwaala humu butiqaa mardaatillahi wa tathbeetan min anfusihim. Ka matha li jannatin bi rabuwa tin asaba hawaabil. So waabil is basically a torrential rain. A very powerful rain. Storm, you could say. So, jannah is referring to a garden. Right? So Allah is giving the example of a person who spends in the way of Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala. For the sake of Allah. For seeking the pleasure of Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala. And so Allah is saying,
[SPEAKER_00] that it's like a garden that's a heavy rain. Asaba ha. It afflicts it. Meaning it basically pours onto it. Asaba ha. So the ha is going back to jannah, which is a feminine word. So that's why the female pronoun is used. Okay. Yeah. Good. Same ayah. Same thing. Yeah. Good. Good. Yeah. Ma aghna anhu ma luhu wa ma kasab. His wealth, ma luhu, his wealth, meaning Abu Lahab's wealth. Ma aghna anhu. It did not help him. It will not benefit him. Ma luhu wa ma kasab. Yeah. Good. Wa mra'atuhu and his wife. Imra'a means a woman and imra'atuhu means his woman, meaning his wife.
[SPEAKER_00] So wa mra'atuhu, his wife. Zawjiha. Good. Yeah. Qad sami'allahu qawla allati tujadiluka fi zawjiha. What is tujadiluka? Right? Arguing with you. Meaning it's a story of Khawla bin Sa'labah radiallahu anha and how the situation that happened between her and her husband and how she complained to Nabi sallallahu alayhi wa sallam. And so, tujadiluka. She was basically going back and forth with you fi zawjiha regarding her husband, her husband, zawjiha. Okay. Somebody. Ma'i. Good. Yeah. Fa'arsin ma'iya bani Israel. Ma'i. With me. So ma'a. You have ma'a. But then you add the ya. Means ma'i. With me.
[SPEAKER_00] Good. Inna ka. Let me know. Inna is something inshallah come in the second book. Inna is for extra emphasis. So, inna ka. It would be surely you or indeed you. Right? Inna ka. Let me know. Indeed or surely you are from the messengers. Wa ma'a daraaka. Yeah. There's many ayat. Yeah. Yeah. Wa ma'a daraaka ma'a hiya. For example, in Surah Qari'ah. So, and what will make you know? Good. So, ith qala rabbuka. And when your Lord said to the angels. Rabbuka. Your Lord. Good. Good. As in the durood. Right? Inna ka. Indeed you are praiseworthy and glorious. Good. Inna ka. Good. Allah is. Addressing Musa Alayhi Salaam.
[SPEAKER_00] Telling him that indeed you, inna ka, are in the blessed valley of Tua. Good. Waladina yu'minuna bima undila ilayka. And those who believe in that which was revealed to you. We already know ila. Right? Ila. Ila means to. Right? I went to. Blank. Right? They have to ila al-masjid, for example. Ila means to. So, ilayka. You just add the. When you add a kaf to it, it becomes ilayka. Just like ala becomes alayka. If you add a ka to ila, it becomes ilayka. Right? So, bima undila ilayka. Those who believe in that which was revealed to you. Meaning to Nabi Sallallahu Alaihi Wasallam. Good. Good. To him belongs that
[SPEAKER_00] which is in the heavens and the earth. Meaning Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala. Good. Inna shani aka huwal abtar. Shani means a person who hates. A hater. Right? So, indeed, your hater. Shani aka. Your hater. Allah is addressing Nabi Sallallahu Alaihi Wasallam. Surely, your hater is the one who is abtar. Who is cut off. Right? Why? Because if you look at the tafsir of the ayah. One of the kuffar of Mecca. He was trying to make fun of Nabi Sallallahu Alaihi Wasallam. That his children would all. Male children would all pass away. And so, he called him abtar. That he's like a person who's. Like a lizard whose tail is cut off, for example. Because a person who did not have children. Would be considered as if they had no legacy. Nobody to take on their name after they passed away. So, Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala told him. That rather, you're not the one who's cut off. Allah is giving you kawthar. Great abundance. Your hater. The one who said that statement.
[SPEAKER_00] Your hater is the one who is cut off. So, Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala. Responded on behalf of his beloved Nabi Sallallahu Alaihi Wasallam. And assured him. That he is not cut off. Rather, his hater is the one who is cut off. And history has proved that statement to be true. As those people are basically in the dustbins of history. Nobody even knows. Really cares about their name. Except maybe you'll read it in a tafsir book. But nobody cares about them. And their very own children. Instead of upholding their legacy. They ended up following the legacy of Rasulullah Sallallahu Alaihi Wasallam. And so, Nabi Sallallahu Alaihi Wasallam has the greatest legacy of any human being. To step foot on the face of the earth. Despite him not having any children. So, Your hater. Surah Yusuf. Good, yeah. Yeah. She is the wife.
[SPEAKER_00] Basically, now the women are talking smack about the wife of the Aziz Zulaikha. Because she basically was trying to commit a certain act with Yusuf Sallallahu Alaihi Wasallam. And so, they started spreading rumors and talking about her. That, oh, she is trying to. She is trying to seduce her. Her, basically, her slave. Her slave. Her servant. Despite his, basically, resistance. Yeah, but over there, there's no pronoun that we mentioned. Because Nuhyi, the Yadir is from the actual verb itself. It's not for... Yeah, yeah. But you did have another
[SPEAKER_00] one there, which is أَحْصَيْنَاهُ فِي كِتَابِ فِي إِمَامِ مُبِينٍ Yeah. And we have, basically, encompassed everything in a clear book. فَصَلِّ لِرَبِّكَ Good. فَصَلِّ لِرَبِّكَ And pray for your Lord. For the sake of your Lord. Your Lord. رَبِّكَ Yeah, good. Yeah, one of those mentioned that already. Good. أَلَّمَهُ الْبَيَانِ The beginning of Surah Ar-Rahman. Allah is saying that He taught him al-bayan, speech. Very good, good example, yeah. قُلْ إِنَّ صَلَاتِي وَنُسُكِي وَمَحْيَايَ وَمَمَاتِي لِلَّهِ رَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ Indeed, my salah, my
[SPEAKER_00] sacrifice, my life, مَحْيَايَ وَمَمَاتِي وَمَمَاتِي وَمَمَاتِي لِلَّهِ is for Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala, رَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ the Lord of the universe. What a beautiful ayah, right? إِنَّ صَلَاتِي وَمَمَاتِي وَمَمَاتِي وَمَمَاتِي لِلَّهِ There is still the same thing. It's still the pronoun for me. And my life, وَمَمَاتِي وَمَمَاتِي لِلَّهِ is for Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala, the Lord of the universe. Sorry? Yeah, إِسْمُهُ أَحْمَلُ Yeah, didn't we mention that in the last class? Okay, لَا إِلَهَ إِلَّا أَنْتَ سُبْحَانَكَ Yeah, glory be to you. Good. Good. اللَّهُمَّ أَعِنِّي أَعِنِّي أَوَلَهُمَّ أَعِنِّي أَوَلَّهُمَّ أَعَنِّي أَعَلَى
[SPEAKER_00] ذِكْرِكَ To remember you. ذِكْر, we know it means remembrance of Allah. ذِكْرِكَ أَوَلَّهُمَّ أَعَنِّي أَعَنِّي أَعَلَى ذِكْرِكَ وَشُكْرِكَ And to thank you. وَحُسْنِ عِبَادَتِكَ And to worship you in a beautiful... حُسْن حُسْن means beauty. وَحُسْنِ عِبَادَتِكَ And to worship you in a beautiful manner. Very good. So there's multiple. Everywhere. So that's why we shouldn't think it's a waste of time. This is actually, inshallah, solidifying this. More and more we hear. More examples we hear, inshallah, it becomes solidified in our mind. The different pronouns. Any more examples? لَا تَأْخُذُهُ Yeah, good. لَا تَأْخُذُهُ Right, talking about Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala, surah, in ayat al-kursi. That neither drowsiness nor sleep overcomes Him, Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala. إِذَا وَلْتَكْسِيَتُوا إِذَا
[SPEAKER_00] لِكَ فَقَوْلُ رَبَّنَا أَتِنَا مِنَ الدُّنْكَ رَحْمَةٌ أَتِنَا Yeah, I think you said مِن لَدُّنْكَ already. I said it a second time. Oh, a second time. Yeah, same concept. مِن لَدُّنْكَ Yeah, good. وَجَعَلْنِي مِن وَرَثَةِ جَنَّةِ النَّعِيمِ Ibrahim alayhi salam is making dua to Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala and make me from the inheritors of the gardens of bliss. وَجَعَلْنِي مِن وَرَثَةِ جَنَّةِ النَّعِيمِ Make me. رَبِّ شْرَحْ لِي صَدْرِي My Lord, basically expand my chest for me. لِي وَيَسِّرْ لِي أَمْرِي And make my matter easy for me. وَحَدُ الْعُقْدَةَ مِّن لِسَانِي And untie this knot in my tongue. From my tongue. لِسَانِي لِسَانِي means tongue. لِسَانِي means my tongue. وَيَفْقَهُ قَوْلِي
[SPEAKER_00] So they may understand my statement, my speech. قَوْلِي Okay, I think it's enough examples, inshallah. But you see again that we should really, really be pondering now. We know a lot, actually. If you really take a step back and try to implement all the rules that we've learned so far and you start looking at the Qur'an, you can actually realize that you actually know a lot. A lot of different words. Right now it's still a little bit early, but inshallah soon you'll get to the point where the main thing is once you figure out how to basically figure out what are the root letters of a word, right? Once you figure that out, then I'll teach you how to use an Arabic dictionary. Once you learn how to use an Arabic dictionary, basically the sky is the limit because now you can look up any word in the Qur'an and you can figure out, okay, what tense is it used in? What form is it used in? What
[SPEAKER_00] context is it used in? And through that, inshallah, you can even go even further. Right now you're a little bit limited. I don't want to take you further than you're able to right now. But even then, if you were to just apply everything you know so far, you'd realize that you would actually know quite a bit and you're actually able to grasp a lot. All right, let's get started on lesson 11, inshallah. Bismillah ar-Rahman ar-Rahim. Who wants to read? Bismillah ar-Rahman ar-Rahim. Yeah, place or time. In this case, it indicates
[SPEAKER_00] place. So, translate. This is my house. My house is in front of the masjid. Good. Yeah, my house is in front of the masjid. My house is beautiful. So humble, mashallah. Mashallah. In his? Let him figure it out. I'm sorry. What is hadeeqah? Hadeeqah. Can anybody remind him what is hadeeqah? Garden. Garden. In it is a small garden. Yeah, good. Hadeeqah. Hadeeqah. Hadeeqah. Hadeeqah. Whoever is reading, let them know. Let them try to figure it out because that's how, inshallah, we will learn.
[SPEAKER_00] This is my room. Good. Mirwahatun. That's a new word, I think, right? Or did it come before? I think it came before. No, mirwahatun. No, maybe it didn't come. Okay. Mirwahatun is a fan. It came before. It did, right? What is nafaza? Nafiza, that came before. Yeah. Somebody... Window. Yeah, window. Okay. Hadeequrfati is my room. Feeha nafiza kabiratun. When it says feeha in the... Why is it feeha instead of fee? So what is it going... Think about what it's going back to. What is it referring to? Hadeeqah? Hadeeqah? That will... Will a garden have a window? No.
[SPEAKER_00] Feeha nafiza tun. Nafiza is what? A window. Yeah, so look... See the... Okay, the general rule for... It's not always the case, but the default is that the dhamir, the pronoun, will go back... It will go back to the closest noun that's to it. Right? So you don't have to think far back. Or maybe it's going all the way back. A few sentences. No. The default is that it's going back to the closest thing that was mentioned. Sometimes it'll go back to something else. That's a different scenario. But generally speaking, it's going to go back to the closest thing that was mentioned. So what was the closest thing that was mentioned before? Huh? No. No. The window. The window? No, no, no. Room. Sorry? Yeah, room. Ghurfati. Because we're talking about the window itself. We're saying the window is in something.
[SPEAKER_00] In the room is a big window. What was the name of the window? Fan. With a beautiful fan. And a beautiful fan, yeah. And a beautiful fan. Hatha shariri wa hadha kursi wa hadha makdadi. This is my bed. And this is my bed. And this is my chair. And this is my desk. So basically he's giving a tour of his house. Sa'ati wa alami wa kitabi ala al-maktabi. Sa'ati. This is my clock and my pen and my book on the desk. Yeah, watch would be more likely. Sa'ati could be either watch or clock. So I
[SPEAKER_00] think over here it's more likely a wall. Because it's on a desk. And my bag is under the desk. Nafidatun. Sorry? Nafidahoo. It's a tamer. Nafidatoo. Nafidatoo ghorfati maftoohatoo. Maftoohatoo. Maftoohatoon. Good, yeah. Okay, my question to you is why is it not nafidatoon? Nafidatoon ghorfati. Nafidatoon ghorfati. It's the window of my room. Oh, because it's mullahullah. So, the window of
[SPEAKER_00] my room is open. So remember, mudhaf cannot get tanween. Okay, continue. Hada ghorfatu. Hadihi. Hadihi ghorfatu aqee. This room is my brother's. This is? This is my brother's room. Yeah. So if you were to say, this room is my brother's, you would say it like this. Hadihi ghorfatu li aqee. Do you get the difference? Yeah. So you translated it as this room is my brother's, right? But remember we learned that if you were to say that, you would say, Hadihi ghorfatu li aqee. This room, Hadihi ghorfatu li aqee, belongs to my brother. But if you wanted to say, this is my brother's room, then you would say it like this. Hadihi ghorfatu aqee.
[SPEAKER_00] This is mudhaf mullah fil aya as well. Yeah, mudhaf mullah fil aya. That's why it's ghorfatu. Yeah. What is the ghorfatu uqti? And that is my sister's room. Mm-hmm. Ghorfatu aqee kabiratun wa ghorfatu uqti sabiratun. My brother's room is big and my sister's room is small. Ghorfatu aqee amama ghorfati wa ghorfatu... Uqti amaman maqbaq. Amaman maqbaqee. I wonder why that's the case. My brother's room is in front of the room. Which room? Oh, in front of my room and my... Why is it ghorfatu if it's a female? What else would it be? That's mudhaf mullah fil aya. Oh. No, so what were you thinking? I was thinking it was like... Ghorfatu aqee kabiratun wa ghorfatu uqti sabiratun. Yeah, but over here they're not using
[SPEAKER_00] a pronoun at all. It's just... Yeah. And my sister's room is in front of the bathroom. Mm? In front of the kitchen. Kitchen, yeah. That's where it's supposed to be. That's where it's supposed to be. All right. Ghorfatu aqee amama ghorfatu uqti sabiratun wa ghorfatu uqti sabiratun. My brother... My brother... My brother... Li akhun wahidun. I belong... So what does... For example, hadhal kitabu li sa'im. What does that mean? Belongs to... Say it again. Hadhal kitabu li sa'imin. This book belongs to Sa'im. Okay. So now li means... Belongs to me. Okay. And then what comes after it? I have one brother. Okay.
[SPEAKER_00] Belongs to me, my brother. You say, I have... I have one brother. Oh, okay. I have one brother. His name is Usama. Mm-hmm. Wali ukhdun wahidatun ismuhas Su'ad. Su'ad. And I have one sister. Her name is Su'ad. Okay. Say it again. Fi? No. It should be Kasra. Yeah. Because of Fi. Translate. It's still Telka, right? Fi, Telka, Kel... Warfati. Yeah. It's kind of... This is... I don't want to confuse you guys with this point, but basically,
[SPEAKER_00] just consider in terms of this point about Fi, consider Telka as if it's not there. So it's as if Fi is affecting Al-Ghurfa and Kabira directly. The Al-Ghurfa is of Kabira. That's Mus'ud. Yeah, good. Yeah, it's Mus'ud. My father and my brother... Sorry. My father and my mother, their room is that big room. No, they... Yeah, are in that big room. Good. Yuzhishan, you're raising your hand. I love my mother, my father and my mother. And I love my brother and my sister. And my sister. Uhibbu means I love. Love. It's more for love, right? I love my father
[SPEAKER_00] and my mother. And I love my brother and sister. And my sister. Okay, good. MashaAllah. All right. So what do we learn from this lesson? So we kind of already did this part, Fi and Fiha, right? We already went over that. In the last lesson, because we were giving a lot of examples from the Qur'an and stuff. So, but they just wanted to highlight specifically that when you attach the dhamir to Fi, then it looks like this, Fi and Fiha, in it. Right? So, من في هذا البيت فيه حامد Somebody translate this? Read and translate. Who's in this room? Beit. Oh, sorry. In the house? In this house? Hamid is in it. فيه حامد. Yeah, good. So also they're trying to emphasize that
[SPEAKER_00] فيه will come first many times, right? Well, it's not always the case, but many times it will come first. So, for example, you won't normally say حامد فيه. You'll say فيه حامد. Get it? That's generally the case. For example, in Surah Bayyinah, فيها, كتب قيمة. Okay, but it's not always the case, but yeah. Continue next. Do you want to read number two? Okay, so you want to read number two? مالك القيمة فيها قتابي و قلبي و دستري What is in the bag? My books, my pen, and my notebook is in it. Good. In it is my pen, my book, my notebook, my pen and my notebook. Very good. Mashallah. Alright. حافظ القاشم
[SPEAKER_00] من تسيالتي فيها أبي و أمي و أخي و أختي Who's in the car? In it is my father, my mother, my brother, and my sister. Good. Brother Ali. Next one. من تسيالتي الجامعة الآن الآن جامعة الآن ما فيه أحب Who is in the universe? جامعة الأحبة Who is in the universe? What is Masjid? You know what Masjid means? So what is this in terms
[SPEAKER_00] of the grammar, in terms of the rules that we learned so far? Masjid al-jami'ati. Which one? Yeah, which rule is it? I'm not sure. For example, كتاب حامد What rule is that? Yeah, so same thing here. Masjid al-jami'ati. Or here's Masjid al-kazafi. Al-jami'a, you remember what it means? Jami'a is like a class? No, university. University, right? Yeah. So the masjid? University masjid? The masjid of the university, yeah. The masjid of the university, okay. I mean, it might be foreign to us because we don't really have masjids in our universities, but in Arab countries,
[SPEAKER_00] they'll have masjids within the university. Okay, who is in the masjid of the university? Al-an means? I'm not sure. I don't know. No. Yeah, al-an means right now. This is a very common word we should all know. In Arabic, that's called al-masjid al-jami'u. Al-masjid al-jami'u is a jami'a masjid. Yeah. Al-masjid al-jami'u. There's no time to put on it. And it's mawsoof sifa, not mudhaf mudhafi. What's the difference between saying masjid al-jami'ati an and masjid al-jami'ati al-an? Like what's the difference between an and al-an? It's just that you're supposed to say al-jami'ati al-ana because alhamdulillahi wa sallam. Remember, al-wasl, you're not supposed to pronounce it if it's in the middle of. Is
[SPEAKER_00] there a difference between putting the al in the front? What do you mean? It does have al-an. Like the word is al-an, right? Al-an. Yeah. Okay, mafihi ahadun. Ahadun. So. What does ma mean over here in this context? Is it? So basically, yeah, we learned there's two possibilities. Whenever you see ma now, you should think, at least for now, for us, because we didn't learn all the other possibilities, like five, six, seven possibilities for ma. But for now, we only learned two possibilities for ma. What are they? Yeah, one is, sorry? What and? Yeah. So either you're asking a question, ma hadha, what is this? Or you're negating. You're saying. I do not have, right? So either you're negating or either you're asking
[SPEAKER_00] a question, right? So over here, which one is it? What do you think? Negating. Yeah, good. Ahad means a single person, yeah? So if you're saying mafihi ahadun, it means nobody, there's nobody in it. Good. Mafihi ahadun, there's nobody in it. All right. Last one. Anybody? Al-mudiru. Yeah. So fi is, it's, it's, it's, whatever, it's amal, meaning it's, effect is going on to the ha. So it doesn't affect the mudir. Okay. Who is in the room? Mm-hmm. This room. Hadhi al-gurfa. Who is in this room? Mm
[SPEAKER_00] -hmm. In it is the principal. Good. Very good. Mashallah. Who is in this room? In it is the principal. Okay. Is it girl principal? Sorry? Is that a girl principal? No, girl principal would be al-mudiratu. Fi ha, the reason why it's a female pronoun is it's going back to the ghurfa, the room, in the question. The room is a feminine word, so that's why it's fi ha. Sorry, I'm a little confused. Is the ha, like you just said, the ha in this case is because it's referring to the room, but I thought it's ha because there's a human being and not the room itself. Like the previous examples that we did, any time there's a human being, then ha is used, but any time there's an object used, then he is used. No. No.
[SPEAKER_00] If you look back at that it that it's referring to, is it a masculine word or a feminine word? And based on that, you put either fi hi or fi ha. So in number four, when it says ma fi hi ahadun, there's no one in it, it's referring to the masjid. Exactly. The masjid is masculine, so therefore you're saying fi hi. If you were just to ask about the jami'ah, if he was going to say man fi al-jami'ati al-an, then he would say ma fi ha ahad, because al-jami'ah is a feminine word because it has ha. This is where, ma fi ha zahi haad? Yeah. Haadihi. Can we say
[SPEAKER_00] in it, fi ha, but can we say also in this direction? In it, in this, fi, in this would be fi hadha. You get it? But for the pronoun, you say in it. Yeah, it is a pronoun. This is not a pronoun. Okay. For the fi hi, the previous one, ma fi hi ahadun, is that referring to the masjid, the fi hi? Yeah. It's referring to the masjid, masjid al-jami'ah. Remember we mentioned that when you're talking about mudhaf, mudhaf ilayh, in reality, mudhaf itself is the one thing that's being talked about in the sentence. Right? For example, the pen of Hamid, qalamu Hamidin. So you're not talking about Hamid here, you're talking about Hamid's pen. Do you get it? So in that case, whatever you're going to describe after, it's referring to the pen. The pen of Hamid. Not Hamid. Hamid is irrelevant here. Generally speaking. Okay. Now, we learned a word, uhibbu.
[SPEAKER_00] Right? This is actually a present tense verb. So this is the first present tense verb we're going to learn. So far, we've only learned what type of verbs? Farah al-Mawli, which is past tense verbs. Right? We learned dhahaba, dhabta, also we learned. Dhabdu. I went. Right? So we learned basic things and I gave you guys a whole chart, which inshaAllah we will be starting to utilize more often inshaAllah. So that was all for past tense. Now, this is the first time we're using a present tense verb, but I'm not going to confuse you guys yet by giving you the chart and everything. So for now, just remember that if you want to say you love something or someone, you say, uhibbu blank. Right? So for example, let's read number one. Thaqif. Uhibbu abi wa ummi. I love my father and my mother. Good. Hafidh Mu'min, number two.
[SPEAKER_00] Uhibbu akhi wa akhi. Okay. I love my brother and my sister. Okay. I love my classmate. Good. Uhibbu zamili. Which classmate are you talking about? Zamili. Which one? Which one specifically? Alif. MashaAllah. Okay. Okay. Number four. Anybody? Uhibbu ustadi. Oh, JazakAllah. Okay. Number five. Uhibbu Allah. Yeah. Okay. Now, we are, for the first time, introduced to a very, very important rule, right? So, if you look at it, it says, Uhibbu Allah. Why is it becoming a fatha? Right? So far, we've only learned things that make other things. Kasra. Now, we're learning about things that make other things. Fatha.
[SPEAKER_00] Why is it becoming fatha? It's because this is a verb. Right? So, normally, with a verb, you have a doer, the one who's doing the action. And then, you have the object, which is the thing that the action is being done upon. Right? So, in Arabic language, generally speaking, the object is doing the action. The object of the verb gets a fatha. Right? In Arabic, it's called, Maf'oolun bihi. Maf'oolun bihi. Maf'oolun bihi. Right? The object of the verb. Everybody understand what's meant by object, right? Right? Yes? Da'awullaha. They made dua. They called to Allah. Da'awullaha. That's why the word Allah is fatha. Right? And there's so many examples in the Qur'an. Right? Wa nada ashabu aljannati ashaban
[SPEAKER_00] nari. Nada means to call out. The people of Jannah called out to the people of the fire. Ashaban nari. It's fatha because they're the object. They're the one who are being called out to. Understood? You ready? Yeah. So basically, so far, we've only done verbs that don't, so not every verb has an object. Right? There are many verbs that don't require an object. Right? Because you're leaving the room, you're not doing that to anybody. Right? So the nature of the verb dictates whether you'll need an object or not. So for hitting, for example, daraba, you're going to require something that's being hit. Right? But if you're going somewhere, there's not necessarily an object. There's not necessarily an object that you're doing that to. You get it? So it depends on the nature of the verb. Right? And this is something that you'll pick up based on how the verb is used in
[SPEAKER_00] Arabic. When you say, jadassal wajibu, isn't the man receiving the sitting? No, he's doing the sitting. So it doesn't count? Yeah. So basically, so just this. So this is a general rule. The mafrul bihi gets a fatha and the fa'il, if it's mentioned, gets a dhamma. Right? For example, dhahaba sa'imun ilal bayti. Sa'im went to the house. Right? So fa'il is the object. Sorry, the doer. So that we kind of already learned, but we didn't go over the actual rule. But that's a general rule. But the doer gets a dhamma and the object gets a fatha. Right? Like I said, let me just write that example down.
[SPEAKER_00] And for hufaal, this rule will actually help you a lot for taraweeh. Right? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Let me take a look. Every verb, every type of verb. Let me do it this way. This is a passing verb, Ashabul... This is the passing verb. Okay, when Hawk, how bold dunno, this is Obama because it's, it's a doer of nada-nada means to call out. So the people of Jannah they called out And who's the object Who's on the receiving end of the calling out It's Ashab al-Nari So people of Jannah called out To the people of the five So that's why they're Ashab al-Nari Got it? There's a question here
[SPEAKER_00] So the Like Wahibu Abiy Ummi These are human beings They're not objects That's why you have the E in there When you say Wahibu Wahibullah That It's not you I guess you're defining their lives No so basically Because normally for names You don't add a Ya at the end Right? Okay Yeah for example like You don't say like A person's name and say Add a Ya at the end You don't say For example Muddathiri Right? You don't say it like that You will say For example If he's your classmate You will say Zamili Muddathir Right? But you won't say the person's name Say My Even in English You don't normally say Like my My Sa'im Or my You know You don't say that So same thing You don't say So if you want to say My Lord Rabbi Then that You can say that About Allah So it's not that It's not that You can't apply Ya to
[SPEAKER_00] Allah It's just that The word Allah Is his name Right? Whereas Rab is like a title Of Allah So therefore That's why you You say Rabbi You understand? So the calling Is being done By the companions Of the Jannah Right? So they That's the doer Who gets the dhamma That's why That's hafu And then The object is The people of the fire And that gets The fathat But the naar In the Jannah They have The kasra Because Muddathiri Exactly They're both Muddathiri Maybe an easier example Would be Muddathiri Al-ladhi jama'a ma'alan Jama'a Sin surah Humaza Jama'a Ma'alan Ma'alan So jama'a Means to gather Ma'al Means Wealth So The doer is Mentioned before
[SPEAKER_00] Humaza Al-humaza Al-ladhi jama'a So The one who Al-humaza Al-humaza Right? The slandering The one who Backbiter So He He gathers Wealth You get it? So the object is The wealth That's the thing that The verb is being done upon The gathering is being done to The wealth Right? So therefore He's going to get a fatha Jama'a ma'alan Understood? Yeah? Clear? Why does the doer not have A dhamma? So in this case The doer is A pronoun Like That's something That might get a little confused That's what we'll do Inshallah In the second book It'll come It's going to come That chapter Sometimes the doer Is not mentioned Sarihan Is not mentioned Clearly Rather It's Basically Implied Right? So jama'a Is actually He He gathered So the It's not mentioned Clearly in the sentence But sometimes It is mentioned Clearly in the sentence So when it's mentioned Clearly in the sentence Then you give it
[SPEAKER_00] a dhamma Otherwise It's implied Understood? But isn't it also Because al-ladhi comes Yeah that too Yeah You could say that In a way Yeah Right Yeah That's not Yeah Yeah There's another example Of nada Nada again means To call out Right? Nada Nuhun Rabbahu Right? Wanada So somebody translate this for me Based on what you know Good And Nuh called his lord Or called to his lord Right? So the The subject I'm sorry The doer is Nuh He's
[SPEAKER_00] the one who's doing the calling And the calling is being done to His lord So that's why it's getting fatha Rabbahu Get it? Understood? So this This I mean The purpose of this lesson Wasn't to teach this But since it came up I'm just telling you guys now So that you get a head start So it's gonna come up This actual concept will be Much more thoroughly discussed Later in the book But we just need to know that When you say Uhibbu If you're gonna say Kitabi Or things like that Then you don't have to worry Because Even though technically It does have a fatha on it Because it's the object But because of the ya It doesn't show Right? Uhibbu kitabi Right? Technically it should be Kitabay Right? It should be a fatha But because of the ya It doesn't show So it does have a fatha But it's just not showing So you just pronounce it as Kitabi But when it doesn't have E For example Then you're gonna You're gonna have to have a fatha on it Right? So if you wanna say Uhibbu I love Any object or person or thing You make it fatha Right?
[SPEAKER_00] If you're not talking about E For example Uhibbul masjida Right? Uhibbullaha Uhibbull rasulullahi Sallallahu alayhi wasallam In this one It ended up with Dhamma right? Rabbuhu No this is fatha Rabbahu Rabbahu Oh no so The You don't consider the pronoun As the end of the word The word rabb Is the end Do you get it? The pronoun is separate Just consider it as the end Yeah Exactly Yeah I had another example But not I was wondering why the Nuh doesn't get A tanween But it's actually in the Nuh after It's like Yeah Good It's actually Yeah But because The Hamzatul Wasl rule Remember I told you the Kasra rule right? So We did that I think in class Some time before Yeah Good example
[SPEAKER_00] Alright so I mean you don't have to know this In detail Because it's gonna come In detail later But just know that If you wanna say I love something Or somebody You put a Fathah on it Right? So let's read the last few I love Allah Keep going Anybody? Brother Haq The Prophet If you were to say My Prophet Then you would say I love my Prophet I love my Prophet Or Rasooli But you're just saying The Prophet Al-Nabiya Sallallahu alayhi wa sallam Alright Last one Al-Lughatal Yeah Trying to
[SPEAKER_00] think? Yeah Because it's Mawsoof and Sifah Good I love the Arabic Language So again you're making it Fathah Because it is Mufroon B It is the object Everybody understood all of that? Yes? Alright good Wait I'm confused now So if the object Is getting a Fathah Why number four Is it I love Ustazee I mentioned that Basically when there's a When there's a Ya When you're saying Kitabi There is technically A Fathah But it's hidden Right? Because of the Ya You don't pronounce it Because it would be like Difficult to pronounce It would be like Ustazayi Right? So you just say Ustazee Okay It's implied basically So basically The attached pronoun Removes like the effect Sometimes Not always Like for example Over here Rabbahu It still shows The Fathah still shows Rabbahu You get it? So only in the case of Ya normally Does
[SPEAKER_00] it hide The effect of it Otherwise Other cases it does Even if there's other pronouns It will show Alright we can end here Inshallah Once I love the teacher Of the madrasa I say Very good yeah Alright inshallah We'll go on to lesson number Twelve On Monday So it's Wednesday right? Okay Monday inshallah And just a heads up We will not have class On Wednesday Because I'm going to be traveling Inshallah But we'll continue to We'll continue the Monday After that Inshallah So we'll have We have class this Monday Then no class Wednesday Then we have class The Monday after that Inshallah If you guys want to do Like a group review session Or something Together Maybe you could do that But Sorry Allah Allah Allah Allah Allah Allah Allah
[SPEAKER_00] Allah Allah Allah Alas That Can Yes The Am 콩 My am peque use the Surah Al-Fatihah