[SPEAKER_00] Thank you very much. Thank you.
[SPEAKER_00] Thank you. Thank you.
[SPEAKER_00] Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
[SPEAKER_00] So, a pronoun, do you remember what it is? Yes? No? What's a pronoun? No, just in general, English. What does a pronoun do? Sorry? It decides gender. Okay, gender. A little more specific. Basically, you use a pronoun when you don't want to repeat the name of somebody or something over and over again. So, you'll mention the name once, and then the rest of the time, you'll use a pronoun to refer to them. So, in a sentence, you're not going to say, like, brother movement, came to the masjid, brother movement, praise Allah, brother movement, talk to brother, brother movement, left. You're not going to keep saying brother movement, brother movement, or movement over and over and over. You're just going to say his name once, and after you say it, then he did this, then he did that. So, you use a pronoun to, basically, make it shorter,
[SPEAKER_00] to make it concise. So, the same way you have in Arabic. You mention the name of something or a person once, and after you use a pronoun to refer to them. So, now, So, now, what are the pronouns we learned earlier? We learned things like huwa, huwa means he. Huwa means masjid, for example. Hiya means she. In both ways, they also mean it. Because, in Arabic, objects also have gender. So, it can mean he or it. Then, we also learned anda. Anda means you. Anda means you. Anda means you. Which means you will talk to a female. Then, we learned ai, which is ana.
[SPEAKER_00] So, these are some of the pronouns that we learned, and these are detached. Why? Because they're standalone. They're not connected to anything else. Rather, they're self-sufficient. They don't need anybody else. There's other types of pronouns which are attached pronouns. So, they have to be connected to another word. Now, in this lesson, we learned a few of these. So, one is ka. So, this means you. So, for example, So, ism ka means ism means name. Wasm taadibi hamza. Ism taadibi hamza.
[SPEAKER_00] So, ism alone means name. Ism ka means your name. So, whatever you attach ka to, that means it becomes your. You get it? This is your pen. means this is your book. Let's say you're outside, for example, and you're talking, and you're like, I'm going somewhere, and you start walking to your fancy car. And a person's like, oh, is this your car? So, again, you just attach ka to whatever the object is, and that means it's your blank. You get it? So, ka itself means you, right? Or your, depending on the context of the sentence. Then, so that's one type of attached pronoun. Then, the ya, i, is a different type. Right? Or
[SPEAKER_00] the the word before it. So, it goes and this itself will become. Right? So, my book. My pen. Right? Right? We learned that. means my lord. Right? Anybody else? My mother, my father. Right? Any other examples? Huh? Yeah, exactly. And yeah, Allah is saying that, purify my house, which is referring to the Kaama. Right? Yeah. Yeah. My sister. Yeah, good. Anabi? Anabi? No, not Anabi. Just say Anabi. Anabi means I am. So, you're saying I am my father, right? Almost.
[SPEAKER_00] Just say Anabi. That's why you have this pronoun, right? You don't need to say, like, you would think that, again, when you don't know Arabic properly, you would just think, like, these pronouns would suffice. You would say, you know that Ana means me and father. So, you would think, oh, my father means Ana. Right? Or something. Right? But now we know that, you don't use these pronouns. You use these. Right? You just say, and you add this to the end. means my father. So, you don't need Ana at all. You can say, means my city, my country. Right? My land. Any other examples? Yeah, means my brother. Yeah, my friend. Good. means chest. means my chest. He's asking Allah, expand my chest. Good example. Anabi?
[SPEAKER_00] No, he has part of the word itself. Yeah. . . Good. My heart. Yeah. . Yeah, that's a different context. I don't want to confuse the business here. . Good. Right? means my statement. Right? Yeah, we mentioned that already. . My beard. Good. . . . . . . . . . . . . .
[SPEAKER_00] . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .
[SPEAKER_00] . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .
[SPEAKER_00] . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .
[SPEAKER_00] . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . or let's just restart the lesson it's been more than a month so we might as well restart the lesson who wants to read the Shabu? what page?
[SPEAKER_00] page 54 I am a student of university in the university you are a new student? are you a new student? yes I am a student of university I am a student of university yes I am a new student yes I am a new student so again these are examples of Mosul Sifat Baalibun and Jadidun is describing Baalibun and they fit in those four categories can you remind me
[SPEAKER_00] of those four categories? ya, Ding Hamid, Ding wait sorry can you explain yourself? why are you saying ding? in a little flat? um, Muhammad Khan taught me a yeah yeah I understand the four rules for Mosul Sifat is ding, that's how you easily remember it but it's definite daalaf definite or indefinite daalaf is the ending N is the number and G is the gender good, yeah remember we learned the four categories that these four categories are the same as the other five? These four things have to be the same in Mosul and Sifah, right? So there's an easy acronym you can remember if you always forget. It'll help you remember, right? It goes like this. Indefinite slash indefinite
[SPEAKER_00] Errob means the ending. And then en? Number. Meaning singular, plural. Gender. So you just think of ding. And you remember this. And it'll help you remember the four things that the Mosul and Sifah are supposed to be the same in. So talibun, jadeedun. They're both indefinite because they both have the mean. Talibun. They both have dhamma. So they both have the same errob meaning ending harakah. Then they are both singular. And they are both male. So therefore they fit all the criteria
[SPEAKER_00] for them to be considered Mosul. And Sifah. And obviously jadeedun is describing the student. So therefore we can safely say this is a Mosul-Sifah construct. Right? So then therefore you would translate it as a new student. Right? So you wouldn't say student is new or something. You would translate it as a new student. Okay. Are you a new student? Yes, I am a new student. Okay. You could continue. Yes? Singular, plural. Singular, plural. Yes. Etc. Okay. Do you know? Okay. Where are you from? Good. I am from India. Okay. What's your name? Muhammad. . Muhammadun.
[SPEAKER_00] Muhammadun. Yes. Okay. So if you have a student that is a new student, you could say, Okay. It's like, what's your name? Muhammad. So you would say, . . Okay. So if you put it like this, and in your native language, okay. Okay. Mat and stand. Can you say everything all together? Yes. Okay, go ahead. Who is the young man
[SPEAKER_00] with you? Good. Who is this young man, who is this young man who is with you? Muhammad. So ma'aqa, right, sorry, this is a key here, right? So the ma'a means, ma'a means with, by itself, right? And we learned that it's a dhawf, right? It makes the next word kestrel. But now we have qa, I guess, added to it and it connects to it. So it becomes ma'aqa, right? So that means with you, right? If you want to say with me, how would you say it? Ma'i. Good. Ma'i. This comes in the Qur'an too, right? إِنَّ مَعِيَ رَبِّي سَيَهِينَ My Lord is with me and He will guide me. With Him, yes. Ma'aqoo, ma
[SPEAKER_00] 'aqoo will be with Him. Ma'aqa means with you, and ma'i is with me. Okay. And then? Huwa dhameel, huwa dhameel. Muhammad, huwa dhameel, dhameel be. Is dhameel? Yes, dhameel is? Colleague. Colleague or classmate. Amen. Okay, so key word here is the yaa at the end of dhameel. Dhameelun just means colleague, a colleague or a classmate. Dhameeli means my classmate or my colleague. Yeah, continue. Huwa my classmate. He is my classmate. Amen. Huwa a'idin minal hin. He is also from. Is he? There is a question, right? Ah, the Hamza
[SPEAKER_00] in the beginning, remember we have pushed all around, we called that the Hamza in the beginning. It's called Hamzatul. No, not Huzul Althum. Hamzatul istifham. It means it's indicating the word asking a question. He is also from. No, is he? Is he? Idan is not also. Sorry? Idan. He is also, but I'm saying, you're saying he is, but it's a question so you should say, is he? He is also from. Yeah. Muhammad la huwa min al-Yabani. No, he is from Japan. Japan, yeah. Min al-Yabani. Min al-Yabani. Why is it Kessler? Min. Quick, come on. Will you guys get it hard for Doug? Will you guys get it hard for Doug? Min. Min? Min al-Yabani. What is it about hali Kessler? Hori kaudjaab na thairoo. Everything is very extra quiet today. Seems pretty depressed to be here. Horo kaudjaab.
[SPEAKER_00] Harastun jawed. Everybody else forgot? No? Depressed to be back in class? Amir T mumfav ki di선? Behishmo. Okay, lunche, Rick 140? Maborant, ma esmuk khumtiya ist uncomfortable dedi, Elike ikki cana. That's None part of the question. What is your name? No, his name. Who? Yeah, what is his name? What is his name? Yeah, so let's start first. His name is Hamza. Wait, his name is Hamza. Sorry, what are the questions? Okay. Is Hamza an exception to the Tamirin at the end of the name? Yeah. Because it has a Tamirin at the end, right, normally the female names you learn that they are exceptions and they don't get the name, right? So
[SPEAKER_00] Hamza is one of the rare male names that have a Tamirin at the end. Normally, again, we mentioned the general rule is if it's Tamirin, you can automatically say it's female. However, there are some rare male names that also have Tamirin, right? For example, Hamza. Hamza. Hamza, right? So that has a Tamirin, so it will also carry the same ruling as the female names in the sense that it will not get the name. Another example is Talhatu, right? Talha is a name that has the Tamirin, therefore it will not get the name, as well. Okay. What does it mean? What is your name, O Muhammad? O Muhammad? Or what? O Muhammad. No, what is it? Yeah, because ya. If you put ya, then automatically what happens? You get one dhamma, right? Not the middle. Ya Muhammad.
[SPEAKER_00] Ya Muhammad, okay. What's his language? His? Your. Lughatuka. My language. Lughatuka. Yeah. What's your language? Your language. So, lughatun in general means language. Lughatuka means? Your. Your language. Your language. What's the translation for ya? O? Yeah, you can say O, yes. Lughatula. Lughatula. Your language. O Muhammad, right? Mm-hmm, yes. Muhammad, lughati al-Urdaniya. No. No. Urdi. Urdiya. Yeah, al-Urdiya. Al-Urdiya. What's your language? Your favorite language. Al-Urdiya. Al-Urdiya. What is that? Urdiya is Urdu. Urdu. Yeah. Lughati al-Urdiya. Muhammad. Lughati means my language, and al-Urdiya means Urdu, Urdu language. Okay.
[SPEAKER_00] Amr. Ahia. Ahia. Ahia. Lughatun sahlatun. Ahia. Is this language easy? No, no. Sahlatun. Ahia lughatun sahlatun. Oh. Is. Translate it again, please. Lughatun. Lughatun sahlatun. Is that your language? No. Hiya. Why is it her? No. So, hiya, remember it can be her, but objects in Arabic are also considered female or male as well. So, lughat is a female object. Therefore, you would say. Is it. Is it. Is it. Is it. Is it. Is it a language? Is it easy language? Is it an easy language? Easy. Because it's Takbeen, right? So, you're trying to ask, is it an easy language? Okay.
[SPEAKER_00] Muhammad, now, hiya lughatun sahlatun. Lughatun. Lughatun sahlatun. Sahlatun. Yes. Muhammad, yes. It is easy language. Yes, it is an easy language, yes. So Luma Tun Sahla is Mawsoof and Sufah, right, because they're both female, just go through the din, right? They're both indefinite, and they're both, Errab is saying the last harakah is the same, they're both Dhamma, and they're both singular, and lastly they're both female, feminine, right? Okay, is there any? I'll continue. Yeah, you continue. Khamidana wa hamza wa hamzatu maa lughatuhu. Maa lughatuhu. Maa lughatuhu. Khamid. And Hamza, what is his language? Good. Hamza, maa lughatuhu, right? And Hamza, and what about
[SPEAKER_00] Hamza? As I've been saying, what about Hamza? What is his language, right? So if you're in a conversation with somebody, and you want to say, for example, let's say if you want to say, you just say maa lughatuhu, they're wondering, who are you talking about? Lughatuhu just means his language, so you can be like, who is his language? So you say it like this, wa, and you say the name, then you say maa lughatuhu, then it makes sense to be clear whose pronoun you're referring to. Hamzati. Sorry? Exactly, yeah. What if you say maa lughatuhamzati? Yeah, no, Hamza, yeah, you say Hamzatat, but yeah. Hamzati. Because, I don't know myself, I've already learned the language, so I don't know who I'm talking to, but you'll say maa lughatuhu from nur nassar. Okay. But you can say, yeah, you can say that, too. Right, but this is just a different way of saying it. Okay, same. And what about Hamza? What is his language, like that? Whereas when you say it, it's what is Hamza's language, okay? Lughatuhamzati. Yeah, it's a different way
[SPEAKER_00] of saying the same thing. So what if instead of Hamza you say Wa Ismwa, and his language. Yeah, I mean, if you're just having a conversation, nobody will say you're wrong, but, like, grammatically speaking, it's not like you're from the same sentence. Yeah. So, you just say, Right? Okay. Continue. No, that's, I think that's a mistake. It shouldn't be that. Oh. Cool. His language is Japanese. Good. His language is Japanese. Good.
[SPEAKER_00] And it's a difficult language. Yes, and it is. Kiya, again, we shouldn't make a mistake. It means she or her, right? Over here, it's referring to it, referring to language. Language. It is a difficult language. Continue. Hamidun ayna alooka ya muhammad. Yes. Hamid. Where is your father, ya muhammad? Mm-hmm. Muhammadan. Yeah. Abif al-Kuwaiti. Huwa tabibun shaheerun. True. Muhammadan. My father is in Kuwait. Mm-hmm. He's a famous doctor. Yeah, good. Shaheer means the same thing as mashkoor, which means famous. Famous. Well known. I'm not sure. Hamidun, ba ayna umnita. Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_00] Hamid, and where is your mother? Mm-hmm. Muhammadan. She is aident in Kuwaiti, ma abib. Ma abib. Muhammad. She is also in Kuwait with father, my godfather. Yes. Yeah, continue. She is also in Kuwait with my father. Yeah. She is a teacher there. Good. Hamidun, as a half-stack. Mm-hmm. Okay, so this is where we got into the verbs, right? This is why we started the whole chart. Because
[SPEAKER_00] as of now, we have only learnt dhahabah, and kharajah, and one more verb, I think, jalasah, right? We only learnt three verbs, and we only learnt one version of these verbs, which is singular, past tense, third person. Third person, what else? Singular, past tense, third... Male. Male, yes. Right? So dhahabah just means he went. Jalasah, he sat. Right? But now, we're changing it up. Now it's saying dhahabdah, right? Now, everybody who has the chart, a few of you may not have the chart, but whoever was here in the last lesson, if you look at your chart... Dhahabdah. Dhahabdah. Which one of them would follow? What would fall under? Second person, male. Second person, male. Good. Second person, male. Right? Dhahabdah. Dhahabdah. Which means what? What would it mean? You went. You went. Good. But since he's saying, so it's
[SPEAKER_00] asking a question. What does that mean? Did you go? Yes. Did you go? Good. Yes. Did you go to Kuwait? No. No. No. No. odpowied cidade casual. feet. All this. Good.ędzie. جاءتء TRUE muhammaddeen و نعم.. Yes. عائده الحب ضع صاحب جاءت اسطfa Rocket Histor stunning. Yes. 되지 spins again. Yes. aur what is the Hab Do again? If you don't understand what first person, second person, third person means, just remember third person means you're talking about somebody. So it's he or she or something like that. Then second person means you're talking to somebody. So it's like you, either a female or male. And first person means you're talking
[SPEAKER_00] about yourself. So first person together means I. First person plural means we. Multiple people. So the abdu means I went. Okay, we're going to finish in a couple of minutes, so inshallah. Alright. Yeah, abuhu, right? So we learned already ab, right? Abun means father. Abuhu, right? You add that waw in there, right? If you're adding, if you're making it, well, I don't want to confuse you. But you add that waw in there, and you say abuhu, right? Like in the Quran, وَكَانَ أَبُوهُمَا صَالِحًا Right?
[SPEAKER_00] Okay. So wait, I'm sorry. So it says, and your classmate? What's the translation? Yeah, and your classmate, where is his father? Where is his father? Abuhu qaafi. Abuhu qaafi. Abuhu qaafi. Abuhu qaafi. Quba taajirun qabirun. Muhammad. His father is in Qatan. He's a big merchant. Yeah. In this case, he's not talking about physically big, right? He's not calling him fat. He's saying that he's a big merchant, meaning he does big business. He's a rich guy. Okay. Okay. Okay. Laka, this is something new. Well, not really new, because we already learned laam. That's a harf al-jal, right? Hatha li sa'imin. Right? Hatha
[SPEAKER_00] al-qalamu li sa'imin. This pen belongs to sa'im. Right? Hatha al-kitabu li saleemin. Right? This book belongs to saleem. Right? This is just a different form of it, right? If, in certain circumstances, this same laam can have fatha on top of it. Right? Why? The reason is simple. It's just because the Arabs, they prefer to pronounce things in a way that it's more intuitive. It makes it sound easier. It's easier on the tongue. It's lighter on the tongue. Right? So it would be weird if you say alika. Right? Right? Alika. Alika. Right? So they just changed the kasra into a fatha. Laka. But it's still the same letter. It's still a harf al-jal. It still means to belong to somebody. But they just changed the kasra into a fatha to make it easier to pronounce on the tongue. Right? So laka. Right? Belongs to you. Basically, it means belongs to you. Because ka means you. Right?
[SPEAKER_00] Akhen. Right? But basically what it's saying is do you have a brother. Right? Alaka. Akhen. Okay. Do you have a brother? Mm-hmm. Alika. Alika. Alika. Alika. Alika. Do you have a brother? Do you have a brother? So that's the whole translation for this question? Yes. Do you have a brother? Yes. Let's just quickly get through to the end of the lesson. We're almost... I mean, time is... We're already finished. Forty-five... Forty-three minutes. Let's just finish the lesson and we can end it. Inshallah. Inshallah. Inshallah. Inshallah. Inshallah. Inshallah. Inshallah. Yeah, Usama is another example of a name, a male name that has a female, that has Taam al-Butha. So it's treated like a female name in terms of the rules. So it doesn't get the mean as well. Usamatoo, right? It's not Usamatun, it's Usamatoo. So same thing as Talhatoo, Hamzatoo, right? Yeah, no,
[SPEAKER_00] actually he purposely does that, the author. He purposely brings multiple things of the same type in the same lesson. So you start noticing it, you get it? So he never brought any of these exceptions before. He's bringing them now on purpose because that's one of the things, the new concept he wants to introduce in the book. Okay, you can translate from here. Anybody want to help? Yeah, I have one brother. So remember, the Lam attaches to whatever you own, right? Or you not own, or like something belongs to you, right? So the Ya means me. So Li means I have. Get it? I have my
[SPEAKER_00] brother. His name? His name is Usama. Okay, good. His name is Usama. And he is with me there in Madinah. No, Hunaka is there. Huna means here. Hunaka is there. Huna means here. He is with me here in? So Madinah al-Munawwarah, we obviously hear this word all the time, but we may have not realized this is actually a Malsoof and Sifah as well. Al-Madinah means city. Al-Munawwarah means enlightened city, right? Noor comes from Noor. Munawwarah means enlightened, right? So if you look at it, it fits all four of these things, right? But I'm not going to go through it now. So anyways. Okay. And
[SPEAKER_00] I have one sister. . . Good. So this is a new thing we learned here, another attached pronoun. It's Ha, right? Ha, right? So Hu means his, Ha means her. Got it? Right? This comes many places in the Quran as well, right? One example. . Yeah, that's true. Yeah. . Yeah, good, good examples. But something a little more easy to understand. . Whatever, okay. But you get the point. It means same thing, same concept. It just means her blank. Okay. . So over here, I have one sister. . . Just note that it's because it's the Sifah of . It's a description of .
[SPEAKER_00] . Her name is Zaynab. . Okay, so I'm going to say it again. and she is in Iraq with her husband good she is in Iraq with her husband just note it's why because what did we learn about it just right now no it's a yeah and it makes the word after it so that's why okay alright her husband is a an engineer continue
[SPEAKER_00] we learned in the last lesson right Yeah, with But if you're saying it like this It means I have or you have Literally, you're trying to say with you or with me But practically speaking, it just means Do I have this or I have So for example, if you want to say I have a question You say Or if you just want to say I have a book You say I have a car So now he's asking What does that mean? Do you have Do you have a car, my brother Or my brother Right, my brother Continue
[SPEAKER_00] You don't have a car A car Mohamad, no It's not my car Okay Okay, this is a new We didn't learn this here, right? Ma meaning no I do not have We didn't learn that yet? Okay, we'll go into that next time I'll just not be confused But just know that ma here Means no, I don't have Ma indi I don't have Why do you have la? And ma both La is one sentence No Then next sentence I don't have a car You get it? There's a question Yeah, so this ma is for It's called ma annafia It's for negation But we'll learn that next lesson In more detail, inshallah It's to negate something Ma annafia, right? Ma indi sayara I do not have a car Continue Inti darajatun I
[SPEAKER_00] I am What is darajatun again? Darajatun is a car Darajatun means bike Bicycle I have a bike Bicycle Hamza Hamza who? In the who? Sayara Hamza Is it your car? No, no In the who? In the who? Is it his car? No, it's not a question It's a statement In the who? Is he Yeah Hamza He has a car It's like he's saying Hamza, he has a car I don't have a car He has a car So it's that Okay, Hamza So we finished the lesson So hopefully you understood everything So very quickly I want you guys to do tamrins The At least The first two Right? The first one Ajib a'alil as'ilatil aatiyah You just have to answer the questions So All these 22 Are all questions You just have to answer them Right? In Arabic obviously Not in English So Masmuka You
[SPEAKER_00] just enter But I want you to answer With a complete sentence So just write Sa'im Don't just write like that I want you to write Ismi Sa'imun Like that Right? So basically this is going to Help you practice with your These pronouns These Attached pronouns Right? Because most of them If not all of them Will be using these pronouns Everybody understood that? So just answer all these 22 questions It sounds like a lot But it's like two word answers Right? So it shouldn't take too long Then number two Da'afil faraqi Fima yali Al-damira Ha Or ha Hu or ha Right? So place in the empty spots Either the pronoun ha Or ha Right? Meaning the male pronoun Or the female pronoun So they're just testing to see If you know the difference Between the male pronoun And the female pronoun So you either put Ismuhu Zainab Or you put Ismuh Ha You get it? In the same way You either put Ibnu hu
[SPEAKER_00] muhandison Or ibnu ha muhandison So you either put Next You know You either put Ismuhu Abdullah Or Ismuhu Abdullah You either say Ummu ha or Ummu hu And uhtu ha or uhtu hu You get it? Understand? Okay Just do these two Tamreen These two Exercises Inshallah And we will meet On Wednesday Inshallah Jazakallah SubhanAllah Alhamdulillah Alhamdulillah Alhamdulillah Alhamdulillah Alhamdulillah Alhamdulillah Alhamdulillah Alhamdulillah Alhamdulillah Thank you.