[SPEAKER_00] Okay, so we were explaining Tabligh number 3 and 4 Tabligh number 3 was Basically give 5 questions and answers That are upon the same structure as This sentence, these two sentences Do you have a pen? Yes, I have a pen So basically you just replace the word pen With other words in Arabic And we're talking about possession Used for objects Then bring 5 more examples for number 4 Same thing but the structure is different Because you're saying no, I don't have a pen So la is the answer to the question Do you have one? So it's just no, right? But then to further explain you're saying I do not have a pen Right? So So yeah, so So So ma over
[SPEAKER_00] here So far we learned one type of ma Which is Yeah That's called ma al-istifhamiyya Right? So if you want to go to your family's page If you have a family's page Hopefully everybody can have one by now If you want to go to your family's page And you go to Al-istifham, right? The words that are used to ask questions So amongst them you have ma, right? That's the first actually lesson that we learned Right? Is ma hala What is this, right? So That is called ma al-istifhamiyya We learned that istifham is Questioning, right? To ask a question Okay? That's one type of ma Now we have two types of ma, right? There's actually much more We'll look at that in a little bit We'll learn as we go along Inshallah
[SPEAKER_00] More than five, six different types of ma But So far we learned two now This one is ma al-istifhamiyya The second one is Ma al-nafiya Ma al-nafiya Al-nafiya means Negating Negating Ma al-nafiya means The ma that negates Right? It's very pessimistic It's always negative Right? So ma al-nafiya Okay? So over here If you read ma al-nafiya Now you have two ma So you have to see Okay, is it this one or this one? Is it a question or is it negation? So just look at the context
[SPEAKER_00] And it'll be clear Right? Would you think it's a question here? Ma al-nafiya It doesn't make sense If you try to try to do a question Right? What? What? I have a car That's not a question Right? So it makes more sense To understand it as a nafi As nafiya As a negation I do not have a car Understood? So this is called ma and nafiya Okay? It's used in specific context But I don't want to confuse you guys Because that'll come as time to say this Time comes to understand When to use ma And when to use la That might be confusing for you guys Because we all know la Is for the same purpose To negate Right? So now when to use ma When to use la That's something Again, I don't want to confuse you So slowly, slowly With time it'll come inshallah But for now At least we know this one sentence Ma al-nafiya Blank I don't have this So we can just At least use this sentence We can use Right? We can start speaking InshaAllah when we're practicing Ma al-nafiya Blank I do not have blank Why can't people Don't have ma
[SPEAKER_00] So if you just If you just say Andi sayyara Then you're just saying I have a car That's the opposite Of what you're trying to say You get it? So ma makes it A negative sentence I do not have a car You get it? So Yeah So why can't you say La andi sayyara That's just not The way the Arabs Would say it Yeah So in this context They would use ma Yeah So that's what I'm saying That's why I wanted to mention That you know Each is used In their own specific context Right? So Let's say for example If you're answering a question Right? Like for example Do you want to go to The masjid So you wouldn't answer By saying ma No you would answer By saying la Right? So again Each one has Their own specific context That they're using
[SPEAKER_00] So we'll have to Learn that as time goes on InshaAllah But again At least we know This one sentence Ma andi blank That is For negation Right? I do not have a Pen or whatever It is Okay So yeah So that's all you have to do For the lesson number For sorry Question number four All the words Into the house Are just Different pronouns Yeah so actually Yeah all it is Is it's just teaching It's just teaching What we already learned About the pronouns Right? Beytun means house Right? Beytun means house Beyti means My house Beytuka means Beytuhu means Beytuha means Right? So now Let's just To practice Let
[SPEAKER_00] us change the word Qalami means Qalamuha means Qalamuhu Qalabuka Your pen Okay Qamis Okay My shirt His shirt Her shirt Your shirt Okay Let's see What else? Give me another word Chair Okay Chair Kursiyi Kursiyuka Kursiyuhu Kursiyuha Her chair Kursiyu is not a house By the way Yeah Okay All right One more word Give me one more Sorry? Sayyara Fine, let's do sayyara Okay
[SPEAKER_00] So how do you say Your car? How do you say Her car? Sayyartuha Yes His car Sayyartuhu Yeah And your car? Okay, good You guys got the concept? Yeah If you keep practicing It'll become second nature My car? What did you say? My car? You tell me Sayyaratu Yeah If it's a female word Like a male word That we make it For example I can't think of an example But you don't talk about? Like a male word A male word that you made A female meaning? Like you know how you add the Oh, like tabiba Yeah So how do you say Oh, wait That's not a word His doctor Her doctor You can say that Like my doctor? Yeah My female doctor? Yeah I mean you shouldn't be having A female doctor in the first place But If you want to say that Then tabibati So you just add
[SPEAKER_00] the Yeah You just add the yeah At the end Yeah Hamza Hamza Like the hamza Has a two in it Like some male words Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah How do we So normally You don't really Attach ya To a name Because you don't say like You don't say like Sa'imi Right? Unless you're talking about Your wife or something But normally You don't say that, right? Because Arabic Is not really said like that So So yeah So normally It's not like that But either way It's very simple You just add ya Whatever you're going to do Add to And that becomes my Yeah Okay Alright Next Fifty-eight Oh, okay There's actually more ten means Than I thought Sorry, guys But Okay Okay Okay
[SPEAKER_00] , how do you say This is
[SPEAKER_00] Okay How do you say book? Okay, how do you say my book? You just add a ya at the end E Yeah This is my book Right? So anything you want to say This is my blank You just add e at the end Right? This is my pen This is my pen Right? This is My son This is my son Right? This is my son Right? For example So anything you want to add You just add a ya at the end Okay Brother Shiraz This is your pen Sorry, sorry Book This is your book Good This is your book Good Alright Brother Kasha This is his pen I mean, sorry Book Yeah, you're right Yeah Brother Harun Hafiz Harun This is his pen This is her book
[SPEAKER_00] Good Alright Next Sareer Sareer means? Bed Right? Okay, brother Jibreel How do you say This is my bed? Good Good Brother Thaqif How do you say This is your bed? Okay, good Brother Zeeshan How do you say This is her bed? Sareeruha Good Yeah, this is her bed Okay And You wouldn't make a sareeruha? No Because the bed doesn't become female just because it belongs to a female Do you get it? So you keep the bed as it is Okay Okay, so you keep the bed as it is Okay Okay Okay Okay Okay Okay This is his bed
[SPEAKER_00] Alright When we write this Whether for homework or in the book Do you still want us to be writing harakah or no? You can if you want to But it's not a big deal if you do or if you don't Yeah Alright Next Ismun Alright So how do you say What is his name? Tamim Hafiz Tamim What is his name? Hada No, Hadas What is his name? What is What is Masmuh Yeah Say it again one more time, louder It's Masmuh, right? Masmuh, yeah Yeah What is his name? And Barat Tawheed What is My name? Well, you're not going to ask what is my name, but My name? Yeah, Masmi, yeah Yeah Okay Next Fala Salim What is your name? Masmuk Yeah, Masmuk Good Alright Alright Mendeel Alright Everybody know what a Mendeel is?
[SPEAKER_00] Handkerchief Handkerchief Right Do you know what a handkerchief is? Is that enough? But like you keep it on Good Mashallah So how do you Alright, now Who didn't go yet? Brother Mudassir How do you say This is her Handkerchief Yeah, good Mendeel Alright Brother Dawood How do you say This is His Handkerchief Good Alright Brother Osman Hafiz Osman How do you say This is Your Handkerchief Okay, Brother Mu'min Hafiz Mu'min My Good Okay Ibnun Right Ibnun means Son Your brother Brother Mustafa
[SPEAKER_00] Yes How do you say My son My son Good And then Your son Yeah Your son Ibnuka Good This is your son Good This is His son His son Her son Her son Your son It is her son So again This could Hopefully clarify Brother Hafiz Zeeshan's Question Which is That Not question But your mistake That you're saying Right So But over here For example Ibn Right You're not going to make the Ibn female Just because the mother is female You get it So you're only talking about the The Possessor of that You're not talking about The thing itself So you're not going to say Hadhi ibnatu ha If it's If it's her son Right So
[SPEAKER_00] you say Ibnu ha Got it Okay Brother Zeeshan My car This is my car My car Is Sayyarati Good MashaAllah Hadhi sayyarati Good Who didn't go yet I think everybody went Right No Abdullah Hafiz Abdullah How do you say Your car Hadhi sayyarati Yeah Hadhi though Because it's female Yeah Good Everybody else went Alright Just Just go One more round Hamad Quickly His car Hadhi Hadhi Hadhi Sayyarati Had Not his car Male Sayyarati Sayyarati who Yeah Okay Next Female Good
[SPEAKER_00] Next Miftah My pen Sorry My key Good Yours Your key Miftah Good Miftah Miftah Miftah Miftah Miftah Miftah Miftah Miftah Miftah Miftah Miftah Miftah Miftah Miftah Miftah Miftah Miftah Miftah No but You want to say hadhi because We're talking about the key We're not talking about the owner of the key So you're saying this is The key doesn't become female It's because the owner is female You get it So you keep the key as male Hadha Hadha Miftah Miftah Miftah Miftah Miftah Ha Miftah Miftah Miftah How you say hand
[SPEAKER_00] Miftah Okay Yadi comes in the Quran Where does it come in the Quran? Hufaq? Oh you didn't Brother You didn't go right? Okay So you can go next Where does Yadi come in the Quran? No that's Yadullahi That's Ka Yadika Okay that's good Yadika is in the Quran Right? We're talking to Allah Subhanahu wa ta'ala Khair, good is in your hands Biyadika Huh? Biyadihi That's in his hand See Same concept right? But I'm talking about Yadi Yadi is Come on Hufaq I'm not going to stretch out my hands So that I can kill you That's Habil said to Qabil Right? Yadi
[SPEAKER_00] I'm not going to spread out my hand To kill you Even if you're going to attack me I'm not going to spread out my hand Yadi Basi Yadi So Yadi My hand Right? Yeah good Biyadihi And in his hand is the Dominion of all things Good So see these If you pay attention to the Quran These pronouns Come over Every single page You'll have multiple Of each one of these pronouns Right? So if you understand this You're already Getting a huge percentage You know So make sure you have these Down strong And start paying attention To the Quran Right? And start thinking You know again You're not going to really Fully grasp Arabic Until you start thinking All these rules That we're Learning You start applying it In the Quran And start thinking For example You know that these are all pronouns Right? Now think Okay this is a pronoun What is it referring back to? Right? Because every time you think For example Biyadihi So now you think Him But who is he referring to? You go back In the context of the Quran Usually you can understand
[SPEAKER_00] From the context Who is going back to him A lot of times Going back to Allah Right? Biyadihi Malakutu kulli shay So If you start thinking And pondering Of course you won't get it Every time Because you're still learning But this pondering And thinking Will help you Really really It'll strengthen the concepts In your mind a lot InshaAllah A lot of you just Learn the rules And you don't apply them Then you're going to forget them Right? You're going to revise Revise Revise Revise That will help you But the best way To keep these rules Fresh in your mind Is to keep applying them Then you'll never forget it Right? I haven't touched these rules For years Like I studied this book Ten years More than ten years ago Right? But I just Pick it up And I just teach you guys I don't really prepare Right? Because It's I've been using these rules So often For ten years now That it's It's like The back of my hand Right? So The same thing If you guys keep using Keep using Keep applying Keep applying Keep applying InshaAllah It'll become like Second nature Right? Okay? So But
[SPEAKER_00] make sure Again that's why I always Always emphasize Bringing examples From the Qur'an Because I want you guys When you're reading the Qur'an To also First we have to First and foremost We have to build a habit Of reading the Qur'an That's the first If you're not even doing that Then we're not getting Anything out of this Right? So if we have a habit Of reading the Qur'an daily Now let's set some time Maybe you can have Some more time Where you have a goal Okay you have a specific Amount you want to recite So you recite that amount But then an extra ten minutes Where you just sit and ponder Like think Okay I'm going to take This few lines I'm going to try to Apply whatever rules I learned in Arabic And try to figure out Something of what's going on Right? I'm not going to Fully understand Of course I'm not trying To do tafsir or anything I'm just trying to figure out What's going on Trying to apply the rules And you'll see a huge Huge inshallah jump In your abilities in Arabic Inshallah The you pronoun That's singular you? Or that could be No that's only singular Yeah good question So yeah Good question So when we say Ka right? Qalamuka Your pen That's only for One word When you're talking To one person Right? If
[SPEAKER_00] you want to talk To multiple It's going to come up later Inshallah But I mean I might as well tell you now It's kum Right? That's why As-salamu alaykum Right? It's for a plural If you were to say To one person You say As-salamu alayka Right? That's when we go to Medina What do we say? As-salatu was-salamu alayka Ya Rasulullah Right? Because we're talking To only Rasulullah Sallallahu alayhi wa sallam So we're saying it With singular Right? As-salamu alayka Even in the At-tahiyyat Right? As-salamu alayka Ayyuhan nabiyyu Right? Because we're talking Only to Nabi Sallallahu alayhi wa sallam Right? But if you're talking To a group of people You say As-salamu alaykum Right? And also if you're just Talking to one person You can So technically speaking If you're talking to one person You can just tell them As-salamu alayka Right? Or you can say As-salamu alaykum too It's not wrong either Because sometimes You can use a plural form For respect Right? So that's fine too So yeah Also when you say
[SPEAKER_00] Sallallahu alayhi wa sallam No That's part of Allahu That's part of the name Allah Sallallahu But alayhi The ha And alayhi Is going back Going to Rasulullah Upon him Why is it he Instead of who? Because of Ala Ala Because of Ala Ala Ala And if you add the ha To Ala It becomes alayhi Sallallahu alayhi May Allah send blessings Upon him Alaihi The ha Again this The mead Right? So if you look around And if you ponder These pronouns Are everywhere In the Quran And hadith Everywhere So inshallah We start applying And start thinking And then everything Will start making sense InshaAllah Abduhu wa rasuluh Yeah good So that's talking about Allah Abduhu Meaning Ashadu anna muhammadan The witness that Muhammad sallallahu alayhi wa sallam Is Abduhu His slave Meaning Allah's slave Wa rasuluhu And his messenger Meaning Allah's messenger
[SPEAKER_00] You understand? Right? Everything's clicking right? So that's what I'm saying If you keep thinking If you keep applying All of a sudden So many things will just click Right? So let's start applying InshaAllah Where does the ya come in Ala Like alayka for example Where does the ya come? It's from Ala Right? So the word Ala It's When it's attached to something It becomes like a ya Yeah Yeah Yeah Because it's also written like a ya too right? If you look at it It's written like this Like that right? It looks like a ya But without the dots So as soon as it gets attached to something Alaika for example Then it becomes a ya Right? Yeah Okay Next we have Iqra Okay so this is important This is actually part of the lesson So sometimes the author does this In the tamreen He'll include part of the lesson So actually That's why it's important to go through all tamreen The actual part of the lesson Because this is actually part of the lesson Itself Right? It's
[SPEAKER_00] teaching us something new over here Okay So somebody read this Read this Can you read this? Number six You Yeah So I have one sister So wahidatun Is that a new word we learned? We didn't learn that yet right? Yeah Wahidun means one Right? And if you're talking about one sister So it's a female So you add a ta Right? So if you want to say I have one of something You add wahid after it Right? For example How would you say Brother Akash How would you say I have one car Yeah good But in this case though You would use andi That's going to come You would say andi Because it's an object But yeah The main point I want to focus on Is wahida Right? One car Right? I have one pen Pen I
[SPEAKER_00] have one pen How do you say that? Yeah Andi kalamun wahidun Right? For me for example I want to say I have one daughter Andi Sorry Li bintun wahidatun Right? I have one son Li ibnun wahid Right? Right So li uhtun wahidatun I have one daughter Continue Sorry One sister Right? Do you have a brother? No I do not have a brother Okay Yeah Do you have a brother? No So you see ma over here again Ma over here is being used In As nafiyah Right? Ma li akhun Right? So over here it's I do not have a brother Right? So through the context We figure it out There's no other way to figure out Which ma it is Except through context Right?
[SPEAKER_00] Through the context You'll figure out Is this for nafiyah Or is it istifhamiyah Is it a question Or is it negation? Is li only used for humans Or like living things in general? Like pets and stuff? It's normally used for humans Yeah Okay So alaka akhun Do you have a brother? La ma li akhun Okay Continue Okay My sister has A small I don't know Tiflun is Tiflun is a child or baby Tiflun is a baby My sister has a small baby Okay Tifl come in the Quran too Oh Tifl alladheena lam yadharu ala awratin nisa Right? And the plural of it is also In the Quran Al-atfal Wa idha balaghal Atfalu minkum al-huluma Right? So tifl means basically like a baby Or a
[SPEAKER_00] small child Okay? Sorry? No, so tifl is male And then tiflatun is female Yeah Okay? Sagheerun means small Sagheerun means small Yeah Sagheerun, yeah Lahaz The lam is the same harf al-jar She has Lahaz is the dhamir The female pronoun Right? She has So but it's just The way you say it You wouldn't really translate You would just say My sister has Right? So but if you want to translate literally You would just say My sister She has a Small child You get it? Okay Next Zamili Zamili Zamili lahu akhun wa akhtun My classmate has a brother and sister Good
[SPEAKER_00] My classmate Zamil means classmate Zamili, my classmate Lahu akhun wahid He has one brother and one sister Okay, good So from this we learn Li laka lahu laha Right? So one thing to point out here is that Even though this is the same lam That we've been learned We learned about a long time ago Right? For example Li sa'imin kitabun wahidun Right? Sa'im has a small One book Right? So we already learned this lam A long time ago It's for milk It's for It's to show possession Right? But over here what they're showing Is that when it's connected to certain Pronouns Then it will become a fatha Normally it has a kasra under it Right? Li Right? But if it's connected to ka Or hu or ha Then it changes to a fatha Why? To make it easier to pronounce Right? So So technically speaking If it was to say the same It
[SPEAKER_00] would be lika Or lihu Or liha But doesn't it sound a bit like Difficult to pronounce? Right? So that's why the Arabs They would just take the kasra And turn it into a fatha Just to make it easier to pronounce Otherwise it's the same li That we've learned before Right? But it's The fatha comes upon it To make it easier to pronounce So it's laka Or lahu Or laha This comes so many places In the Qur'an All these Right? Just the word Classmate Without the li What's the Zamilun Zamilun Yeah Give me an example of li In the Qur'an Good Yeah Rabbi Shroh Li Good Rabbi Shroh And what is li And what is li I don't worship Who has given me Right? And then laka What is laka? Hufad Hufad Okay But that's lakum That's plural But okay I'll accept that Huh?
[SPEAKER_00] Good Wa rafa'na Laka Dhikrak Very good Masha'Allah Surah Inshirah Right? And we have raised For you Your mention Dhikrak Wafa'na Laka For you Laka dhikrak Good Lahu That's How come Tens of Hundreds maybe Place in the Qur'an Yeah Lahu mulku samawati Lahu ma'afi samawati Ma'afi laud Wait If lahu means Belongs to Him Then why are we using In Uh Uh Zamid Zamid Lahu No that just means My classmate For him belongs Like my classmate He has It's a main So what's the question? I'm not sure What's the question? I just figured it out While I was asking Sorry? I figured it out While I was asking Okay Alright So lahu Lahu ma'afi samawati Ma'afi To whom To him belongs Whatever is in the heavens or earth Lahu comes Plenty of times in the Qur'an What about laha In the Qur'an One more Laha saba'at abwaab Good
[SPEAKER_00] Masha'Allah It's referring to Jahannam Jahannam Good Wa inna jahannama Lamaw'iduhum ajma'een Laha saba'atu abwaab Likuli ba'ab min hujood So the word jahannam I think we mentioned it before Even though it looks like it's male Doesn't have to have marbuta But it's a female word Right So that's why It's Laha Saba'atu abwaab It has Seven So ba'ab means Door Abwaab means doors Right So it has seven doors Okay One more In surah Laha ma kasabat Wa alayha maktasabat Good Very good Masha'Allah It's going back to nafs I was going to say A separate one For you and the female Laki Yeah good We didn't Technically we didn't learn The you for female yet But yeah Good Masha'Allah Laki And then Um Laha Wa laha arshun azim Right Referring to This is in surah naml Right Where the The bird Hudhud Is
[SPEAKER_00] telling Sulaiman a.s. About Who Bilqis Right The queen of Sheba Asaba Right Um He's talking about her Um Wa laha arshun Inni wajadtu mra'atan Tamlikuhum Wa utiyat min kulli shay' Wa laha arshun azim And she has She has Arshun azim What is arsh? Throne Arsh is a throne Azim Great Right She has Laha arshun azim She has a great throne Understood? So again This comes over and over And over and over again In the Quran Okay This next sentence says Naqulu Andi kitabun Wa nakulu Li akhun La nakulu Andi akhun Understood? So what it's saying over here is We say Andi kitab You say So in Arabic You say I have a book Andi You use the word Andi Right? And you say Li akhun Right? You use the word Li for brother
[SPEAKER_00] For human beings Not for objects So you can use it for objects too But Andi is Just generally just used for objects Not for human beings Right? La nakulu Andi akhun So if you want to say I have a brother Don't say Andi akhun Rather you say Li akhun Okay so that's One of the lessons That they taught us here La nakulu It means Do not say La nakulu means We do not say But it's just Teaching us that We shouldn't say this We don't say it like this Yeah What is that called? The noon coming in From the word That's basically So you know how The same All those different Versions of the past tense Verb that we learnt Yeah So now when you go to Present tense verbs Mudarir Then It's different forms So this is like You know it's like Faalna Zahabna Or Zahabna Right That's we went So this is the The present tense version Of that Right Naqulu We say Right So you add a
[SPEAKER_00] na When it's We You get it? Yaqulu means he It's the first one Yaqulu Yeah Okay Alright I think we can end over here In sha Allah Is exercise six Just translating? Yeah so like I said Exercise six is technically You They should have just put it Part of the lesson Right Because basically part of the lesson Because teaching you that The difference between Li and Ainda Right So So that's why Even this next one Says maa Right So this is just teaching you More about maa Because the new word That came up right Maa means With So this is just This is just going over that In more detail This is dharf Dharf yes It's a dharf Okay So we'll just end here I mean So for homework You have to do Tamneen's number One Two Three Four Five
[SPEAKER_00] we already did So just one two three four Okay Everybody got that? We'll continue from Tamneen number seven On Monday And we'll In sha Allah Start to finish the next lesson Two hopefully On Monday In sha Allah In sha Allah Alright Subhanallah Bihamdi Alhamdulillah Bihamdi Alhamdulillah Alhamdulillah Alhamdulillah Alhamdulillah Alhamdulillah Alhamdulillah